<Document>
# Zetans

[textlink="View Full Wiki Page" link="https://ss14.misfitsystems.net/wiki/index.php/Zetans"]

<Table Columns="2">
  <Box>[bold]Status[/bold]</Box>
  <Box>Active — Extraterrestrial</Box>
  <Box>[bold]Location[/bold]</Box>
  <Box>Unknown (random encounters)</Box>
  <Box>[bold]Leadership[/bold]</Box>
  <Box>Unknown</Box>
  <Box>[bold]Ideology[/bold]</Box>
  <Box>Unknown — possibly scientific observation</Box>
  <Box>[bold]Motto[/bold]</Box>
  <Box>[italic]"..."[/italic]</Box>
</Table>

<hr/>

<p>Zetans are extraterrestrial beings. Their presence in the Fallout universe stretches back before recorded wasteland history — recovered audio logs, crop circles, and abductee testimonies suggest they have been observing and experimenting on humans for longer than post-war civilization can remember. Their technology is categorically beyond anything produced on Earth, before or after the Great War.</p>

<p>They did not come here for diplomacy.</p>

<hr/>

## Origin

<p>Zetans appear prominently in Fallout 3's Mothership Zeta, though references to alien presence appear throughout the series. Their motives remain the most profound mystery in the Fallout universe: scientific research, resource harvesting, or something with no human equivalent are all possible. They have never offered an explanation in any language surface inhabitants can interpret.</p>

<hr/>

## Capabilities

<p>Zetans possess directed energy weapons, stasis technology, anti-gravity systems, and advanced alloys that no wasteland craftsperson can replicate. Standard wasteland tactics and equipment are poorly matched to what they bring. Engaging them without specialized preparation is not advisable.</p>

<ColorBox Color="#cc3333">
  <Box Margin="2">
  [bold]Warning — Zetan Contact[/bold]
  </Box>
</ColorBox>
<Box>
Do not engage Zetans without coordinated preparation and the best available equipment. Their weapons are lethal and their defenses do not respond to conventional wasteland tactics. A coordinated group response is strongly recommended over any individual approach.

If you witness a Zetan presence, report immediately to faction leadership. Their appearance is anomalous and their intentions cannot be assumed to be benign under any circumstances.
</Box>

<hr/>

## Faction Relations

<p>Zetans do not maintain diplomatic relations with any known faction. Communication in any language that surface inhabitants can interpret has not been reliably established. Treat all Zetan contact as immediately hostile unless demonstrated otherwise.</p>
</Document>
