<Document>
# Energy Weapons

[textlink="View Full Wiki Page" link="https://ss14.misfitsystems.net/wiki/index.php/Energy_Weapons"]

<p>Energy weapons use focused laser technology to deliver precise, armor-punching hits. They do not use conventional ammunition, relying instead on power cells and other specialized energy feeds.</p>

<p>These weapons are rare and expensive, and are most often seen in the hands of the Brotherhood of Steel, the Enclave, and elite scavengers.</p>

<hr/>

## Laser Pistols

<p>Compact laser sidearms useful for self-defense, patrol work, and precision shooting.</p>

<ul>
<li>[bold]Laser Pistol[/bold] — Standard energy sidearm. Reliable and easy to maintain with charged cells.</li>
<li>[bold]Laser Revolver[/bold] — Revolving-chamber laser pistol. Slower to reload but packs more punch per shot.</li>
<li>[bold]Recharger Pistol[/bold] — Self-charging energy pistol. Never runs out of ammo but fires slowly.</li>
</ul>

<hr/>

## Laser Rifles

<p>Laser rifles deliver reliable ranged damage and are iconic weapons for advanced factions.</p>

<ul>
<li>[bold]Laser Rifle[/bold] — Standard-issue energy rifle. Accurate and effective at medium range.</li>
<li>[bold]Automatic Laser Rifle[/bold] — Full-auto variant. Burns through cells fast but puts out heavy sustained fire.</li>
<li>[bold]AER14 Prototype[/bold] — Experimental pre-war design with enhanced beam focus and damage output.</li>
<li>[bold]Wattz 3000[/bold] — Premium civilian laser rifle. Excellent accuracy and reliability.</li>
</ul>

<hr/>

## Gatling Laser

<p>The Gatling Laser is a heavy beam weapon capable of sustained fire that can shred exposed targets very quickly.</p>

<ul>
<li>[bold]Gatling Laser[/bold] — Rotary-barrel heavy energy weapon. The energy equivalent of a minigun.</li>
</ul>

<hr/>

## Improvised Energy Weapons

<p>Makeshift and crude laser weapons can be built from salvaged parts, though they are usually less reliable than pre-war models.</p>

<ul>
<li>[bold]Crude Laser Rifle[/bold] — Cobbled together from scrap optics and salvaged cells. Unreliable but functional.</li>
<li>[bold]Makeshift Laser Rifle[/bold] — Slightly better than crude. Uses jury-rigged focusing lenses.</li>
</ul>
</Document>
