<Document>
# Small Guns

[textlink="View Full Wiki Page" link="https://ss14.misfitsystems.net/wiki/index.php/Small_Guns"]

<p>Small Guns are the most common ranged weapons in the Wasteland. They are reliable, easy to maintain, and fed by the ammunition you are most likely to find or trade for.</p>

<hr/>

## Pistols

<p>Compact sidearms suited to close and medium range. Pistols are common, practical, and easy to carry every day.</p>

<ul>
<li>[bold]10mm Pistol[/bold] — Standard military sidearm. Reliable, accurate, and uses widely available 10mm rounds.</li>
<li>[bold]9mm Pistol[/bold] — Lightweight civilian pistol. Fast draw speed and low recoil make it ideal for beginners.</li>
<li>[bold]10mm Pipe Pistol[/bold] — Improvised pistol cobbled from scrap. Less accurate but cheap and easy to repair.</li>
</ul>

<hr/>

## Revolvers

<p>Revolvers are slower to reload than pistols, but they hit harder and are valued for their rugged simplicity.</p>

<ul>
<li>[bold].44 Magnum[/bold] — Heavy-hitting hand cannon. Expensive ammo but devastating per-shot damage.</li>
<li>[bold]10mm Revolver[/bold] — Practical wheel gun using common 10mm rounds. Good balance of power and availability.</li>
<li>[bold].45-70 Hunter[/bold] — Long-barreled revolver chambered in rifle cartridges. Outstanding range for a handgun.</li>
</ul>

<hr/>

## Rifles

<p>Rifles cover most medium- and long-range engagements and are standard issue for many organized factions.</p>

<ul>
<li>[bold]R91 Assault Rifle[/bold] — Pre-war U.S. military standard. 5.56mm, select-fire, and accurate at medium range.</li>
<li>[bold]Chinese Assault Rifle[/bold] — 7.62mm automatic rifle. Higher damage per round but harder to control.</li>
<li>[bold]5.56 Carbine[/bold] — Compact rifle variant for patrol and close-quarters work.</li>
</ul>

<hr/>

## Shotguns

<p>Shotguns deal massive damage at close range and are ideal for room clearing and hunting dangerous fauna.</p>

<ul>
<li>[bold]Double-Barrel Shotgun[/bold] — Two shots, then reload. Simple, brutal, and loud.</li>
<li>[bold]Pump Shotgun[/bold] — Reliable repeating shotgun with a tube magazine. The Wasteland workhorse.</li>
<li>[bold]Sawed-Off Shotgun[/bold] — Shortened barrel for point-blank devastation. Concealable but short range.</li>
</ul>

<hr/>

## Submachine Guns

<p>SMGs fire pistol-caliber rounds at high rates of fire. They excel in close quarters and settlement fighting.</p>

<ul>
<li>[bold]10mm SMG[/bold] — Standard-issue automatic weapon. Common ammo and controllable recoil.</li>
<li>[bold]12mm SMG[/bold] — Heavier caliber submachine gun. Hits harder but burns through ammunition fast.</li>
</ul>

<hr/>

## Snipers

<p>Precision long-range weapons built for picking off targets before they can close the distance.</p>

<ul>
<li>[bold]Hunting Sniper[/bold] — Bolt-action precision rifle. The classic Wasteland marksman's choice.</li>
<li>[bold]Varmint Rifle[/bold] — Lightweight 5.56mm rifle with a scope. Good for hunting and long-range patrol.</li>
<li>[bold].308 Lever Rifle[/bold] — Lever-action rifle with excellent range. A favourite among caravan guards and bounty hunters.</li>
</ul>
</Document>
