<Document>
# Followers of the Apocalypse

[textlink="View Full Wiki Page" link="https://ss14.misfitsystems.net/wiki/index.php/Followers%20of%20the%20Apocalypse"/]

<p>◈ Followers of the Apocalypse ◈ Faction Dossier ◈ Humanitarian ◈</p>

<Table Columns="2">
  <Box>[bold]Followers of the Apocalypse[/bold]</Box>
  <Box></Box>
  <Box>◈ FACTION DOSSIER ◈</Box>
  <Box></Box>
  <Box>[bold]Status[/bold]</Box>
  <Box>Active - Neutral</Box>
  <Box>[bold]Location[/bold]</Box>
  <Box>Wendover Region, Utah
Mobile Field Clinics</Box>
  <Box>[bold]Commander[/bold]</Box>
  <Box>Regional Coordinator</Box>
  <Box>[bold]Ideology[/bold]</Box>
  <Box>Humanitarian Pacifism
Knowledge Preservation</Box>
  <Box>[bold]Motto[/bold]</Box>
  <Box>[italic]Knowledge. Medicine. Hope.[/italic]</Box>
  <Box>[bold]Affiliation[/bold]</Box>
  <Box>Independent - Non-Aligned</Box>
  <Box>⬜ RESTRICTED ACCESS ⬜</Box>
  <Box></Box>
</Table>

<p>The [bold]Followers of the Apocalypse[/bold] were founded in the ruins of the Los Angeles Public Library - a group that believed knowledge, medicine, and education were more powerful tools for rebuilding civilization than any weapon or army. They have grown into one of the most respected organizations in the post-war West, running free clinics, teaching the illiterate, and maintaining one of the largest accessible archives of pre-war knowledge.</p>
<p>They are non-violent. They are non-aligned. And they will help anyone.</p>

## Philosophy

<ColorBox Color="#1a1a1a" OutlineColor="#666666" OutlineThickness="1" Margin="5">
  <Box Orientation="Vertical" Margin="8">
[italic]"The old world ended because people chose power over people. Our answer is to refuse that choice entirely. We document so mistakes are not forgotten. We educate so the cycle of ignorance cannot repeat. We treat the sick because suffering is not a political variable."[/italic]
  </Box>
</ColorBox>
<p>The Followers believe that the Great War was caused by humanity's unwillingness to share knowledge and resources. Their response is radical openness - free clinics, free education, and freely shared pre-war records. This philosophy puts them in direct conflict with the Brotherhood of Steel, who believe dangerous technology must be locked away rather than distributed.</p>

## Roles

<Table Columns="3">
  <Box>[bold]Role[/bold]</Box>
  <Box>[bold]Description[/bold]</Box>
  <Box>[bold]Notes[/bold]</Box>
  <Box>Followers Doctor</Box>
  <Box>Provide medical care to anyone who needs it. Your neutrality and your skills make you welcome almost anywhere. You will be tested by factions who want your resources turned toward their cause - hold your principles.</Box>
  <Box>Among the most trusted figures across all faction lines.</Box>
  <Box>[bold]Followers Scholar[/bold]</Box>
  <Box>Record what happens and why. Teach anyone willing to learn. Collect pre-war documents and technical knowledge. The events of a single round may matter to generations - document them accordingly.</Box>
  <Box>Archivists and educators. Their records are genuinely valuable to civilizations trying to rebuild.</Box>
  <Box>[bold]Followers Aid Worker[/bold]</Box>
  <Box>Assist in crisis situations. Distribute food, water, and basic medical supplies to those in need. You are the human face of the Followers' mission - how you conduct yourself in the field is the organization's reputation.</Box>
  <Box>First to arrive in a crisis, last to leave.</Box>
</Table>

## Relations

<p>The Followers are welcomed by most factions as neutral common ground. They serve as natural mediators in conflict and provide critical support during crises. Their strict non-violence principle is both their most respected quality and their most frequently exploited vulnerability.</p>

<Table Columns="3">
  <Box>[bold]Faction[/bold]</Box>
  <Box>[bold]Standing[/bold]</Box>
  <Box>[bold]Notes[/bold]</Box>
  <Box>[textlink="NCR" link="https://ss14.misfitsystems.net/wiki/index.php/New_California_Republic"/]</Box>
  <Box>Allies</Box>
  <Box>The NCR values the Followers' medical expertise and public goodwill. The relationship is cooperative but occasionally strained by political differences.</Box>
  <Box>[textlink="Brotherhood of Steel" link="https://ss14.misfitsystems.net/wiki/index.php/Brotherhood_of_Steel"/]</Box>
  <Box>Hostile</Box>
  <Box>The Brotherhood views the Followers' policy of freely sharing technology as reckless and dangerous. [italic]"Your 'charity' is dangerous, Follower."[/italic]</Box>
  <Box>[textlink="Caesar's Legion" link="https://ss14.misfitsystems.net/wiki/index.php/Caesar%27s_Legion"/]</Box>
  <Box>Hostile</Box>
  <Box>The Legion despises the Followers' pacifism and egalitarianism. Followers captured by the Legion rarely survive.</Box>
  <Box>[textlink="Townsfolk" link="https://ss14.misfitsystems.net/wiki/index.php/Townsfolk"/]</Box>
  <Box>Friendly</Box>
  <Box>Towns welcome Followers clinics and schools. The Followers are often the only organized medical presence available.</Box>
  <Box>[textlink="Wastelanders" link="https://ss14.misfitsystems.net/wiki/index.php/Wastelanders"/]</Box>
  <Box>Friendly</Box>
  <Box>Wastelanders rely on Followers clinics for treatment they cannot afford elsewhere.</Box>
  <Box>[textlink="Wasteland Tribes" link="https://ss14.misfitsystems.net/wiki/index.php/Wasteland_Tribes"/]</Box>
  <Box>Friendly</Box>
  <Box>Tribes respect the Followers' willingness to share knowledge without conditions.</Box>
  <Box>[textlink="Outlaws" link="https://ss14.misfitsystems.net/wiki/index.php/Outlaws"/]</Box>
  <Box>Cautious</Box>
  <Box>The Followers will treat anyone - including raiders - but they are under no illusions about the danger.</Box>
</Table>

</Document>
