<Document>
# One-Handed Melee

[textlink="View Full Wiki Page" link="https://ss14.misfitsystems.net/wiki/index.php/Melee_Weapons"]

<p>One-handed melee weapons are fast, easy to wield, and leave your other hand free for a shield, tool, or secondary weapon. They are ideal for close-quarters combat and self-defense.</p>

<hr/>

## Knives

<p>The most basic of survival tools — useful for crafting, hunting, and fighting.</p>

<ul>
<li>[bold]Combat Knife[/bold] — Military-grade fighting knife. Fast, light, and deadly in trained hands.</li>
<li>[bold]Kitchen Knife[/bold] — Common blade found in any pre-war ruin. Better than bare fists.</li>
<li>[bold]Tribal Knife[/bold] — Handmade tribal blade. Rough but effective.</li>
<li>[bold]Butcher's Cleaver[/bold] — Heavy chopping blade. Slow but deals serious wound damage.</li>
</ul>

<hr/>

## Hatchets and Axes

<p>Fast and reliable. A staple tool and weapon throughout the Wasteland.</p>

<ul>
<li>[bold]Hatchet[/bold] — Compact one-handed axe. Doubles as a tool and a weapon.</li>
<li>[bold]Tribal Hatchet[/bold] — Hand-forged hatchet with tribal markings. Light and quick.</li>
<li>[bold]Fire Axe[/bold] — Heavy emergency axe. Slower swing but excellent damage.</li>
</ul>

<hr/>

## Batons and Clubs

<p>Non-lethal options for subduing enemies, or improvised weapons when nothing else is available.</p>

<ul>
<li>[bold]Police Baton[/bold] — Standard-issue law enforcement baton. Good for subduing without killing.</li>
<li>[bold]Tribal Club[/bold] — Crude but effective blunt weapon. Common among tribal warriors.</li>
<li>[bold]Broken Pipe[/bold] — Scavenged plumbing turned weapon. Desperate but functional.</li>
</ul>

<hr/>

## Short Blades and Swords

<p>One-handed blades that deal more damage than knives while remaining swift.</p>

<ul>
<li>[bold]Machete[/bold] — The Wasteland's favourite all-purpose blade. Fast, reliable, and easy to maintain.</li>
<li>[bold]Scrap Machete[/bold] — Improvised machete made from junk metal. Rougher edge but still cuts.</li>
<li>[bold]Chinese Sword[/bold] — Pre-war military officer's blade. Well-balanced and sharp.</li>
<li>[bold]Ceremonial Sword[/bold] — Decorative but functional blade. Often carried by faction officers.</li>
</ul>
</Document>
