<Document>
# Townsfolk

[textlink="View Full Wiki Page" link="https://ss14.misfitsystems.net/wiki/index.php/Townsfolk"/]

<p>◈ Townsfolk ◈ Faction Dossier ◈ Civilian ◈</p>

<Table Columns="2">
  <Box>[bold]Townsfolk[/bold]</Box>
  <Box></Box>
  <Box>◈ FACTION DOSSIER ◈</Box>
  <Box></Box>
  <Box>[bold]Status[/bold]</Box>
  <Box>Active - Established</Box>
  <Box>[bold]Location[/bold]</Box>
  <Box>Wendover, Utah
Oasis Settlement</Box>
  <Box>[bold]Commander[/bold]</Box>
  <Box>Mayor (Elected)</Box>
  <Box>[bold]Ideology[/bold]</Box>
  <Box>Community Survival
Neutral Commerce</Box>
  <Box>[bold]Motto[/bold]</Box>
  <Box>[italic]Keep the gates open and the peace held.[/italic]</Box>
  <Box>[bold]Affiliation[/bold]</Box>
  <Box>Independent - Neutral</Box>
  <Box>⬜ RESTRICTED ACCESS ⬜</Box>
  <Box></Box>
</Table>

<p>The [bold]Townsfolk[/bold] are the civilians, settlers, and laborers who form the backbone of Wasteland society. They are not soldiers - they are the people who keep settlements running: shopkeepers, doctors, mechanics, farmers, and the law enforcement that holds it all together.</p>
<p>Wendover's settlement - [bold]Oasis[/bold] - is their home. Every other faction passes through it. What happens inside its walls is the Townsfolk's business.</p>

## Core Mission

<ColorBox Color="#1a1a1a" OutlineColor="#666666" OutlineThickness="1" Margin="5">
  <Box Orientation="Vertical" Margin="8">
[italic]"To provide a secure, neutral haven for trade, shelter, and survival, prioritizing the prosperity of our citizens and the strict enforcement of the peace, regardless of what colors you wear outside the gates."[/italic]
  </Box>
</ColorBox>

## Roles

<Table Columns="3">
  <Box>[bold]Role[/bold]</Box>
  <Box>[bold]Description[/bold]</Box>
  <Box>[bold]Notes[/bold]</Box>
  <Box>Mayor</Box>
  <Box>Lead Oasis. Coordinate with the Sheriff on security and negotiate with outside factions on behalf of your people. Every deal you make has consequences for every person in town.</Box>
  <Box>Town leadership. Final authority on civilian matters.</Box>
  <Box>[bold]Sheriff[/bold]</Box>
  <Box>Protect Oasis from threats internal and external. Manage your deputies, keep the peace, and work alongside the Mayor on anything that touches both law and politics.</Box>
  <Box>Law enforcement command.</Box>
  <Box>[bold]Deputy[/bold]</Box>
  <Box>Support the Sheriff. Enforce order, investigate problems, and step up when the Sheriff is unavailable. Your loyalty to the badge - and the people it's supposed to protect - defines what law means in Oasis.</Box>
  <Box>Requires Sheriff oversight.</Box>
  <Box>[bold]Shopkeeper[/bold]</Box>
  <Box>Stock and run the town's store. Trade with travelers, manage inventory, and keep the local economy moving. You may not carry a weapon to war, but caps talk - and yours talk loudly.</Box>
  <Box>Economic backbone of the settlement.</Box>
  <Box>[bold]Mechanic[/bold]</Box>
  <Box>Repair and maintain the settlement's critical equipment - weapons, armor, robots, and machinery. Craft new items for the town's defense or for sale to travelers. When something breaks, everyone comes to you.</Box>
  <Box>Engineering and crafting specialist.</Box>
  <Box>[bold]Doctor[/bold]</Box>
  <Box>Provide medical care to townsfolk and travelers. Charge for your services or give them freely - that is your call. Your skills will be needed before the round ends, regardless of how peacefully things start.</Box>
  <Box>Medical care provider.</Box>
  <Box>[bold]Townsperson[/bold]</Box>
  <Box>Work the land, tend animals, craft goods, and do what your town needs to stay alive. You are not a soldier - but the Wasteland has a way of making everyone a fighter eventually.</Box>
  <Box>General labor and community support.</Box>
</Table>

## Relations

<Table Columns="3">
  <Box>[bold]Faction[/bold]</Box>
  <Box>[bold]Standing[/bold]</Box>
  <Box>[bold]Notes[/bold]</Box>
  <Box>[textlink="NCR" link="https://ss14.misfitsystems.net/wiki/index.php/New_California_Republic"/]</Box>
  <Box>Cooperative</Box>
  <Box>The NCR provides security presence. The town provides a trading post and staging area.</Box>
  <Box>[textlink="Brotherhood of Steel" link="https://ss14.misfitsystems.net/wiki/index.php/Brotherhood_of_Steel"/]</Box>
  <Box>Cautious</Box>
  <Box>The Brotherhood is tolerated as long as they respect town neutrality. Their technology sweeps are disruptive.</Box>
  <Box>[textlink="Caesar's Legion" link="https://ss14.misfitsystems.net/wiki/index.php/Caesar%27s_Legion"/]</Box>
  <Box>Hostile</Box>
  <Box>The Legion views settled civilians as resources to be consumed. Towns are targets.</Box>
  <Box>[textlink="Followers of the Apocalypse" link="https://ss14.misfitsystems.net/wiki/index.php/Followers_of_the_Apocalypse"/]</Box>
  <Box>Friendly</Box>
  <Box>Followers clinics are welcomed. Free medical care benefits the entire community.</Box>
  <Box>[textlink="Wastelanders" link="https://ss14.misfitsystems.net/wiki/index.php/Wastelanders"/]</Box>
  <Box>Open</Box>
  <Box>Drifters and scavengers are welcome in town as long as they keep the peace.</Box>
  <Box>[textlink="Outlaws" link="https://ss14.misfitsystems.net/wiki/index.php/Outlaws"/]</Box>
  <Box>Hostile</Box>
  <Box>Raiders threaten the town's supplies, people, and peace.</Box>
  <Box>[textlink="Wasteland Tribes" link="https://ss14.misfitsystems.net/wiki/index.php/Wasteland_Tribes"/]</Box>
  <Box>Variable</Box>
  <Box>Relations depend on the tribe's leadership and the Mayor's diplomacy.</Box>
</Table>

<p>Townsfolk are one of the [bold]war-capable factions[/bold] and may declare or receive [textlink="faction war declarations" link="https://ss14.misfitsystems.net/wiki/index.php/Faction_War"/] during a round.</p>

</Document>
