<Document>
# Brotherhood of Steel (509th Chapter)

[textlink="View Full Wiki Page" link="https://ss14.misfitsystems.net/wiki/index.php/Brotherhood_of_Steel"]

<Table Columns="2">
  <p>[bold]Status[/bold]</p>  <p>[color=#4caf50]Active — Major Faction[/color]</p>
  <p>[bold]Base[/bold]</p>  <p>Wendover Airfield Bunker, Utah side</p>
  <p>[bold]Leadership[/bold]</p>  <p>Elder (509th Chapter Commander)</p>
  <p>[bold]Ideology[/bold]</p>  <p>Techno-Religious Preservation, Biological Purism</p>
  <p>[bold]Motto[/bold]</p>  <p>[italic]"Ad Victoriam"[/italic]</p>
</Table>

<p>The Brotherhood of Steel (BOS) is a techno-religious military order founded by Captain Roger Maxson. This specific expeditionary force is a direct offshoot of the Mojave Chapter, adhering strictly to the traditions of the West Coast High Elders.</p>

<hr/>

## Core Mission

<ColorBox Color="#1a1a1a" OutlineColor="#3B72BF" OutlineThickness="1" Margin="5">
  <Box Orientation="Vertical" Margin="8">
    [italic]"To identify, secure, and preserve advanced technology, preventing its catastrophic misuse by the ignorant or the corrupt. We are the sole vanguard against the mistakes of the past; the technology of the Old World is ours to protect, by any means necessary."[/italic]
  </Box>
</ColorBox>

<hr/>

## History: The Mojave Heritage

<p>[bold]The Rise (2250s):[/bold] Under Father Elijah, the chapter secured numerous pre-war sites, most notably the HELIOS One solar plant. Elijah's obsession with the facility diverted the chapter's focus from traditional mobile recovery, anchoring them to a fixed position that would draw the NCR's attention.</p>

<p>[bold]Operation Sunburst (2276):[/bold] The NCR launched a massive assault on HELIOS One. Despite the Brotherhood's technological superiority and T-51b Power Armor, they were outnumbered 15-to-1. The battle ended in a devastating retreat to the Hidden Valley bunker and the mysterious disappearance of Father Elijah, leaving the chapter fractured and depleted.</p>

<hr/>

## History: The Lockdown and Resurgence (2282–2296)

<p>[bold]The Kearny Occupation — The Silent Years:[/bold] Following the disaster at HELIOS One, a small detachment led by a REDACTED officer was dispatched toward the northeast salt flats. For over a decade they received no reinforcements and fewer than five transmissions. They survived on institutional stubbornness — salvaging local aerospace tech and maintaining T-51b suits with scavenged parts and salt-flat ingenuity. They became ghosts of the desert.</p>

<p>[bold]The Resurgence — The Enclave Catalyst:[/bold] By early 2296 the Brotherhood has begun a cautious but deliberate resurgence. The discovery of a renewed Enclave threat shattered the policy of isolation. The 509th has transitioned from Hidden Watcher to Active Vanguard, deploying small elite "Surgical Teams" deep into Utah territories to reclaim lost influence and secure untapped technological caches.</p>

<hr/>

## Cultural Dogma: The Purist Mindset

<ColorBox Color="#1a1a1a" OutlineColor="#3B72BF" OutlineThickness="1" Margin="5">
  <Box Orientation="Vertical" Margin="8">
    [italic]"The Brotherhood of Steel holds that technological and biological purity are the last bulwarks of humanity. We are the final uncorrupted lineage of mankind; all others are deviations, mutations, or outright abominations."[/italic]
  </Box>
</ColorBox>

<p>The Brotherhood practices a form of technological and biological elitism. All non-humans are classified under a tiered threat doctrine:</p>

<p>[bold]1. Biological Abominations[/bold] — Ghouls and Mutants. Tolerated at extreme distance. Not trusted, never recruited.</p>

<p>[bold]2. The Tool Tier[/bold] — Mr. Handy, Gutsy, Sentry Bots. Managed property. Audited for logic stability and prime directives.</p>

<p>[bold]3. The Abomination Tier[/bold] — Robobrains. Challenged status. The fusion of organic tissue with machine is an abomination of the worst order.</p>

<p>[bold]4. The Ultimate Threat[/bold] — Synths and Sentient AI. Destroy on sight. A self-aware machine is the endpoint of everything the Brotherhood exists to prevent.</p>

<hr/>

## Culture and Society

<p>Unlike splintered chapters that integrated with local populations, the Mojave Brotherhood remains a closed, techno-monastic society. They adhere strictly to the [bold]Chain of Binding[/bold] — a rigid command protocol where a member answers only to their immediate superior. This ensures that even if a member is captured, the entire organizational structure remains protected.</p>

<p>Every member, regardless of specialty, is expected to be a capable combatant and a scholar of the Codex. Collateral damage during recovery operations is often dismissed as a necessary sacrifice for the Greater Good of preventing another global catastrophe.</p>

<hr/>

## Brotherhood Hierarchy

<ColorBox Color="#3B72BF">
  <Box Margin="2">
  [bold]Elder[/bold]
  </Box>
</ColorBox>
<Box>
[color=#a4885c]Your role:[/color] Command the chapter. Technology acquisitions, alliances, and military operations require your authorization. Other factions will seek your ear first — or avoid you entirely. You interpret the Codex and hold final say on the Chain of Binding, balancing the survival of the bunker with the completion of the Mission.
</Box>

<br/>

<ColorBox Color="#3B72BF">
  <Box Margin="2">
  [bold]Head Knight / Head Scribe / Head Paladin[/bold]
  </Box>
</ColorBox>
<Box>
[color=#a4885c]Your role:[/color] Serve as the supreme leaders of your respective branches and the primary advisory body to the Elder. The Head Knight manages the armory and all Power Armor assets. The Head Scribe directs all research priorities and the preservation of archives. The Head Paladin serves as the Elder's primary tactical advisor.
</Box>

<br/>

<ColorBox Color="#3B72BF">
  <Box Margin="2">
  [bold]Senior Knight / Senior Scribe / Senior Paladin[/bold]
  </Box>
</ColorBox>
<Box>
[color=#a4885c]Your role:[/color] Act as field officers and mentors. You are responsible for the direct supervision of junior members and the execution of complex technical or tactical maneuvers. A Senior Paladin or Knight is often tasked with the final evaluation of an Initiate's readiness.
</Box>

<br/>

<ColorBox Color="#3B72BF">
  <Box Margin="2">
  [bold]Paladin[/bold]
  </Box>
</ColorBox>
<Box>
[color=#a4885c]Your role:[/color] Lead combat operations and enforce Brotherhood authority in the field. You are the Elder's arm. Elevated from the most elite Knights, Paladins are the only members permitted to lead independent recovery teams.
</Box>

<br/>

<ColorBox Color="#3B72BF">
  <Box Margin="2">
  [bold]Knight[/bold]
  </Box>
</ColorBox>
<Box>
[color=#a4885c]Your role:[/color] Protect Brotherhood territory, maintain weapons and armor, and carry out orders from Paladins and above. You are the Brotherhood's backbone in any engagement. Knights are the primary engineers and tactical operators of the Order, responsible for the field-readiness of T-51b Power Armor suits.
</Box>

<br/>

<ColorBox Color="#3B72BF">
  <Box Margin="2">
  [bold]Scribe[/bold]
  </Box>
</ColorBox>
<Box>
[color=#a4885c]Your role:[/color] Research, repair, and document Brotherhood technology. Your knowledge protects assets that no amount of force could replace. Scribes serve as the Brotherhood's scientists, engineers, medics, and archivists. They specialize in reverse-engineering pre-war technology. Rarely deployed into combat, but accompany Knights and Paladins when technical expertise is required.
</Box>

<br/>

<ColorBox Color="#3B72BF">
  <Box Margin="2">
  [bold]Squire[/bold]
  </Box>
</ColorBox>
<Box>
[color=#a4885c]Your role:[/color] Observe, assist, and master the technical foundations of the Brotherhood. Squires have transitioned from general labor to specialized apprenticeship under a senior mentor. Often assigned to a specific Knight or Paladin to assist with field maintenance of Power Armor and heavy weaponry. Permitted on low-risk recovery missions under direct supervision.
</Box>

<br/>

<ColorBox Color="#3B72BF">
  <Box Margin="2">
  [bold]Initiate[/bold]
  </Box>
</ColorBox>
<Box>
[color=#a4885c]Your role:[/color] Follow orders, learn the Brotherhood's ways, and prove your worth. You will be assigned the most demanding and least glamorous duties — and perform them without complaint. Initiates are the Chapter's future, required to undergo rigorous Squire training before being eligible for promotion.
</Box>

<hr/>

## Promotion Scripts

[bold]Initiate → Squire:[/bold]
[italic]Elder/Senior: "Initiate, you have performed your duties without complaint. You have shown the discipline required of the Brotherhood. But the path to the Steel is long. I hereby assign you to [Name] as their Squire. You will be their shadow. You will maintain their gear, carry their ammunition, and learn the weight of the Codex through their actions."[/italic]
[italic]Squire: "I accept the burden. Steel be with you."[/italic]

<br/>

[bold]Squire → Knight:[/bold]
[italic]Elder: "Squire [Name], your mentorship is complete. Your mentor vouches for your skill with the wrench and the rifle. You have proven that you understand technology is a burden, not a toy. By the authority of the High Elders, I promote you to the rank of Knight. We entrust you with the relics of the Old World. Guard them with your life. Rise, Knight [Name]. Ad Victoriam!"[/italic]
[italic]Knight: "I rise in service to the Chapter. Ad Victoriam."[/italic]

<hr/>

## Field Protocols: Technology Classification

<p>The Brotherhood categorizes gear into Tiers. Active intervention is generally reserved for Tier 3 technology.</p>

<p>[bold]Tier 1 — Ignore.[/bold] Service Rifles, Pistols, Leather Armor, Stimpaks. Standard wasteland gear.</p>

<p>[bold]Tier 2 — Monitor.[/bold] Laser Weaponry, Advanced SMG, Servo-Assisted Gauntlet. Note the owner and origin.</p>

<p>[bold]Tier 3 — Requisition.[/bold] Plasma/Gauss Weapons, Power Armor, Pip Boys, Holotapes.</p>

<hr/>

## Rules of Engagement: The Escalation Ladder

<p>When Tier 3 technology is identified in unauthorized hands (NCR, Legion, or Civilians), follow these steps:</p>

[bold]1. The Formal Request:[/bold] State the hazard and offer a trade if possible.
[italic]"Hold there, Wastelander. That Plasma Rifle is a dangerous relic of the Old World; you are unauthorized to possess it. For the safety of the wastes, we request you turn it over. In exchange, we can offer you Caps and a reliable Service Rifle."[/italic]

[bold]2. The Final Warning:[/bold] If the request is refused, weapons are drawn (but not fired).
[italic]"This is not a request, Trooper. Hand over the hardware now, or it will be secured by force. Final warning."[/italic]

[bold]3. Forced Seizure:[/bold] Combat is authorized only to disable the tech-user. Once down, BOS secures the specific item and retreats immediately.
[italic]"You chose the hard way. Ad Victoriam!"[/italic]

<p>[color=#a4885c]Strict Rule:[/color] Do NOT loot the player's personal items (food, water, armor, caps). Only the high-tech objective and its specific ammo are to be taken. Lethal force is only authorized under: direct orders from a higher ranking member, renewed hostile action from the subject, or environmental/situational threats endangering a Brotherhood member.</p>

<hr/>

## Formal Greetings and Mottos

<p>[bold]Ad Victoriam / Ad Victoriam:[/bold] "To Victory." The standard greeting, salute, and battle cry.</p>
<p>[bold]Steel Be With You:[/bold] A parting phrase, often used by Scribes or during somber moments.</p>
<p>[bold]Walk in the Light of the Founders:[/bold] A formal blessing reserved for ceremonies or Elders.</p>
<p>[bold]Knowledge is Our Shield:[/bold] A Scribe-favored motto emphasizing that preservation of technology is the Order's true protection.</p>
<p>[bold]By the Will of the Founders:[/bold] A formal declaration invoking the authority of the Founders; used when issuing orders rooted in doctrine rather than circumstance.</p>

<hr/>

## Brotherhood Lingo and Slang

<p>[bold]Abomination:[/bold] Any non-human threat (Ghouls, Mutants, Synths, Robobrains).</p>
<p>[bold]The Chain:[/bold] Short for the Chain of Binding (the command structure).</p>
<p>[bold]Relic:[/bold] Any piece of Tier 3 technology (Plasma, Power Armor, Pre-War data).</p>
<p>[bold]The Codex:[/bold] The governing set of laws for the Brotherhood.</p>
<p>[bold]Hard-Case:[/bold] A term used for someone in Power Armor (usually a Knight or Paladin).</p>

<hr/>

## Faction Relations (as of 2296)

<Table Columns="3">
  <p>[bold]Faction[/bold]</p>  <p>[bold]Standing[/bold]</p>  <p>[bold]Notes[/bold]</p>
  <p>NCR</p>  <p>[color=#f44336]Cold / Hostile[/color]</p>  <p>Ceasefire observed post-Sunburst</p>
  <p>Caesar's Legion</p>  <p>[color=#ff9800]Cautious[/color]</p>  <p>Primitive but dangerous; avoid unless tech at risk</p>
  <p>Wastelanders</p>  <p>[color=#ff9800]Dismissive[/color]</p>  <p>Ignorant civilians; tech confiscation likely</p>
  <p>Townsfolk</p>  <p>[color=#ffeb3b]Managed[/color]</p>  <p>Protected from threats, kept at arm's length</p>
  <p>Vault Dwellers</p>  <p>[color=#ff9800]Suspicious[/color]</p>  <p>Vault-Tec tech is of high interest</p>
  <p>Followers</p>  <p>[color=#f44336]Hostile[/color]</p>  <p>Tech-sharing philosophy is a direct threat</p>
  <p>Enclave</p>  <p>[color=#f44336]Kill on Sight[/color]</p>  <p>Existential threat; the catalyst for resurgence</p>
</Table>
</Document>
