<Document>
# Misfits: Nuclear Wasteland

<p>Welcome to Misfits: Nuclear Wasteland.</p>

<p>This is a Fallout-themed SS14 fork set in a harsh, persistent Wasteland shaped by player decisions. The server uses a hybrid approach to lore, drawing inspiration from canonical Fallout sources, extended materials, and original worldbuilding to create a grounded but flexible setting.</p>

<p>Our focus is immersive faction conflict, survival, politics, and player-driven narrative.</p>

<hr/>

## Roleplay

<p>Misfits operates under [bold]Medium Roleplay[/bold] standards.</p>

<p>This means:</p>

<ul>
<li>Roleplay quality matters.</li>
<li>Immersion is expected.</li>
<li>Character consistency is important.</li>
<li>Fun is still allowed.</li>
</ul>

<p>You are not the protagonist of the Wasteland. No one is.</p>

<p>Every player is part of a shared, evolving story. Before making drastic decisions, consider how your actions affect the broader narrative and the experience of others.</p>

<p>Stay in character whenever reasonably possible. Avoid unnecessary mechanical references or immersion breaks.</p>

<hr/>

## The Wasteland Philosophy

<p>[italic]The Wasteland does not protect you.[/italic]</p>

<p>Consequences are real. Death, capture, political fallout, and faction retaliation are part of the intended experience. Staff will enforce rules, not rewrite outcomes.</p>

<p>Your reputation, alliances, and choices define your path.</p>

<hr/>

## Getting Started

<p>If you are new, we recommend reviewing the following in order:</p>

<ul>
<li>[textlink="Server Rules" link="DefaultRuleset"]</li>
<li>[textlink="Factions Overview" link="Factions"]</li>
<li>[textlink="Survival Basics" link="N14SurvivalBasics"]</li>
<li>[textlink="Wiki — Full Guidebook" link="MisfitsWiki"]</li>
</ul>

<p>Not every profession or concept currently has a guide. If you are an experienced player and wish to contribute, we welcome community-written documentation.</p>

<p>[italic]The Wasteland is shaped by its players. Help build it.[/italic]</p>
</Document>