<Document>
# All Materials

[textlink="View Full Wiki Page" link="https://ss14.misfitsystems.net/wiki/index.php/Crafting"]

<p>This is a list of all available materials in the Wasteland.</p>

<hr/>

## Natural and Animal Products

<p>Water is a valuable resource. You will often find dirty or irradiated water in the Wasteland, which needs to be cleaned and disinfected to get clean drinking water.</p>

<ul>
<li>[bold]Clean Water[/bold] — purified, safe to drink</li>
<li>[bold]Dirty Water[/bold] — contaminated, causes illness if consumed raw</li>
<li>[bold]Irradiated Water[/bold] — contains radiation, avoid unless desperate</li>
</ul>

<p>Radscorpion tails can be harvested from radscorpions with a knife and used to produce antidote.</p>
<ul>
<li>[bold]Radscorpion Tail[/bold] — antidote ingredient, harvested with a knife</li>
</ul>

<p>Brahmin hide, hides, and chitin are harvested from the respective animals.</p>
<ul>
<li>[bold]Brahmin Hide[/bold] — leather crafting material</li>
</ul>

<p>For all other drinks and drink-related products, see the "Bartending" page.</p>

<hr/>

## Ores, Metals, and Derivatives

<p>Mine lead ore and process it in a forge to get lead ingots.</p>
<ul>
<li>[bold]Lead Ore[/bold] — mined from ore veins</li>
<li>[bold]Lead Ingot[/bold] — processed from ore at a forge</li>
</ul>

<p>Break down items to get some survival resources from them.</p>
<ul>
<li>[bold]Wrecked Sportscar[/bold] — salvageable for scrap</li>
<li>[bold]Scrap Lead[/bold] — recovered from salvage</li>
<li>[bold]Scrap Steel[/bold] — recovered from salvage</li>
<li>[bold]Rusted Computer Terminal[/bold] — salvageable for electronics</li>
<li>[bold]Junk TV[/bold] — salvageable for electronics</li>
<li>[bold]Scrap Copper[/bold] — recovered from electronics</li>
<li>[bold]Scrap Electronic[/bold] — recovered from electronics</li>
</ul>

<p>Mine sulfur ore and process it in a forge to get sulfur powder.</p>
<ul>
<li>[bold]Sulfur Ore[/bold] — mined from ore veins</li>
<li>[bold]Sulfur Powder[/bold] — processed from ore at a forge</li>
</ul>

<p>Gather fertilizer from rocks and grind it to get fertilizer as a reagent.</p>
<ul>
<li>[bold]Fertilizer[/bold] — ground from rocks; used in farming and gunpowder recipes</li>
</ul>

<p>If you need compost immediately, you can also slurry dung with water to make rotten compost for soil and farming recipes.</p>
<ul>
<li>[bold]Rotten Compost[/bold] — made from dung and water; used for soil beds</li>
</ul>

<p>Combine fertilizer, sulfur powder, and carbon (from coal) to make gunpowder.</p>
<ul>
<li>[bold]Gunpowder[/bold] — crafted from fertilizer, sulfur powder, and carbon</li>
</ul>

<hr/>

## Wood and Wood Products

<p>Wooden planks can be made from wooden logs harvested from trees. Then they can be used to make paper, and paper to make cardboard.</p>
<ul>
<li>[bold]Wood Plank[/bold] — processed from logs; base for paper and cardboard</li>
</ul>

<hr/>

## Other Materials

<p>Plastic can be obtained by melting down pre-war plastic scrap with a welding tool, by a chemical reaction, or with a recycler if you can find one.</p>
<ul>
<li>[bold]Sheet Plastic[/bold] — melted from scrap or produced chemically</li>
</ul>

<hr/>

## Pre-War Products

<p>Mr. Handy fuel can be found while exploring the Wasteland, and it is a handy fuel source for welding tools and generators.</p>
<ul>
<li>[bold]Mr. Handy Fuel Tank[/bold] — fuel for welding tools and generators</li>
</ul>
</Document>
