<Document>
# Survival Basics

[textlink="View Full Wiki Page" link="https://ss14.misfitsystems.net/wiki/index.php/Survival"]

<p>Life in the Wasteland is hostile by default. Food, water, radiation, and weather all matter, and neglecting any of them for too long will kill you.</p>

<p>To survive long term, you need [color=green]food[/color] and [color=green]water[/color]. The day-night cycle lasts one hour, and during that span you need to eat and drink at least once.</p>

<hr/>

## Water

<p>Clean water is one of the most important resources in Nuclear 14. Many water sources are dirty or irradiated, so drinking whatever you find is a fast way to get sick.</p>

<ul>
<li>[bold]Filtered Water[/bold] — Safe to drink. Restores thirst without side effects.</li>
<li>[bold]Dirty Water[/bold] — Drinkable in a pinch but carries a risk of illness.</li>
<li>[bold]Irradiated Water[/bold] — Quenches thirst but adds radiation exposure. Avoid unless desperate.</li>
</ul>

<p>Purify water with filters, chemistry, or boiling whenever you can.</p>

<hr/>

## Food

<p>You need a steady food supply. Gather wild plants, hunt animals, trade for supplies, or grow crops if your settlement has the space.</p>

<ul>
<li>[bold]Carrots[/bold] — Common wild vegetable. Safe to eat raw.</li>
<li>[bold]Cram[/bold] — Pre-war canned meat. Long shelf life and decent nutrition.</li>
<li>[bold]Cooked Ribs[/bold] — Grilled meat meal. Good nutrition when prepared properly.</li>
</ul>

<p>Cook raw meat before eating it, and do not assume every plant or scavenged meal is safe.</p>

<hr/>

## Radiation

<p>Radiation is everywhere in the Wasteland. Watch exposure levels, carry treatment when possible, and avoid contaminated areas unless you are equipped for them.</p>

<ul>
<li>[bold]Geiger Counter[/bold] — Handheld radiation detector. Essential for scouting contaminated zones.</li>
<li>[bold]RadAway Inhaler[/bold] — Flushes radiation from the bloodstream. The primary treatment for rad exposure.</li>
<li>[bold]Rad-X[/bold] — Pre-exposure prophylactic. Take it before entering a hot zone to resist radiation buildup.</li>
</ul>

<p>If a zone is hot, move quickly, wear protection, and clear the dose before it stacks up.</p>

<hr/>

## Weather and Exposure

<p>Weather can be as deadly as combat. Sandstorms, acid rain, and sharp temperature swings all punish unprepared survivors.</p>

<ul>
<li>[bold]Gas Mask[/bold] — Filters airborne toxins and protects against sandstorms and acid rain.</li>
<li>[bold]Leather Duster[/bold] — Rugged overcoat that provides moderate protection against the elements.</li>
</ul>

<p>Keep protective clothing, a face covering, and spare supplies ready before you travel far from shelter.</p>
</Document>