<Document>
# Laser Weapons

[textlink="View Full Wiki Page" link="https://ss14.misfitsystems.net/wiki/index.php/Laser%20Weapons"/]

## Energy Weapons (Laser)

<p>Energy weapons use focused laser technology to deliver precise, armor-punching hits. They do not use conventional ammunition, relying instead on power cells and other specialized energy feeds.</p>
<p>These weapons are rare and expensive, and are most often seen in the hands of the Brotherhood of Steel, the Enclave, and elite scavengers.</p>

<h3 Text="Laser Pistols"/>

<p>Compact laser sidearms useful for self-defense, patrol work, and precision shooting.</p>

<Table Columns="2">
  <Box>[bold]Weapon[/bold]</Box>
  <Box>[bold]Notes[/bold]</Box>
  <Box>[bold]Laser Pistol[/bold]</Box>
  <Box>Standard laser sidearm. Common in Brotherhood inventory.</Box>
  <Box>[bold]Laser Revolver[/bold]</Box>
  <Box>Revolver-frame laser weapon. Craftable via blueprint.</Box>
  <Box>[bold]Recharger Pistol[/bold]</Box>
  <Box>Self-recharging laser pistol. No ammunition required, but lower output.</Box>
</Table>

<h3 Text="Laser Rifles"/>

<p>Laser rifles deliver reliable ranged damage and are iconic weapons for advanced factions.</p>

<Table Columns="2">
  <Box>[bold]Weapon[/bold]</Box>
  <Box>[bold]Notes[/bold]</Box>
  <Box>[bold]Laser Rifle[/bold]</Box>
  <Box>Standard pre-war laser rifle. Precision and reliable.</Box>
  <Box>[bold]Auto Laser Rifle[/bold]</Box>
  <Box>Automatic-fire variant. Higher rate of fire, more energy consumption.</Box>
  <Box>[bold]AER14 Prototype[/bold]</Box>
  <Box>Experimental pre-war design. High performance, extremely rare.</Box>
  <Box>[bold]Wattz 3000[/bold]</Box>
  <Box>Pre-war high-end laser rifle. Superior range and damage.</Box>
</Table>

<h3 Text="Gatling Laser"/>

<p>The Gatling Laser is a heavy beam weapon capable of sustained fire that can shred exposed targets very quickly.</p>

<Table Columns="2">
  <Box>[bold]Weapon[/bold]</Box>
  <Box>[bold]Notes[/bold]</Box>
  <Box>[bold]Gatling Laser[/bold]</Box>
  <Box>Heavy beam weapon. Sustained fire, devastating against exposed targets.</Box>
</Table>

<h3 Text="Improvised Energy Weapons"/>

<p>Makeshift and crude laser weapons built from salvaged parts. Usually less reliable than pre-war models, but far more accessible.</p>

<Table Columns="2">
  <Box>[bold]Weapon[/bold]</Box>
  <Box>[bold]Notes[/bold]</Box>
  <Box>[bold]Crude Laser Rifle[/bold]</Box>
  <Box>Post-war construction. Less accurate, lower output than pre-war.</Box>
  <Box>[bold]Makeshift Laser Rifle[/bold]</Box>
  <Box>Craftable via blueprint. Better than crude but still imprecise.</Box>
</Table>

</Document>
