<Document>
# Wastelanders

[textlink="View Full Wiki Page" link="https://ss14.misfitsystems.net/wiki/index.php/Wastelanders"]

<Table Columns="2">
  <Box>[bold]Status[/bold]</Box>
  <Box>Active — Independent survivors</Box>
  <Box>[bold]Location[/bold]</Box>
  <Box>Everywhere</Box>
  <Box>[bold]Leadership[/bold]</Box>
  <Box>None — individual autonomy</Box>
  <Box>[bold]Ideology[/bold]</Box>
  <Box>Personal code, survival, independence</Box>
  <Box>[bold]Motto[/bold]</Box>
  <Box>[italic]"Nobody's soldier. Nobody's enemy. Not by default."[/italic]</Box>
</Table>

<hr/>

<p>Wastelanders are the independent survivors of the nuclear devastation — people who belong to no faction, answer to no flag, and make their living on the open Wasteland through skill, instinct, and personal code. They are the beating heart of every Fallout story: wanderers who walk into every situation without a predetermined role and walk out having shaped it.</p>

<p>No two wastelanders are alike. Former raiders who went straight. Travelers heading somewhere better. Drifters who have been walking since before they can remember. What they share is a refusal to be defined by anyone else's war.</p>

<hr/>

## Philosophy

<ColorBox Color="#1a1a1a" OutlineColor="#81c784" OutlineThickness="1" Margin="5">
  <Box Orientation="Vertical" Margin="8">
    [italic]"There is no single wastelander philosophy — that is the point. Independence and personal code are all that connects them."[/italic]
  </Box>
</ColorBox>

<p>Some run by honor, others by caps, others by something harder to name. The Wasteland does not ask for justification. Only survival.</p>

<hr/>

## Roles

<ColorBox Color="#81c784">
  <Box Margin="2">
  [bold]Drifter[/bold]
  </Box>
</ColorBox>
<Box>
[color=#a4885c]Your role:[/color] You are nobody's soldier and nobody's enemy by default. Make alliances, take contracts, pursue your own goals — or make someone else's goals your own. You are the wildcard this round needs.
</Box>

<br/>

<ColorBox Color="#81c784">
  <Box Margin="2">
  [bold]Scavenger[/bold]
  </Box>
</ColorBox>
<Box>
[color=#a4885c]Your role:[/color] Explore, recover, and trade. You know what things are worth and where to look for them. The resources you bring back keep the local economy moving — and your own caps flowing.
</Box>

<br/>

<ColorBox Color="#81c784">
  <Box Margin="2">
  [bold]Wasteland Medic[/bold]
  </Box>
</ColorBox>
<Box>
[color=#a4885c]Your role:[/color] Provide medical care to anyone who needs it — for caps, for favors, or out of principle. Your neutrality is a strength: you can go where soldiers cannot and be trusted where guns would get the door slammed.
</Box>

<hr/>

## Faction Relations

<Table Columns="3">
  <Box>[bold][color=#a4885c]Faction[/color][/bold]</Box>
  <Box>[bold][color=#a4885c]Standing[/color][/bold]</Box>
  <Box>[bold][color=#a4885c]Notes[/color][/bold]</Box>
  <Box>NCR</Box>
  <Box>[color=#a4885c]Variable[/color]</Box>
  <Box>Depends on your choices. Some wastelanders work for the NCR; others avoid them.</Box>
  <Box>Brotherhood of Steel</Box>
  <Box>[color=#a4885c]Variable[/color]</Box>
  <Box>Will confiscate advanced tech if they spot it on you.</Box>
  <Box>Caesar's Legion</Box>
  <Box>[color=#cc3333]Hostile[/color]</Box>
  <Box>The Legion views unaffiliated people as recruits, slaves, or obstacles.</Box>
  <Box>Townsfolk</Box>
  <Box>[color=#6bba5e]Welcome[/color]</Box>
  <Box>Drifters are welcome in town if they keep the peace.</Box>
  <Box>Tribes</Box>
  <Box>[color=#a4885c]Variable[/color]</Box>
  <Box>Some tribes welcome travelers, others do not.</Box>
  <Box>Caravan Company</Box>
  <Box>[color=#6bba5e]Friendly[/color]</Box>
  <Box>Good source of caps and contracts for independent operators.</Box>
</Table>

<p>[color=#a4885c]Note:[/color] Wastelanders can use [bold]/warjoin[/bold] to join an active faction war on either side.</p>
</Document>
