<Document>
# Big Guns

[textlink="View Full Wiki Page" link="https://ss14.misfitsystems.net/wiki/index.php/Big%20Guns"/]

## Big Guns

<p>Big Guns are heavy weapons that deal devastating damage. They are difficult to carry and expensive to feed, but nothing matches their raw stopping power once a fight turns serious.</p>
<p>[bold]Warning:[/bold] Big Guns are usually restricted to military-grade factions. Carrying one openly is enough to attract attention almost anywhere in the Wasteland.</p>

<h3 Text="Miniguns"/>

<p>Miniguns deliver overwhelming volume of fire and are best used for suppression, defense, and faction-level fire superiority.</p>

<Table Columns="2">
  <Box>[bold]Weapon[/bold]</Box>
  <Box>[bold]Notes[/bold]</Box>
  <Box>[bold]Minigun[/bold]</Box>
  <Box>Standard heavy minigun. High sustained fire rate.</Box>
  <Box>[bold]Avenger Minigun[/bold]</Box>
  <Box>Enhanced variant. Higher damage and accuracy than standard.</Box>
</Table>

<h3 Text="Launchers"/>

<p>Grenade and missile launchers are area-denial weapons that break fortified positions and punish clustered enemies.</p>

<Table Columns="2">
  <Box>[bold]Weapon[/bold]</Box>
  <Box>[bold]Notes[/bold]</Box>
  <Box>[bold]Grenade Launcher[/bold]</Box>
  <Box>Launches explosive grenades at medium range.</Box>
  <Box>[bold]Missile Launcher[/bold]</Box>
  <Box>Fires guided missiles. Maximum area denial.</Box>
  <Box>[bold]Grenade Rifle[/bold]</Box>
  <Box>Shoulder-fired grenade launcher. More portable than the standard launcher.</Box>
</Table>

<h3 Text="Light Machine Guns"/>

<p>LMGs provide sustained automatic fire and excel in prepared positions or coordinated squad fights.</p>

<Table Columns="2">
  <Box>[bold]Weapon[/bold]</Box>
  <Box>[bold]Notes[/bold]</Box>
  <Box>[bold]Light Machine Gun (LMG)[/bold]</Box>
  <Box>Belt-fed automatic. High sustained fire in defensive positions.</Box>
  <Box>[bold]Auto Rifle (LMG variant)[/bold]</Box>
  <Box>Lighter LMG profile. More mobile than belt-fed.</Box>
</Table>

<h3 Text="Flamers"/>

<p>The flamer projects burning fuel across a wide area and is especially effective against creatures and lightly armored targets.</p>

<Table Columns="2">
  <Box>[bold]Weapon[/bold]</Box>
  <Box>[bold]Notes[/bold]</Box>
  <Box>[bold]Flamer[/bold]</Box>
  <Box>Wide area incendiary. Very effective at close range against flesh and lightly armored targets.</Box>
</Table>

</Document>
