<Document>
# New California Republic

[textlink="View Full Wiki Page" link="https://ss14.misfitsystems.net/wiki/index.php/New%20California%20Republic"/]

<p>◈ New California Republic ◈ Salt Dogs Battalion ◈ Bonneville Station ◈</p>

<Table Columns="2">
  <Box>[bold]New California Republic[/bold]</Box>
  <Box></Box>
  <Box>◈ FACTION DOSSIER ◈</Box>
  <Box></Box>
  <Box>[bold]Status[/bold]</Box>
  <Box>Active - Forward Deployed</Box>
  <Box>[bold]Location[/bold]</Box>
  <Box>Bonneville Station, Nevada side
Wendover Bridge Corridor</Box>
  <Box>[bold]Commander[/bold]</Box>
  <Box>Major Blackhawk & Major Walker
Ranger DAGGER-02 (Intel)</Box>
  <Box>[bold]Ideology[/bold]</Box>
  <Box>Democratic Federalism
Rule of Law · Expansionism</Box>
  <Box>[bold]Motto[/bold]</Box>
  <Box>[italic]Bear the Republic's burden[/italic]</Box>
  <Box>[bold]Affiliation[/bold]</Box>
  <Box>New California Republic</Box>
  <Box>⬜ RESTRICTED ACCESS ⬜</Box>
  <Box></Box>
</Table>

<p>The [bold]New California Republic[/bold] (NCR) stands as a beacon of democracy and order in the wasteland - a federal presidential republic rooted in old values of democracy, personal freedom, and the sanctity of law. Founded by Aradesh and his daughter Tandi in Shady Sands, it is now led by President Aaron Kimball. The NCR's mission is to restore civilization, uplift infrastructure and economic frameworks, and foster peace. But the Republic is not devoid of flaws: it grapples with expansion, territorial disputes, wavering loyalties, and rising corruption.</p>

## Bonneville Station

<h3 Text="The Salt Dogs Battalion"/>

<p>The NCR's foothold east of Nevada is held by the [bold]Salt Dogs Battalion[/bold], garrisoned at Bonneville Station on the Nevada side of the Wendover bridge. The Utah side is maintained as a forward checkpoint on rotation. The bridge itself is a permanent NCR asset - it does not change hands.</p>
<p>The battalion is commanded jointly by [bold]Major Blackhawk[/bold] and [bold]Major Walker[/bold]. Intelligence operations are coordinated by [bold]DAGGER-02[/bold], a Ranger attached from regional command.</p>
<p>Wendover sits at the last real chokepoint before Utah opens into open wastes. I-80 runs through it. The salt trade runs through it. Whatever moves east or west in this region moves through Bonneville, and the Salt Dogs are there to make sure the NCR has a say in how it moves.</p>

<h3 Text="Strategic Context: DAGGER-02 Field Report"/>

<ColorBox Color="#1a1a1a" OutlineColor="#666666" OutlineThickness="1" Margin="5">
  <Box Orientation="Vertical" Margin="8">
[italic]"Station is established. Major Blackhawk and Major Walker are on the ground and operational. I'll be plain: given the current situation back home, I'm not certain who is reading this or in what capacity anymore. I'm filing it anyway. That's the job. We're here for I-80 and salt. Wendover is the last real chokepoint before Utah opens up. The salt funds the operation, which matters more now than it did when we were assigned here. Nevada side of the bridge is home base. Utah side is a forward checkpoint on rotation. The bridge stays ours. The Brotherhood has dug into the old airfield on the Utah side. They're not here by accident and they aren't telling us why. Nothing actionable yet. Legion presence has been noted in the region. Unknown which Legio, considering the civil war. Extent and intent unknown. Command should consider this when reviewing resupply prioritization.  - DAGGER-02, attached, Bonneville Station  Co-signed: Major Blackhawk, Major Walker - Salt Dogs Battalion, NCR"[/italic]
  </Box>
</ColorBox>

## Laws

<p>Dictated by the constitution of the Republic, every citizen of the NCR - civilian or military - must follow these laws.</p>
<p>It is a crime to [bold]take the life of another[/bold], be it murder or manslaughter. These acts are harshly punished; depending on severity, punishment can reach execution. It is a crime to [bold]steal from another[/bold] regardless of circumstances, punishable by prison with the possibility of parole.</p>

<h3 Text="Basic Rights"/>

<p>All citizens hold the following universal rights which may not be infringed upon:</p>

<div>
<ul>
<li>The right to own personal property</li>
<li>The right to freedom of expression, religion, and speech</li>
<li>The right to self-defense</li>
<li>The right to bear a sidearm and concealed carry inside NCR-controlled territories</li>
<li>The right to enlist</li>
<li>The right to an attorney</li>
<li>The right to remain silent in cases of self-incrimination</li>
<li>The right to a fair trial</li>
</ul>
</div>

<p>In the case of criminal arrest, all rights barring the right to remain silent, to a fair trial, and to an attorney are suspended.</p>

<h3 Text="Treason"/>

<p>All acts of treason are, in most cases, punishable by death. Includes: fraternizing with or providing information to an enemy of the state, terrorism, desertion, and dereliction of duty.</p>

<h3 Text="Fraudulent Activities"/>

<p>Punishable by prison or voluntary labor. Includes: money laundering, identity theft, falsification of reports or official documents, forgery of currency, and the sale/distribution of illicit substances (Jet, Psycho, Turbo).</p>

## New California Republic Army (NCRA)

<p>The defense forces of the Republic. The NCRA must tackle conflicts in a non-aggressive way - de-escalate first, deal with threats using the minimum force possible.</p>
<ColorBox Color="#1a1a1a" OutlineColor="#666666" OutlineThickness="1" Margin="5">
  <Box Orientation="Vertical" Margin="8">
[italic]"The mission of the NCR is to uphold the law in the region, as well as trying to gain anything valuable - trading with major powers or settlements, or obtaining resources from the area. Expansionism is allowed but only by diplomacy or to expel a threat. Keeping a good image of the Republic is key."[/italic]
  </Box>
</ColorBox>

<h3 Text="Basic Principles"/>

<div>
<ul>
<li>Follow the rules of war and human rights</li>
<li>Obey the chain of command</li>
<li>While on duty, do not drink alcohol or gamble</li>
<li>Treat prisoners with respect and dignity; field execution requires officer or High Command authorization</li>
<li>Wear your uniform at all times. Dog tags and rank pins must always be visible</li>
<li>Going off-duty requires chain-of-command approval; always ask command before stepping down</li>
</ul>
</div>

<p>[bold]Field Promotions[/bold] are legal. An NCO may promote enlisted personnel; a CO may promote an NCO for exceptional service. Cannot promote between branches, nor skip from enlisted to officer.</p>

<h3 Text="Chain of Command"/>

<Table Columns="3">
  <Box>[bold]Rank[/bold]</Box>
  <Box>[bold]Type[/bold]</Box>
  <Box>[bold]Role[/bold]</Box>
  <Box>Captain</Box>
  <Box>CO</Box>
  <Box>Command the NCR's local detachment. All military and diplomatic decisions run through you.</Box>
  <Box>[bold]Lieutenant[/bold]</Box>
  <Box>CO</Box>
  <Box>Second-in-command. Support the Captain, manage day-to-day operations, step into command when needed.</Box>
  <Box>[bold]Medical Doctor[/bold]</Box>
  <Box>CO (attached)</Box>
  <Box>Senior medical officer. Keep soldiers combat-capable; advise command on medical threats. Your skills are a diplomatic asset.</Box>
  <Box>[bold]Sergeant First Class[/bold]</Box>
  <Box>NCO</Box>
  <Box>Senior NCO of the detachment. Translate officer intent into enlisted action; enforce discipline; manage formation readiness.</Box>
  <Box>[bold]Staff Sergeant[/bold]</Box>
  <Box>NCO</Box>
  <Box>Senior squad leader. Lead troops in the field and coordinate with the Sergeant First Class.</Box>
  <Box>[bold]Sergeant[/bold]</Box>
  <Box>NCO</Box>
  <Box>Squad leader. Know your soldiers, execute direction, and make the right call when there is no time to ask.</Box>
  <Box>[bold]Specialist[/bold]</Box>
  <Box>Enlisted</Box>
  <Box>Trained specialist serving in combat, engineering, or medical roles. Pick your loadout to match the mission.</Box>
  <Box>[bold]Private First Class[/bold]</Box>
  <Box>Enlisted</Box>
  <Box>Experienced private. Proven reliable - better gear, more latitude, more trust from NCOs.</Box>
  <Box>[bold]Private[/bold]</Box>
  <Box>Enlisted</Box>
  <Box>Standard soldier. Enforce NCR authority, protect personnel and assets, and carry out orders.</Box>
  <Box>[bold]Recruit[/bold]</Box>
  <Box>Enlisted</Box>
  <Box>Newest enlistee. You are at the bottom of a long ladder. Follow orders, learn the ropes, avoid getting yourself or your squadmates killed.</Box>
</Table>

## New California Republic Rangers (NCRR)

<p>The Rangers - originally descended from Pre-War Rangers - are the elite soldiers of the NCR. A volunteer special force renowned for survival, reconnaissance, scouting, sabotage, and martial arts. Their primary purpose is dealing with threats the regular NCRA cannot handle.</p>
<p>The Rangers are the living image of NCR ideals of liberty, justice, and freedom from tyrants, slavers, and raiders.</p>
<ul>
<li>A [bold]Ranger[/bold] holds authority equivalent to a Sergeant.</li>
<li>A [bold]Veteran Ranger[/bold] holds authority equivalent to an Officer.</li>
<li>Rangers operate with autonomy but cooperate with NCRA partners. They can give orders to the NCRA if no NCRA command is available.</li>
</ul>

## Crime and Punishment

<p>Punishment in the NCR is divided between Non-Judicial and Judicial Punishment.</p>

<h3 Text="Non-Judicial Punishment (NJP)"/>

<p>For less severe offenses. Given by NCOs and Officers in the field. These punishments must best fit the severity of the offense and cannot be cruel or arbitrary.</p>
<ul>
<li>Reprimand · Forfeiture of Pay · Extra Duty · Diminished Rations</li>
<li>Confinement to Base or Brig</li>
<li>Loss of Rank (requires Captain or higher approval)</li>
</ul>

<h3 Text="Judicial Punishment (JP)"/>

<p>Determined after court martial for major or capital offenses.</p>
<ul>
<li>Other Than Honorable Discharge · Dishonorable Discharge</li>
<li>Execution via Firing Squad or Hanging</li>
<li>Barred from Reenlistment</li>
</ul>

<h3 Text="Court Martial"/>

<p>Requested by high-ranking members or the Military Police. Handles serious crimes between NCRA and NCRR. Non-military personnel are not sentenced to Court Martial - they receive a Civilian Court Trial. Court martials take time; they are not instantaneous.</p>

## List of Offenses

<Table Columns="4">
  <Box>[bold]Offense[/bold]</Box>
  <Box>[bold]Category[/bold]</Box>
  <Box>[bold]Description[/bold]</Box>
  <Box>[bold]Punishment[/bold]</Box>
  <Box>Assault, Verbal</Box>
  <Box>MR</Box>
  <Box>Threatening to use physical force against a person.</Box>
  <Box>Brig (5 min)</Box>
  <Box>Hooliganism</Box>
  <Box>MR</Box>
  <Box>Loud yelling on comms after being warned, throwing garbage, breaking windows.</Box>
  <Box>Brig (5 min)</Box>
  <Box>Insubordination, Minor</Box>
  <Box>MR</Box>
  <Box>Disobeying a lawful order; undermining authority without inciting mutiny.</Box>
  <Box>Brig (10 min)</Box>
  <Box>Failure of Proper Conduct</Box>
  <Box>MR</Box>
  <Box>Poor grooming, improper uniform, friendly fire, public misconduct.</Box>
  <Box>Situational; brig (5–10 min)</Box>
  <Box>Neglect of Duty</Box>
  <Box>MR</Box>
  <Box>Careless or intentional failure to perform official duties.</Box>
  <Box>Loss of rank; brig (10 min)</Box>
  <Box>Substance Abuse (legal)</Box>
  <Box>MR</Box>
  <Box>Use of permitted substances (Med-X) while on-duty without medical authorization.</Box>
  <Box>NJP (10 min)</Box>
  <Box>AWOL</Box>
  <Box>MR</Box>
  <Box>Abandoning post without authorization, with intention to return.</Box>
  <Box>Situational; loss of rank, dismissal (10–20 min)</Box>
  <Box>Drug Trafficking (legal)</Box>
  <Box>MR</Box>
  <Box>Selling alcohol on-duty.</Box>
  <Box>NJP (10 min)</Box>
  <Box>Assault, Physical</Box>
  <Box>MR–MO</Box>
  <Box>Attacking with body only (MR); use of weapons escalates to MO.</Box>
  <Box>Body: brig (10 min). Weapons: loss of rank (20 min)</Box>
  <Box>Substance Abuse (illegal)</Box>
  <Box>MR–MO</Box>
  <Box>Use of Jet, Psycho, etc. even off-duty. Send to medbay.</Box>
  <Box>Loss of rank (20 min)</Box>
  <Box>Drug Trafficking (illegal)</Box>
  <Box>MR–MO–CO</Box>
  <Box>Selling Jet, Psycho, etc. Can escalate to CO for repeat offenses.</Box>
  <Box>Demotion; can reach life imprisonment</Box>
  <Box>Fraternization</Box>
  <Box>MO</Box>
  <Box>Undue relationship between enlisted/NCO and a Commissioned Officer.</Box>
  <Box>Dismissal or loss of rank (20 min)</Box>
  <Box>Manslaughter</Box>
  <Box>MO</Box>
  <Box>Unintentional death through negligence.</Box>
  <Box>Dismissal or loss of rank (until next shift)</Box>
  <Box>Abandonment of Duty</Box>
  <Box>MO</Box>
  <Box>Willingly failing to report to assigned post.</Box>
  <Box>Loss of rank (20 min)</Box>
  <Box>Assaulting/Disobeying an Officer</Box>
  <Box>MO</Box>
  <Box>Disobeying lawful order from an Officer, or physically assaulting one.</Box>
  <Box>Dismissal or loss of rank (20 min or until next shift)</Box>
  <Box>Sedition</Box>
  <Box>MO</Box>
  <Box>Conspiring or openly opposing rightful authorities and the rule of law.</Box>
  <Box>Dismissal or loss of rank (until next shift)</Box>
  <Box>Desertion</Box>
  <Box>MO</Box>
  <Box>Willingly abandoning post with no intention of return.</Box>
  <Box>Execution or life imprisonment (until next shift)</Box>
  <Box>Fraternization with Enemy</Box>
  <Box>MO</Box>
  <Box>Cooperating with any enemy of the NCR. Escalates to CO if an ongoing relationship exists.</Box>
  <Box>Execution or life imprisonment (until next shift)</Box>
  <Box>Insubordination, Major</Box>
  <Box>MO–CO</Box>
  <Box>Disobeying orders, resulting in mutiny, NCR casualties, or desertion in force.</Box>
  <Box>Dismissal (until next shift); escalates to CO if it triggers a shootout</Box>
  <Box>Use of Mercenaries</Box>
  <Box>CO</Box>
  <Box>Paying civilians or non-NCR personnel to fight for the NCR.</Box>
  <Box>Execution or life imprisonment (until next shift)</Box>
  <Box>Treason</Box>
  <Box>CO</Box>
  <Box>Giving shelter or aid to enemies of the NCR, or working against the NCR while owing it allegiance.</Box>
  <Box>Execution or life imprisonment (until next shift)</Box>
  <Box>Murder</Box>
  <Box>CO</Box>
  <Box>Intentionally killing a person, with or without forethought.</Box>
  <Box>Execution or life imprisonment (until next shift)</Box>
  <Box>Sabotage</Box>
  <Box>CO</Box>
  <Box>Hindering military operations; destroying NCR equipment, comms, medication, or weapons.</Box>
  <Box>Execution or life imprisonment (until next shift)</Box>
  <Box>Cannibalism</Box>
  <Box>CO</Box>
  <Box>Willingly and knowingly consuming a human, ghoul, or sapient mutant.</Box>
  <Box>Execution or life imprisonment (until next shift)</Box>
</Table>

<p>[bold]Modifiers:[/bold] Aggravating factors (repeating an offense, refusing to cooperate) make punishment harsher. Mitigating factors (surrendering, cooperating) make it less harsh.</p>

## Dress Code

<p>All on-duty personnel must be in full uniform during all NCR operations. Cadets cannot modify their issued loadout. Upon reaching NCO rank, soldiers may wear non-NCR apparel (cowboy hats, bandanas), provided they remain identifiable as NCR personnel.</p>

<h3 Text="Hair Regulations"/>

<p>Hair must be well-groomed, natural color, cut no further than the shoulders or tied back, and fit underneath a helmet. Helmets may be removed indoors when appropriate.</p>

<h3 Text="Weapon Regulations"/>

<p>Low-ranking troopers use weapons issued at shift start and may not change them without authorization. Weapons manufactured by other factions are [bold]strictly forbidden[/bold] and will be held in the armory until repurposed. High-quality weapons are distributed by logistics to where they are needed.</p>

## Criminals and Prisoners of War

<h3 Text="Criminals"/>

<p>Individuals not part of any faction who have broken NCR laws, committed crimes against NCR citizens or personnel, or undermined NCR operations. Criminals are protected under NCR laws - they must be treated humanely, provided with food, clothing, and shelter, and may not be abused while non-resisting. Non-lethal methods are authorized if they attempt to escape.</p>

<h3 Text="Prisoners of War (POWs)"/>

<p>Individuals who are part of a faction currently at war with the NCR. POWs are protected under NCR laws and must be treated humanely. They are [bold]not[/bold] to be used for tactical purposes (e.g. planning an ambush), nor traded, exchanged, or released without High Command authorization. Anyone releasing a POW without authorization is charged with Sedition or Treason.</p>

</Document>
