<Document>
# Armor

[textlink="View Full Wiki Page" link="https://ss14.misfitsystems.net/wiki/index.php/Armor"/]

<p>◈ Armor ◈ Wasteland Protection ◈</p>
<p>Armor is the difference between walking away from a firefight and being carried out of one. The Wasteland offers a wide range of protective equipment - from leather scraps to pre-war Power Armor. Know what you are wearing, what it stops, and what it does not.</p>

## Power Armor

<p>The pinnacle of pre-war military technology. Power Armor transforms a single soldier into a walking tank - but it is rare, heavily regulated, and not available to most factions.</p>

<Table Columns="3">
  <Box>[bold]Model[/bold]</Box>
  <Box>[bold]Description[/bold]</Box>
  <Box>[bold]Primary Users[/bold]</Box>
  <Box>T-45</Box>
  <Box>First-generation Power Armor. Heavy, reliable, and still capable against most wasteland threats.</Box>
  <Box>Brotherhood of Steel, NCR (salvaged)</Box>
  <Box>[bold]T-51[/bold]</Box>
  <Box>The iconic pre-war infantry suit. Superior protection and ergonomics compared to the T-45. The standard of Brotherhood operations.</Box>
  <Box>Brotherhood of Steel</Box>
  <Box>[bold]T-60[/bold]</Box>
  <Box>Advanced model with improved plating and servo systems. Rare even by Brotherhood standards.</Box>
  <Box>Brotherhood of Steel</Box>
  <Box>[bold]T-60 Tesla[/bold]</Box>
  <Box>T-60 variant with integrated Tesla coils for energy weapon amplification.</Box>
  <Box>Brotherhood of Steel (specialized)</Box>
  <Box>[bold]Advanced Power Armor Mk1[/bold]</Box>
  <Box>Enclave-manufactured. Superior to anything the Brotherhood fields.</Box>
  <Box>The Enclave</Box>
  <Box>[bold]Advanced Power Armor Mk2[/bold]</Box>
  <Box>Top-of-the-line Enclave engineering. The most advanced personal armor in the known world.</Box>
  <Box>The Enclave</Box>
  <Box>[bold]Mk2 Hellfire[/bold]</Box>
  <Box>Incendiary-hardened Mk2 variant designed for extreme combat environments.</Box>
  <Box>The Enclave (elite)</Box>
  <Box>[bold]Raider Power Armor[/bold]</Box>
  <Box>Scavenged, jury-rigged Power Armor held together by willpower and scrap metal. Provides Power Armor protection at Power Armor weight - without Power Armor reliability.</Box>
  <Box>Raiders, Outlaws</Box>
</Table>

## Standard Armor

<p>The bulk of wasteland protection. Standard armor ranges from primitive leather to pre-war combat plating.</p>

<h3 Text="Combat Armor"/>

<p>Pre-war military issue. Multiple variants exist - standard, Mk2 (reinforced), and Mk3 (heavy). Provides solid ballistic and melee protection across all damage types.</p>

<h3 Text="Faction-Specific Armor"/>

<Table Columns="2">
  <Box>[bold]Faction[/bold]</Box>
  <Box>[bold]Armor Types[/bold]</Box>
  <Box>[bold]Brotherhood[/bold]</Box>
  <Box>Knight Armor, Squire Armor, Head Knight Armor, Scribe Robes</Box>
  <Box>[bold]NCR[/bold]</Box>
  <Box>Enhanced Vest, Pouched Combat Armor, Heavy Combat Armor, Elite Combat Armor, Command Armor, Field Medic Vest, Salvaged Metal Armor, Regional camouflage variants</Box>
  <Box>[bold]Legion[/bold]</Box>
  <Box>Warrior Armor, Prime Decanus Armor, Veteran Decanus Armor</Box>
  <Box>[bold]Outlaws[/bold]</Box>
  <Box>Fiend Armor, Jackal Armor, Viper Armor, Khan's Jacket, Khan's Armored Jacket, Khan Combat Armor</Box>
  <Box>[bold]Enclave[/bold]</Box>
  <Box>Rank Pins (15 military ranks), Peacekeeper armor variants</Box>
</Table>

<h3 Text="General Armor"/>

<ul>
<li>[bold]Leather Armor[/bold] - Light, common, minimal protection. Better than nothing.</li>
<li>[bold]Metal Armor[/bold] - Solid protection, heavy. Widely available scrap-built variants.</li>
<li>[bold]Reinforced Armor[/bold] - Upgraded leather or metal with additional plating.</li>
<li>[bold]Tribal Armor[/bold] - Handcrafted tribal protection. Light but culturally significant.</li>
<li>[bold]Chitin / Insect Armor[/bold] - Harvested from wasteland creatures. Surprisingly effective.</li>
<li>[bold]Rad Armor[/bold] - Specialized protection against radiation exposure.</li>
</ul>

<h3 Text="Creature-Sourced Armor"/>

<Table Columns="2">
  <Box>[bold]Item[/bold]</Box>
  <Box>[bold]Source[/bold]</Box>
  <Box>[bold]Deathclaw Cloak[/bold]</Box>
  <Box>Deathclaw hide</Box>
  <Box>[bold]Razorclaw Armor[/bold]</Box>
  <Box>Razorclaw hide</Box>
  <Box>[bold]Raven Cloak[/bold]</Box>
  <Box>Wasteland raven feathers</Box>
  <Box>[bold]Deathclaw Hood[/bold]</Box>
  <Box>Deathclaw skull</Box>
  <Box>[bold]Razorclaw Helm[/bold]</Box>
  <Box>Razorclaw skull</Box>
</Table>

</Document>
