<Document>
# Currency

[textlink="View Full Wiki Page" link="https://ss14.misfitsystems.net/wiki/index.php/Currency"/]

<p>◈ Currency ◈ Wasteland Economy ◈</p>
<p>The Wasteland runs on trade, barter, and cold hard currency. Multiple forms of money circulate in the Wendover region - each backed by different powers and carrying different weight depending on who you are dealing with.</p>

## Currency Types

<Table Columns="4">
  <Box>[bold]Currency[/bold]</Box>
  <Box>[bold]Description[/bold]</Box>
  <Box>[bold]Value[/bold]</Box>
  <Box>[bold]Denominations[/bold]</Box>
  <Box>Bottlecaps</Box>
  <Box>The universal wasteland currency. Accepted everywhere, trusted by everyone. The standard unit of exchange.</Box>
  <Box>1 cap = 1 unit</Box>
  <Box>1, 10, 50, 100, 500</Box>
  <Box>[bold]NCR Dollars[/bold]</Box>
  <Box>Paper money issued by the New California Republic. Backed by the Republic's gold reserves - or what remains of them. Worth less than caps due to inflation and limited acceptance outside NCR territory.</Box>
  <Box>[bold]0.5[/bold] per dollar</Box>
  <Box>10, 50, 100, 500</Box>
  <Box>[bold]Legion Aureus[/bold]</Box>
  <Box>Gold coins minted by Caesar's Legion. Solid gold, universally recognized as valuable regardless of political opinion. One Aureus equals 10 Denarii.</Box>
  <Box>10× Denarius</Box>
  <Box>Individual coins</Box>
  <Box>[bold]Legion Denarius[/bold]</Box>
  <Box>Silver coins of the Legion. The base denomination of Legion currency. Widely accepted as a medium of exchange even by factions hostile to the Legion - silver is silver.</Box>
  <Box>Base unit</Box>
  <Box>Individual coins</Box>
  <Box>[bold]Pre-War Money[/bold]</Box>
  <Box>Old-world paper currency. Worthless as legal tender but collected as a curiosity, used as kindling, or traded to those who value pre-war artifacts.</Box>
  <Box>Cosmetic / 1 per unit</Box>
  <Box>10, 50, 100, 500</Box>
</Table>

## Wallets

<p>[bold]Wallets[/bold] (belt or ID slot) can hold multiple currency types and keep your money organized. All items tagged as [bold]Currency[/bold] are eligible for wallet storage.</p>

## Economic Notes

<ul>
<li>Bottlecaps are the [bold]default medium of exchange[/bold] throughout the Wasteland</li>
<li>NCR Dollars trade at [bold]half value[/bold] - two dollars for one cap's worth of goods</li>
<li>Legion currency is accepted widely due to its [bold]metal content[/bold] (gold and silver), regardless of political alignment</li>
<li>Pre-War Money has [bold]no standardized trade value[/bold] - its worth depends entirely on who wants it</li>
</ul>

</Document>
