<Document>
# The Enclave

[textlink="View Full Wiki Page" link="https://ss14.misfitsystems.net/wiki/index.php/Enclave"]

<p>Self-proclaimed continuation of the United States government. Founded by a secret cabal of political, military, and corporate elites who retreated to fortified installations before the Great War. The most technologically advanced — and most dangerous — human organization in the Wasteland.</p>

<hr/>

## Historical Timeline

<ColorBox Color="#1a1a1a" OutlineColor="#336699" OutlineThickness="1" Margin="5">
  <Box Orientation="Vertical" Margin="8">
    [bold][color=#336699]2077: The Great War and the Great Retreat[/color][/bold]
    Primary leadership fled to Control Station Enclave (oil rig off the California coast). Secretary of Agriculture Thomas Eckhart seized the Appalachian Whitespring Bunker, murdered superiors to take control, and declared himself President.
  </Box>
</ColorBox>

<ColorBox Color="#1a1a1a" OutlineColor="#336699" OutlineThickness="1" Margin="5">
  <Box Orientation="Vertical" Margin="8">
    [bold][color=#336699]2102: The Appalachian Civil War[/color][/bold]
    [bold]Hardliners[/bold] (Thomas Eckhart): Wanted to trigger a second nuclear exchange to destroy remaining communist threats.
    [bold]Reformers[/bold] (General Ellen Santiago): Questioned Eckhart's sanity and abandonment of American reconstruction.
    Outcome: Bloody stalemate. Rogue AI [bold]MODUS[/bold] killed remaining human occupants after they attempted to sabotage its systems.
  </Box>
</ColorBox>

<ColorBox Color="#1a1a1a" OutlineColor="#336699" OutlineThickness="1" Margin="5">
  <Box Orientation="Vertical" Margin="8">
    [bold][color=#336699]2242: The Fall of Western Command[/color][/bold]
    The Oil Rig was destroyed by the "Chosen One." Loss of the President forced transition from global superpower to migratory force. Survivors led by Scientist Autumn Senior began the "Great March" toward the East Coast.
  </Box>
</ColorBox>

<ColorBox Color="#1a1a1a" OutlineColor="#336699" OutlineThickness="1" Margin="5">
  <Box Orientation="Vertical" Margin="8">
    [bold][color=#336699]2277: The Capital Wasteland Campaign[/color][/bold]
    Re-established at Raven Rock and Adams Air Force Base in Washington, D.C.
    [bold]John Henry Eden[/bold] — Sentient ZAX supercomputer. Proposed modified FEV for genocide of all mutated DNA.
    [bold]Colonel Augustus Autumn[/bold] — Pragmatist. Rejected genocide, preferred water supply as political tool.
    Outcome: Decisively defeated by the Brotherhood of Steel.
  </Box>
</ColorBox>

<ColorBox Color="#1a1a1a" OutlineColor="#888888" OutlineThickness="1" Margin="5">
  <Box Orientation="Vertical" Margin="8">
    [bold][color=#888888]2281: The Mojave Remnants[/color][/bold]
    Western branch no longer existed as a political entity. Small squads in hiding under Judah Kreger. Aging veterans, no longer loyal to purist ideology. Integrated into wasteland society as doctors, pilots, and scavengers.
  </Box>
</ColorBox>

<ColorBox Color="#1a1a1a" OutlineColor="#888888" OutlineThickness="1" Margin="5">
  <Box Orientation="Vertical" Margin="8">
    [bold][color=#888888]2287: Commonwealth Echoes[/color][/bold]
    Post-D.C. defeat splinter cells and "Black Ops" units remained active. "Echo Sites" tasked with salvaging tech and establishing secret outposts. Decentralized paramilitary. Maintained old "purity" standards.
  </Box>
</ColorBox>

<ColorBox Color="#1a1a1a" OutlineColor="#cc3333" OutlineThickness="1" Margin="5">
  <Box Orientation="Vertical" Margin="8">
    [bold][color=#cc3333]2296: The Research Resurgence[/color][/bold]
    Shifting from open warfare to advanced bio-engineering and energy physics. Extreme secrecy. View themselves as ultimate stewards of the planet. Possess [bold]Cold Fusion[/bold] technology. Less interested in immediate genocide — more interested in total control of planetary resources.
  </Box>
</ColorBox>

<hr/>

## Technology Assets

<Table Columns="2">
  <Box>
    [bold][color=#a4885c]Asset[/color][/bold]
  </Box>
  <Box>
    [bold][color=#a4885c]Description[/color][/bold]
  </Box>
  <Box>
    [bold]Advanced Power Armor Mk1[/bold]
  </Box>
  <Box>
    Superior to BoS equipment. Full environmental sealing, integrated HUD, servo-assisted strength.
  </Box>
  <Box>
    [bold]Advanced Power Armor Mk2[/bold]
  </Box>
  <Box>
    Top-of-the-line. Most advanced personal armor known to exist.
  </Box>
  <Box>
    [bold]Mk2 Hellfire[/bold]
  </Box>
  <Box>
    Incendiary-hardened Mk2 variant. Elite issue only.
  </Box>
  <Box>
    [bold]Plasma Weaponry[/bold]
  </Box>
  <Box>
    Enclave-manufactured plasma rifles and pistols. Superior output.
  </Box>
  <Box>
    [bold]Vertibirds[/bold]
  </Box>
  <Box>
    Pre-war military transport aircraft. Unmatched strategic mobility.
  </Box>
</Table>

<hr/>

## Faction Relations

<Table Columns="3">
  <Box>
    [bold][color=#a4885c]Faction[/color][/bold]
  </Box>
  <Box>
    [bold][color=#a4885c]Standing[/color][/bold]
  </Box>
  <Box>
    [bold][color=#a4885c]Notes[/color][/bold]
  </Box>
  <Box>
    Brotherhood of Steel
  </Box>
  <Box>
    [bold][color=#cc3333]Kill on Sight[/color][/bold]
  </Box>
  <Box>
    Fought twice, won. Will not allow a third round on Enclave terms.
  </Box>
  <Box>
    NCR
  </Box>
  <Box>
    [color=#cc3333]Hostile[/color]
  </Box>
  <Box>
    Views Enclave as rogue military government, direct threat to democracy.
  </Box>
  <Box>
    Caesar's Legion
  </Box>
  <Box>
    [color=#cc3333]Hostile[/color]
  </Box>
  <Box>
    Enclave tech = everything Caesar sought to destroy.
  </Box>
  <Box>
    Townsfolk
  </Box>
  <Box>
    [color=#ffb000]Fearful[/color]
  </Box>
  <Box>
    Means forced relocation at best, extermination at worst.
  </Box>
  <Box>
    Wastelanders
  </Box>
  <Box>
    [color=#cc3333]Hostile[/color]
  </Box>
  <Box>
    To Enclave: mutated subhumans. The feeling is mutual.
  </Box>
  <Box>
    Followers
  </Box>
  <Box>
    [color=#cc3333]Hostile[/color]
  </Box>
  <Box>
    Represents everything Enclave despises — free knowledge, humanitarianism.
  </Box>
  <Box>
    Outlaws
  </Box>
  <Box>
    [color=#cc3333]Hostile[/color]
  </Box>
  <Box>
    Raiders = vermin to be cleansed. No negotiation.
  </Box>
</Table>

</Document>
