<GuidePage Title="Faction Sustainability" Subtitle="This guide outlines the essential loops for replenishing a faction's supplies mid-round, focusing on ammunition production and medical farming." Link="https://ss14.misfitsystems.net/wiki/index.php/Guide_to_Faction_Sustainability">
<GuideInfoBox Title="Operational Focus">
<p>Mid-round sustainability depends on two stable loops: munitions production for combat readiness and medical farming for recovery.</p>
</GuideInfoBox>

<GuideSection Title="Ammunition Production">
<p>When round-start supplies are exhausted, combat effectiveness depends on a steady logistical chain of lead, steel, and gunpowder.</p>

<GuideSubSection Title="Resource Acquisition">
<p>There are three primary ways to gather the raw materials needed for casings and bullets:</p>
<ul>
<li>[bold]Salvaging[/bold] - Searching junk piles, shelves, and crates in the wastes or bunkers. This is the most efficient method in the early game.</li>
<li>[bold]Dismantling[/bold] - Breaking down wrecked cars or vehicles found on roads and in junkyards. This provides a significant yield of Lead and Steel scraps.</li>
<li>[bold]Mining[/bold] - The least viable method. Ore veins (Coal, Sulfur, Iron) have low yields and inconsistent drops, making it difficult to target specific materials.</li>
</ul>
</GuideSubSection>

<GuideSubSection Title="Ammo Recipes">
<p>Standard ammunition requires an Ammo Bench. Ensure you have the following materials inserted into the workbench:</p>
<Table Columns="5">
Ammo Type | Lead (Bar) | Steel (Sheet) | Gunpowder | Secondary Mat
5.56mm | 1.5 | 2.25 | 1.5 | 1 Cardboard
Shotgun Shell | 0.6 | 0 | 0.6 | 1 Cardboard + 1 Paper
</Table>
<GuideInfoBox Title="Workbench Note">
<p>[italic]Cardboard is crafted from 2x Paper. Paper is crafted from 1x Wood Plank.[/italic]</p>
</GuideInfoBox>
</GuideSubSection>

<GuideSubSection Title="Crafting Gunpowder">
<p>Gunpowder is the most complex component and must be crafted via the crafting menu. There are two ways to produce it:</p>

<GuideExampleBlock Title="Method 1: Basic Crafting (Manual)">
<ul>
<li>[bold]Recipe:[/bold] 1x Fertilizer + 1x Coal + 1x Sulfur.</li>
<li>[bold]Coal:[/bold] Processed in a Forge from Charcoal (1 Plank = 1 Charcoal; 1.5 Charcoal = 1 Coal).</li>
<li>[bold]Fertilizer and Sulfur:[/bold] Primarily obtained through mining or faction base stockpiles.</li>
</ul>
</GuideExampleBlock>

<GuideExampleBlock Title="Method 2: High-Efficiency (Chemset and Mortar)">
<p>If you have access to a Chemical Set and beakers, you can produce gunpowder in bulk with much higher efficiency.</p>
<ul>
<li>[bold]1. Grinding:[/bold] Use a Mortar and Pestle (crafted with 2x Wood) to grind Sulfur, Fertilizer, and Coal (which becomes Carbon) into a liquid form.</li>
<li>[bold]2. Mixing:[/bold] Collect the resulting liquids into a Chemical Set.</li>
<li>[bold]3. Ratios:[/bold] Redistribute the chemicals into a single beaker in a strict [bold]1:1:1 ratio[/bold] (e.g. 30u Sulfur : 30u Fertilizer : 30u Carbon).</li>
<li>[bold]4. Final Step:[/bold] It will consume the units directly from the beaker and drop the gunpowder on the ground, allowing for rapid, large-scale production.</li>
</ul>
</GuideExampleBlock>
</GuideSubSection>
</GuideSection>

<GuideSection Title="Medical Supplies and Farming">
<p>Medical sustainability relies on the cultivation of Broc Flower and Xander Root.</p>

<GuideSubSection Title="The Farming Loop">
<p>Farming is a precise cycle. If you miss a step, especially clipping, you may lose your ability to replant for the rest of the round.</p>
<ul>
<li>[bold]1. Planting:[/bold] Start with an empty planter. With a Plant Clipping in your hand, click the planter to sow the crop. Clippings function as seeds.</li>
<li>[bold]2. Weeding:[/bold] Use a Hoe to remove weeds. This can be done either before planting to prep the soil or after the plant has started growing.</li>
<li>[bold]3. Hydration and Nutrition:[/bold] Keep the water level stable. To boost nutrition, collect [bold]Dung[/bold] from Brahmin or Brahdo using a bucket or compost bag. Insert the compost bag into a [bold]Composer[/bold], then use Alt+Click or right-click to toggle the machine on. Once processed into compost, click the planter with the compost in hand.</li>
<li>[bold]4. Clipping:[/bold] Once the plant has grown, you must use [bold]Plant Clipper[/bold] on it before harvesting. This gives you a new clipping to replant.</li>
<li>[bold]5. Harvesting:[/bold] After clipping, you can harvest the plant.</li>
</ul>

<GuideWarningBox Title="Clipping Is Mandatory">
<p>Each plant can only be clipped once. If you harvest before clipping, you lose the ability to replant that crop unless you find a new wild source.</p>
</GuideWarningBox>
</GuideSubSection>

<GuideSubSection Title="Seed Management">
<p>If your faction does not have a Seed Extractor, you must use Plant Clippers:</p>
<ul>
<li>Click a mature crop with the scissors to get a clipping.</li>
<li>[bold]Warning:[/bold] Each plant can only be clipped once. If you harvest a plant without clipping it first, you lose the ability to replant it.</li>
</ul>

<GuideExampleBlock Title="Seed Extractor Frame">
<p>To build the extractor, open your crafting menu and gather the following:</p>
<ul>
<li>4x Planks</li>
<li>1x Cooking Pot</li>
<li>2x Steel Sheets</li>
<li>1x Duct Tape</li>
<li>[bold]Tool Required:[/bold] Screwdriver to finish construction.</li>
</ul>
</GuideExampleBlock>
</GuideSubSection>

<GuideSubSection Title="Medical Recipes">
<p>Once harvested, use a workbench or your crafting menu to create healing items:</p>
<ul>
<li>[bold]Healing Powder:[/bold] 1x Broc Flower + 1x Xander Root.</li>
<li>[bold]Doctor Syringe:[/bold] 1x Plastic + 0.25 Steel, crafted at a workbench.</li>
<li>[bold]Stimpak:[/bold] 1x Broc Flower + 1x Xander Root + 1x Bloodpack + 1x Doctor Syringe.</li>
</ul>
<GuideInfoBox Title="Crafting Note">
<p>[italic]Empty stimpaks cannot be refilled. Super Stimpaks and Dirty Stimpaks are currently uncraftable.[/italic]</p>
</GuideInfoBox>
</GuideSubSection>
</GuideSection>
</GuidePage>
