<Document>
# Followers of the Apocalypse

[textlink="View Full Wiki Page" link="https://ss14.misfitsystems.net/wiki/index.php/Followers_of_the_Apocalypse"]

<p>Founded in the ruins of the Los Angeles Public Library. The Followers believe knowledge, medicine, and education are more powerful than weapons. Non-violent, non-aligned. Will help anyone.</p>

<hr/>

## Philosophy

<p>The Great War was caused by humanity's unwillingness to share knowledge and resources. The Followers' response is radical openness — free clinics, free education, freely shared pre-war records. This puts them in direct conflict with the Brotherhood of Steel, who lock away technology.</p>

<p>The Followers maintain the largest accessible archive of pre-war knowledge in the Wasteland. They run free clinics and teach the illiterate. Their neutrality is both their strength and their vulnerability.</p>

<hr/>

## Roles

<ColorBox Color="#1a1a1a" OutlineColor="#6bba5e" OutlineThickness="1" Margin="5">
  <Box Orientation="Vertical" Margin="8">
    [bold][color=#6bba5e]Followers Doctor[/color][/bold]
    Provide medical care to anyone. Your neutrality and skills make you welcome almost anywhere. Factions will try to co-opt your resources — do not let them. Most trusted figures across all faction lines.
  </Box>
</ColorBox>

<ColorBox Color="#1a1a1a" OutlineColor="#a4885c" OutlineThickness="1" Margin="5">
  <Box Orientation="Vertical" Margin="8">
    [bold][color=#a4885c]Followers Scholar[/color][/bold]
    Record events, teach, collect pre-war documents and technical knowledge. The events of a single round may matter to generations. Archivists and educators whose records are genuinely valuable.
  </Box>
</ColorBox>

<ColorBox Color="#1a1a1a" OutlineColor="#4a6a99" OutlineThickness="1" Margin="5">
  <Box Orientation="Vertical" Margin="8">
    [bold][color=#4a6a99]Followers Aid Worker[/color][/bold]
    Assist in crises. Distribute food, water, and basic medical supplies. You are the organization's human face. First to arrive, last to leave.
  </Box>
</ColorBox>

<hr/>

## Faction Relations

<Table Columns="3">
  <Box>
    [bold][color=#a4885c]Faction[/color][/bold]
  </Box>
  <Box>
    [bold][color=#a4885c]Standing[/color][/bold]
  </Box>
  <Box>
    [bold][color=#a4885c]Notes[/color][/bold]
  </Box>
  <Box>
    NCR
  </Box>
  <Box>
    [color=#6bba5e]Allies[/color]
  </Box>
  <Box>
    Values Followers' medical expertise and public goodwill. Occasionally strained.
  </Box>
  <Box>
    Brotherhood of Steel
  </Box>
  <Box>
    [color=#cc3333]Hostile[/color]
  </Box>
  <Box>
    Views free tech sharing as reckless and dangerous.
  </Box>
  <Box>
    Caesar's Legion
  </Box>
  <Box>
    [color=#cc3333]Hostile[/color]
  </Box>
  <Box>
    Despises pacifism and egalitarianism. Captured Followers rarely survive.
  </Box>
  <Box>
    Townsfolk
  </Box>
  <Box>
    [color=#6bba5e]Friendly[/color]
  </Box>
  <Box>
    Clinics and schools welcomed. Often the only organized medical presence.
  </Box>
  <Box>
    Wastelanders
  </Box>
  <Box>
    [color=#6bba5e]Friendly[/color]
  </Box>
  <Box>
    Rely on Followers clinics for affordable treatment.
  </Box>
  <Box>
    Wasteland Tribes
  </Box>
  <Box>
    [color=#6bba5e]Friendly[/color]
  </Box>
  <Box>
    Respect willingness to share knowledge without conditions.
  </Box>
  <Box>
    Outlaws
  </Box>
  <Box>
    [color=#ffb000]Cautious[/color]
  </Box>
  <Box>
    Will treat anyone including raiders, but no illusions about the danger.
  </Box>
</Table>

</Document>
