<Document>
# The Enclave

[textlink="View Full Wiki Page" link="https://ss14.misfitsystems.net/wiki/index.php/The%20Enclave"/]

<p>◈ THE ENCLAVE ◈ Remnants of the United States ◈ CLASSIFIED ◈</p>

<Table Columns="2">
  <Box>[bold]The Enclave[/bold]</Box>
  <Box></Box>
  <Box>◈ FACTION DOSSIER ◈</Box>
  <Box></Box>
  <Box>[bold]Status[/bold]</Box>
  <Box>Active - Covert</Box>
  <Box>[bold]Location[/bold]</Box>
  <Box>Classified
Wendover Region (Suspected)</Box>
  <Box>[bold]Commander[/bold]</Box>
  <Box>Classified</Box>
  <Box>[bold]Ideology[/bold]</Box>
  <Box>American Continuity
Genetic & Technological Supremacy</Box>
  <Box>[bold]Motto[/bold]</Box>
  <Box>[italic]God Bless the Enclave. God Bless America.[/italic]</Box>
  <Box>[bold]Affiliation[/bold]</Box>
  <Box>United States Government (Self-Proclaimed)</Box>
  <Box>⬜ RESTRICTED ACCESS ⬜</Box>
  <Box></Box>
</Table>

<p>The [bold]Enclave[/bold] is the self-proclaimed continuation of the United States government. Founded by a secret cabal of political, military, and corporate elites, they retreated to fortified bunkers and offshore installations just before the Great War to survive the nuclear apocalypse they helped facilitate.</p>
<p>They are the most technologically advanced human organization in the known world. They are also the most dangerous.</p>
<ColorBox Color="#1a1a1a" OutlineColor="#666666" OutlineThickness="1" Margin="5">
  <Box Orientation="Vertical" Margin="8">
[italic]"We are the United States of America. We never fell. We never surrendered. And we are coming back."[/italic]
  </Box>
</ColorBox>

## History

<h3 Text="2077: The Great War and the Great Retreat"/>

<p>Immediately following the nuclear exchange, the Enclave leadership activated their continuity of government protocols. While the primary leadership fled to the [bold]Control Station Enclave[/bold] (an oil rig off the coast of California), regional branches took command of specialized bunkers across the continent.</p>
<ul>
<li>[bold]The Appalachian Branch:[/bold] Led by Secretary of Agriculture Thomas Eckhart, this group occupied the Whitespring Bunker. Eckhart was an extremist who believed the war was not "won." He murdered his superiors to seize control and declare himself President.</li>
<li>[bold]The Poseidon Oil Rig:[/bold] The "Main Branch" established their base of operations here, overseeing the various regional outposts from afar.</li>
</ul>

<h3 Text="2102: The Appalachian Civil War"/>

<p>The Enclave in West Virginia faced an internal ideological split that would ultimately lead to their localized extinction.</p>

<Table Columns="2">
  <Box>[bold]Faction[/bold]</Box>
  <Box>[bold]Position[/bold]</Box>
  <Box>The Hardliners</Box>
  <Box>Led by Thomas Eckhart. Wanted to trigger a second nuclear exchange to destroy any remaining communist threats.</Box>
  <Box>The Reformers</Box>
  <Box>Led by General Ellen Santiago. Questioned Eckhart's sanity and his abandonment of actual American reconstruction in favor of global destruction.</Box>
</Table>

<p>[bold]The Outcome:[/bold] The conflict ended in a bloody stalemate. A rogue AI named [bold]MODUS[/bold] (Multi-Operation Direction and Utility System) eventually killed the remaining human occupants after they attempted to sabotage its systems.</p>

<h3 Text="2242: The Fall of Western Command"/>

<p>The destruction of the Oil Rig by the "Chosen One" is a pivotal moment in Enclave history. The loss of the President and the Rig forced the Enclave to transition from a global superpower to a migratory force. Surviving members, led by Scientist Autumn Senior, began a "Great March" toward the East Coast.</p>

<h3 Text="2277: The Capital Wasteland Campaign"/>

<p>By this year, the Enclave had re-established a massive presence at [bold]Raven Rock[/bold] and [bold]Adams Air Force Base[/bold] in Washington, D.C.</p>

<Table Columns="2">
  <Box>[bold]Leader[/bold]</Box>
  <Box>[bold]Position[/bold]</Box>
  <Box>John Henry Eden</Box>
  <Box>A sentient ZAX supercomputer that believed it was the reincarnation of all great American Presidents. Hardliner - proposed using a modified FEV to commit global genocide against anyone with mutated DNA.</Box>
  <Box>Colonel Augustus Autumn</Box>
  <Box>Son of Autumn Senior. [bold]Pragmatist[/bold] - rejected Eden's genocidal plan, preferring to use the region's water supply as a political tool to force the population to accept Enclave rule.</Box>
</Table>

<p>[bold]The Outcome:[/bold] The Enclave was decisively defeated by the Brotherhood of Steel. This marked the end of the Enclave as an organized, open military government on the East Coast.</p>

<h3 Text="2281: The Mojave Remnants"/>

<p>In the West, the Enclave no longer existed as a political entity. Instead, small squads of soldiers from the original Western branch lived in hiding.</p>
<p>[bold]The Remnants:[/bold] Led by Judah Kreger, this "branch" was actually a group of aging veterans. They were no longer loyal to the Enclave's purist ideology, having integrated into wasteland society as doctors, pilots, and scavengers. They represented the "humanized" Enclave - choosing to use their technology to assist in the Battle of Hoover Dam based on personal conviction.</p>

<h3 Text="2287: Commonwealth Echoes"/>

<p>Following the defeat in D.C., small splinter cells and "Black Ops" units remained active in the North.</p>
<p>These units, referred to in logs as [bold]Echo Sites[/bold], were tasked with salvaging lost technology and establishing secret outposts. They operated without a central President, functioning more like a decentralized paramilitary organization. They remained hostile to all outsiders, maintaining the old "purity" standards.</p>

<h3 Text="2296: The Research Resurgence"/>

<p>Decades after their major defeats, a highly organized and secretive Enclave branch has emerged.</p>

<Table Columns="2">
  <Box>[bold]Aspect[/bold]</Box>
  <Box>[bold]Details[/bold]</Box>
  <Box>[bold]Strategy[/bold]</Box>
  <Box>Shifting away from open warfare, this branch focuses on advanced bio-engineering and energy physics. They operate with extreme secrecy.</Box>
  <Box>[bold]Ideology[/bold]</Box>
  <Box>This version of the Enclave is more calculated. They view themselves as the ultimate stewards of the planet's future, possessing [bold]Cold Fusion[/bold] technology required to restart civilization.</Box>
  <Box>[bold]Goal[/bold]</Box>
  <Box>Less interested in immediate genocide - more interested in the total control of planetary resources and the technological infrastructure of the new world.</Box>
</Table>

## Technology

<p>The Enclave fields the most advanced equipment in the known world:</p>

<Table Columns="2">
  <Box>[bold]Asset[/bold]</Box>
  <Box>[bold]Description[/bold]</Box>
  <Box>Advanced Power Armor Mk1</Box>
  <Box>Superior to anything the Brotherhood fields. Full environmental sealing, integrated HUD, and servo-assisted strength amplification.</Box>
  <Box>[bold]Advanced Power Armor Mk2[/bold]</Box>
  <Box>Top-of-the-line Enclave engineering. The most advanced personal armor in the known world.</Box>
  <Box>[bold]Mk2 Hellfire[/bold]</Box>
  <Box>Incendiary-hardened Mk2 variant designed for extreme combat environments. Elite issue only.</Box>
  <Box>[bold]Plasma Weaponry[/bold]</Box>
  <Box>Enclave-manufactured plasma rifles and pistols - superior output to any wasteland equivalent.</Box>
  <Box>[bold]Vertibirds[/bold]</Box>
  <Box>Pre-war military transport aircraft. Gives the Enclave unmatched strategic mobility.</Box>
</Table>

## Threat Assessment

<ColorBox Color="#1a1a1a" OutlineColor="#666666" OutlineThickness="1" Margin="5">
  <Box Orientation="Vertical" Margin="8">
[italic]"The Enclave is not a faction. The Enclave is a threat classification. Treat accordingly." - Brotherhood Field Manual, 509th Chapter[/italic]
  </Box>
</ColorBox>
<p>Every major faction in the Wendover region views the Enclave as a threat:</p>

<Table Columns="3">
  <Box>[bold]Faction[/bold]</Box>
  <Box>[bold]Standing[/bold]</Box>
  <Box>[bold]Notes[/bold]</Box>
  <Box>[textlink="Brotherhood of Steel" link="https://ss14.misfitsystems.net/wiki/index.php/Brotherhood_of_Steel"/]</Box>
  <Box>[bold]Kill on Sight[/bold]</Box>
  <Box>The Brotherhood has fought the Enclave twice and won. They will not allow a third round to begin on Enclave terms.</Box>
  <Box>[textlink="NCR" link="https://ss14.misfitsystems.net/wiki/index.php/New_California_Republic"/]</Box>
  <Box>Hostile</Box>
  <Box>The NCR views the Enclave as a rogue military government and a direct threat to democratic governance.</Box>
  <Box>[textlink="Caesar's Legion" link="https://ss14.misfitsystems.net/wiki/index.php/Caesar%27s_Legion"/]</Box>
  <Box>Hostile</Box>
  <Box>The Legion respects strength but the Enclave's technology represents everything Caesar sought to destroy.</Box>
  <Box>[textlink="Townsfolk" link="https://ss14.misfitsystems.net/wiki/index.php/Townsfolk"/]</Box>
  <Box>Fearful</Box>
  <Box>Civilians have heard the stories. The Enclave means forced relocation at best, extermination at worst.</Box>
  <Box>[textlink="Wastelanders" link="https://ss14.misfitsystems.net/wiki/index.php/Wastelanders"/]</Box>
  <Box>Hostile</Box>
  <Box>To the Enclave, unaffiliated wastelanders are mutated subhumans. The feeling is mutual.</Box>
  <Box>[textlink="Followers of the Apocalypse" link="https://ss14.misfitsystems.net/wiki/index.php/Followers_of_the_Apocalypse"/]</Box>
  <Box>Hostile</Box>
  <Box>The Followers represent everything the Enclave despises - freely shared knowledge and humanitarian weakness.</Box>
  <Box>[textlink="Outlaws" link="https://ss14.misfitsystems.net/wiki/index.php/Outlaws"/]</Box>
  <Box>Hostile</Box>
  <Box>Raiders are vermin to be cleansed. The Enclave does not negotiate with bandits.</Box>
</Table>

</Document>
