<Document>
# Survival Basics

[textlink="View Full Wiki Page" link="https://ss14.misfitsystems.net/wiki/index.php/Survival%20Basics"/]

## Survival Basics

<p>Life in the Wasteland is hostile by default. Food, water, radiation, and weather all matter - neglecting any of them for too long will kill you.</p>
<p>To survive long term, you need [bold]food[/bold] and [bold]water[/bold]. The day-night cycle lasts one hour, and during that span you need to eat and drink at least once.</p>

<h3 Text="Water"/>

<p>Clean water is one of the most important resources in Nuclear 14. Many water sources are dirty or irradiated, so drinking whatever you find is a fast way to get sick.</p>

<Table Columns="2">
  <Box>[bold]Water Type[/bold]</Box>
  <Box>[bold]Safety[/bold]</Box>
  <Box>[bold]Filtered Water[/bold]</Box>
  <Box>Safe to drink. Purified from a clean source.</Box>
  <Box>[bold]Dirty Water[/bold]</Box>
  <Box>Illness risk. Carries bacteria and contaminants.</Box>
  <Box>[bold]Irradiated Water[/bold]</Box>
  <Box>Radiation exposure. Avoid unless treated.</Box>
</Table>

<p>Purify water with filters, chemistry, or boiling whenever you can. See [textlink="Materials" link="https://ss14.misfitsystems.net/wiki/index.php/Materials"/] for water purification recipes.</p>

<h3 Text="Food"/>

<p>You need a steady food supply. Gather wild plants, hunt animals, trade for supplies, or grow crops if your settlement has the space.</p>
<ul>
<li>Cook raw meat before eating it - raw meat carries illness risk.</li>
<li>Do not assume every plant or scavenged meal is safe.</li>
<li>See [textlink="Cooking" link="https://ss14.misfitsystems.net/wiki/index.php/Cooking"/] for meal recipes and [textlink="Botany" link="https://ss14.misfitsystems.net/wiki/index.php/Botany"/] for growing your own food supply.</li>
</ul>
<p>[bold]Quick food options:[/bold]</p>
<ul>
<li>[bold]Raw plants[/bold] (carrots, cabbage, corn) - safe to eat immediately.</li>
<li>[bold]Pre-war packaged food[/bold] (Blamco, Cram, Instamash) - safe and filling.</li>
<li>[bold]Cooked meals[/bold] - best value for nutrition and safety.</li>
</ul>

<h3 Text="Radiation"/>

<p>Radiation is everywhere in the Wasteland. Watch your exposure levels, carry treatment when possible, and avoid contaminated areas unless you are equipped for them.</p>

<Table Columns="2">
  <Box>[bold]Tool / Treatment[/bold]</Box>
  <Box>[bold]Use[/bold]</Box>
  <Box>[bold]Geiger Counter[/bold]</Box>
  <Box>Measures current radiation level in your environment.</Box>
  <Box>[bold]RadAway Inhaler[/bold]</Box>
  <Box>Flushes accumulated radiation from your body. See [textlink="Medicine Crafting" link="https://ss14.misfitsystems.net/wiki/index.php/Medicine_Crafting"/] to craft your own.</Box>
  <Box>[bold]Rad-X[/bold]</Box>
  <Box>Reduces radiation absorption rate while active. Found in medical caches or purchased from doctors.</Box>
</Table>

<p>If a zone is hot: move quickly, wear protection, and clear the dose before it stacks up.</p>

<h3 Text="Weather and Exposure"/>

<p>Weather can be as deadly as combat. Sandstorms, acid rain, and sharp temperature swings all punish unprepared survivors.</p>

<Table Columns="2">
  <Box>[bold]Gear[/bold]</Box>
  <Box>[bold]Protection[/bold]</Box>
  <Box>[bold]Gas Mask[/bold]</Box>
  <Box>Covers airways during sandstorms and toxic environments.</Box>
  <Box>[bold]Leather Duster Coat[/bold]</Box>
  <Box>Full-body weather protection for open Wasteland travel.</Box>
</Table>

<p>Keep protective clothing, a face covering, and spare supplies ready before you travel far from shelter.</p>

</Document>
