<Document>
# Wasteland Tribes

[textlink="View Full Wiki Page" link="https://ss14.misfitsystems.net/wiki/index.php/Wasteland%20Tribes"/]

<p>◈ Wasteland Tribes ◈ Faction Dossier ◈ Tribals ◈</p>

<Table Columns="2">
  <Box>[bold]Wasteland Tribes[/bold]</Box>
  <Box></Box>
  <Box>◈ FACTION DOSSIER ◈</Box>
  <Box></Box>
  <Box>[bold]Status[/bold]</Box>
  <Box>Active - Scattered</Box>
  <Box>[bold]Location[/bold]</Box>
  <Box>Utah Wastes
Wendover Region</Box>
  <Box>[bold]Commander[/bold]</Box>
  <Box>Tribal Chieftain (Per Tribe)</Box>
  <Box>[bold]Ideology[/bold]</Box>
  <Box>Community Survival
Oral Tradition</Box>
  <Box>[bold]Motto[/bold]</Box>
  <Box>[italic]The land provides. The tribe endures.[/italic]</Box>
  <Box>[bold]Affiliation[/bold]</Box>
  <Box>Independent - Tribal</Box>
  <Box>⬜ RESTRICTED ACCESS ⬜</Box>
  <Box></Box>
</Table>

<p>[bold]Tribes[/bold] are among the oldest post-war social structures in the Wasteland. Long before the NCR organized a government or the Brotherhood fortified a bunker, tribal communities formed from survivors who stayed together through kinship, shared land, and shared belief. They have endured for over two centuries through deep environmental knowledge, oral tradition, and fierce community bonds.</p>
<p>Each tribe is shaped entirely by its Chieftain. The Chieftain's philosophy defines whether the tribe is peaceful or aggressive, isolationist or open to trade, suspicious of technology or eager to adopt it.</p>

## Philosophy

<ColorBox Color="#1a1a1a" OutlineColor="#666666" OutlineThickness="1" Margin="5">
  <Box Orientation="Vertical" Margin="8">
[italic]"Tribal societies place community over individual ambition and oral history over written records. They possess environmental knowledge that outsiders entirely miss - which plants are edible, which ruins are stable, which seasonal patterns the Wasteland follows. What all tribes share is a fierce will to survive on their own terms."[/italic]
  </Box>
</ColorBox>

## Roles

<Table Columns="3">
  <Box>[bold]Role[/bold]</Box>
  <Box>[bold]Description[/bold]</Box>
  <Box>[bold]Notes[/bold]</Box>
  <Box>Tribal Chieftain</Box>
  <Box>Set your tribe's character for the round. Decide how your people relate to the town, the NCR, the Brotherhood, and the wider Wasteland. Your choices shape everyone beneath you - make them with intention.</Box>
  <Box>Tribe leadership. Defines the tribe's identity.</Box>
  <Box>[bold]Tribal Warrior[/bold]</Box>
  <Box>Protect the tribe and enforce the Chieftain's will in the field. When conflict arrives - and it will - you are the tribe's first and last line of defense.</Box>
  <Box>Combat and enforcement.</Box>
  <Box>[bold]Tribal Shaman[/bold]</Box>
  <Box>Heal the tribe, maintain its traditions, and counsel the Chieftain. You are the keeper of what the tribe was and the guide toward what it might become. Your expertise makes you valuable to outsiders as well.</Box>
  <Box>Medical and spiritual role.</Box>
  <Box>[bold]Tribesperson[/bold]</Box>
  <Box>Keep the tribe alive. Hunt, gather, farm, and craft. Your labor is the foundation that every Chieftain's decision rests on. Without you, there is no tribe.</Box>
  <Box>General labor. The tribe's backbone.</Box>
</Table>

## Relations

<p>Tribal relations with other factions are complex and vary by Chieftain decision. Historically, tribes have traded with townspeople and cautiously engaged with caravans.</p>

<Table Columns="3">
  <Box>[bold]Faction[/bold]</Box>
  <Box>[bold]Standing[/bold]</Box>
  <Box>[bold]Notes[/bold]</Box>
  <Box>[textlink="Townsfolk" link="https://ss14.misfitsystems.net/wiki/index.php/Townsfolk"/]</Box>
  <Box>Variable</Box>
  <Box>Trade is common. Trust depends entirely on the Chieftain's attitude and past dealings.</Box>
  <Box>[textlink="NCR" link="https://ss14.misfitsystems.net/wiki/index.php/New_California_Republic"/]</Box>
  <Box>Distrustful</Box>
  <Box>The NCR sees tribal land as territory to be annexed. Tribes see the NCR as a threat to their independence.</Box>
  <Box>[textlink="Brotherhood of Steel" link="https://ss14.misfitsystems.net/wiki/index.php/Brotherhood_of_Steel"/]</Box>
  <Box>Mixed</Box>
  <Box>Some Brotherhood commanders see value in recruiting tribal warriors. Others view tribals with open suspicion or hostility.</Box>
  <Box>[textlink="Caesar's Legion" link="https://ss14.misfitsystems.net/wiki/index.php/Caesar%27s_Legion"/]</Box>
  <Box>[bold]Dangerous[/bold]</Box>
  <Box>The Legion absorbs tribes by force - enslaving or assimilating them into their ranks. This is the greatest existential threat to tribal independence.</Box>
  <Box>[textlink="Followers of the Apocalypse" link="https://ss14.misfitsystems.net/wiki/index.php/Followers_of_the_Apocalypse"/]</Box>
  <Box>Friendly</Box>
  <Box>The Followers share knowledge freely and respect tribal autonomy. They are among the few outsiders tribes welcome.</Box>
  <Box>[textlink="Wastelanders" link="https://ss14.misfitsystems.net/wiki/index.php/Wastelanders"/]</Box>
  <Box>Open</Box>
  <Box>Drifters and tribals often share the same roads and resources. Relations are generally neutral.</Box>
  <Box>[textlink="Outlaws" link="https://ss14.misfitsystems.net/wiki/index.php/Outlaws"/]</Box>
  <Box>Hostile</Box>
  <Box>Raiders take what they want. Tribes defend what is theirs.</Box>
</Table>

</Document>
