<Document>
# Brotherhood of Steel (509th Chapter)

[textlink="View Full Wiki Page" link="https://ss14.misfitsystems.net/wiki/index.php/Brotherhood%20of%20Steel"/]

<p>◈ Brotherhood of Steel - 509th Chapter ◈ Faction Dossier ◈ Classified ◈</p>

<Table Columns="2">
  <Box>[bold]Brotherhood of Steel[/bold]</Box>
  <Box></Box>
  <Box>◈ FACTION DOSSIER ◈</Box>
  <Box></Box>
  <Box>[bold]Status[/bold]</Box>
  <Box>Active - Resurgent</Box>
  <Box>[bold]Location[/bold]</Box>
  <Box>Bonneville Salt Flats, Utah
Former Kearny Airfield</Box>
  <Box>[bold]Commander[/bold]</Box>
  <Box>[Classified] Elder</Box>
  <Box>[bold]Ideology[/bold]</Box>
  <Box>Techno-Religious Militarism
Technological Preservation</Box>
  <Box>[bold]Motto[/bold]</Box>
  <Box>[italic]Steel Be With You[/italic]</Box>
  <Box>[bold]Affiliation[/bold]</Box>
  <Box>Mojave / West Coast Brotherhood</Box>
  <Box>⬜ RESTRICTED ACCESS ⬜</Box>
  <Box></Box>
</Table>

<p>The [bold]Brotherhood of Steel (509th Chapter)[/bold] is a techno-religious military order founded by Captain Roger Maxson. This specific expeditionary force is a direct offshoot of the Mojave Chapter, adhering strictly to the traditions of the West Coast High Elders.</p>

## Core Mission

<ColorBox Color="#1a1a1a" OutlineColor="#666666" OutlineThickness="1" Margin="5">
  <Box Orientation="Vertical" Margin="8">
[italic]"To identify, secure, and preserve advanced technology, preventing its catastrophic misuse by the ignorant or the corrupt. We are the sole vanguard against the mistakes of the past; the technology of the Old World is ours to protect, by any means necessary."[/italic]
  </Box>
</ColorBox>

## History

<h3 Text="The Mojave Heritage"/>

<p>The chapter's presence in the Utah region is defined by its recovery from the events of the late 23rd century.</p>
<p>[bold]The Rise (2250s):[/bold] Under the leadership of Father Elijah, the chapter secured numerous pre-war sites, most notably the [bold]HELIOS One[/bold] solar plant. Elijah's obsession with the facility's potential as a superweapon diverted the chapter's focus away from traditional mobile recovery, anchoring them to a fixed position that would eventually draw the eyes of the New California Republic.</p>
<p>[bold]Operation Sunburst (2276):[/bold] A catastrophic conflict where the NCR launched a massive assault on HELIOS One. Despite the Brotherhood's technological superiority and T-51b Power Armor, they were outnumbered 15-to-1. The battle resulted in a devastating retreat to the Hidden Valley bunker and the mysterious disappearance of Father Elijah, leaving the chapter fractured and depleted.</p>

<h3 Text="The Lockdown &amp; Resurgence (2282–2296)"/>

<p>The history of the 509th is defined by two distinct phases: a decade of silence followed by a desperate, militant awakening.</p>

<h3 Text="The Kearny Occupation: The &quot;Silent Years&quot;"/>

<p>Following the disaster at HELIOS One in 2276, the Mojave Chapter retreated into the Hidden Valley bunker. During this chaos, a small, "disposable" detachment led by [bold]REDACTED[/bold] was dispatched toward the Northeast salt flats.</p>
<p>For over a decade, they were a loose thread in the Brotherhood's tapestry. With Hidden Valley in total lockdown under Elder McNamara and the High Elders at Lost Hills preoccupied with the NCR, the detachment received no reinforcements and fewer than five transmissions in twelve years.</p>
<p>Rather than disbanding or going rogue, the unit survived on institutional stubbornness. They operated on a lean, disciplined model, salvaging local aerospace tech and maintaining their T-51b Power Armor suits with scavenged parts and salt-flat ingenuity. They became ghosts of the desert, watching, waiting, and maintaining their gear in total isolation.</p>

<h3 Text="The Resurgence: The Enclave Catalyst"/>

<p>By early 2296, the Brotherhood has begun a cautious but deliberate resurgence. While the Mojave remains scarred by the loss of their assets, the discovery of a renewed Enclave threat in the area has shattered the policy of isolation.</p>
<p>The 509th has transitioned from a Hidden Watcher to an Active Vanguard. The tightening tensions between regional factions and the looming shadow of the Enclave have forced the Chapter's hand.</p>
<ul>
<li>[bold]Expeditionary Focus:[/bold] The 509th no longer waits for permission. They have begun deploying small, elite "Surgical Teams" deep into the Utah territories. These teams are tasked with reclaiming lost influence and securing untapped technological caches before the Enclave or local ignorant factions can seize them.</li>
<li>[bold]The New Mandate:[/bold] Isolation is no longer an option. If the 509th falls at Kearny, the Mojave is next.</li>
</ul>

## Cultural Dogma & The "Purist" Mindset

<ColorBox Color="#1a1a1a" OutlineColor="#666666" OutlineThickness="1" Margin="5">
  <Box Orientation="Vertical" Margin="8">
[italic]"The Brotherhood of Steel holds that technological and biological purity are the last bulwarks of humanity. We are the final uncorrupted lineage of mankind; all others are deviations, mutations, or outright abominations."[/italic]
  </Box>
</ColorBox>
<p>The Brotherhood of Steel practices a form of technological and biological elitism. They view themselves as the last "pure" humans and all others are varying degrees of "Abomination."</p>

<h3 Text="The Classification of Abominations"/>

<p>[italic]Use these field classifications to determine Rules of Engagement for non-human entities.[/italic]</p>

<Table Columns="2">
  <Box>[bold]1. Biological Abominations (Ghouls & Mutants)[/bold]</Box>
  <Box></Box>
  <Box>[bold]Ghouls:[/bold] Generally viewed with disgust. While the Mojave Chapter is more pragmatic than some, they view Ghouls as "shuffling corpses" or "Abominations" and a reminder of the Great War's failures. They are never members of the Brotherhood, except in desperate times, they may be recruited as Initiates or cannon fodder. [bold]Super Mutants:[/bold] An evolutionary mistake and a direct affront to nature. These must be corrected with heavy ordnance.</Box>
  <Box></Box>
  <Box>[bold]Protocol: The "Ghoul Dilemma"[/bold]</Box>
  <Box></Box>
  <Box>In the Brotherhood, biological purity is a core tenet. If a member is exposed to radiation and begins the turning process, the following paths are established:  [bold]The "Final Honor" (Self-Termination):[/bold] A member may request a final moment to secure their legacy, surrender their gear/holotags, and finish their own life to die a human rather than an abomination. This is a highly respected act of devotion. [bold]Command Discretion:[/bold] If the member does not choose the Final Honor, the Commander decides: [bold]Exile:[/bold] Stripped of all rank/property and cast out. Forbidden from returning. [bold]Execution (Mercy Purge):[/bold] Immediate termination to preserve the dignity of the fallen Brother and ensure no "abomination" carries the Order's memories.</Box>
  <Box></Box>
</Table>

<Table Columns="2">
  <Box>[bold]2. The Tool Tier (Handy, Gusty, Sentry Bots)[/bold]</Box>
  <Box></Box>
  <Box>[bold]The Logic:[/bold] These are effectively Calculators with legs. They possess Virtual Intelligence (VI) but no souls. They are slaves to their "If/Then" code and are considered Mobile Property. As long as they remain tools, they are permitted. [bold]Protocol:[/bold] Requisition, reprogram, or use as Mobile Property. However, if the unit is already in civilian/faction service, the BOS should prioritize Intelligence Gathering (Field Audits) over physical requisition. [bold]Interaction:[/bold] [italic]"Protectron, designation 0-4-4, adjust patrol vector. You are now under Brotherhood command."[/italic]</Box>
  <Box></Box>
</Table>

<Table Columns="2">
  <Box>[bold]3. The Abomination Tier (Robobrains) - Challenged[/bold]</Box>
  <Box></Box>
  <Box>[bold]The Logic:[/bold] A Robobrain uses a real, biological human brain as its processor. To the Brotherhood, this is the ultimate sin: the desecration of the human mind by trapping it in a jar to power a machine. It is a mechanical perversion. You cannot reprogram a Robobrain; you can only free the brain inside by destroying the unit. [bold]Protocol:[/bold] [bold]Immediate Termination.[/bold]</Box>
  <Box></Box>
</Table>

<Table Columns="2">
  <Box>[bold]4. The Ultimate Threat (Synths & Sentient AI)[/bold]</Box>
  <Box></Box>
  <Box>[bold]The Logic:[/bold] If a machine has its own will, it can decide that humanity is obsolete. This is exactly what the Brotherhood believes caused the Great War - technology outgrowing its masters. [bold]The AI Rule:[/bold] Any robot showing sentience (real emotion, defiance of orders, or self-awareness) is a malfunction that must be purged. [bold]Protocol:[/bold] Dismantle and study the core to ensure the infection of sentience does not spread. [bold]Interaction:[/bold] [italic]"It's mimicking human fear. Disgusting. Knight, dismantle the unit for analysis."[/italic]</Box>
  <Box></Box>
</Table>

## Culture & Society

<p>Unlike the splintered chapters that have integrated with local populations, the Mojave Brotherhood remains a closed, techno-monastic society. They strictly adhere to the "Chain of Binding," a rigid command protocol where a member only answers to their immediate superior. This ensures that even if a member is captured, the entire organizational structure remains protected.</p>
<p>In their current state, the Brotherhood operates with a "Vanguard" mentality. They view themselves as the rightful guardians of humanity's most dangerous tools, often treating wastelanders with a mixture of cold pity and suspicion. Their swift and harsh response to the "misuse" of technology ensures that local populations understand the Brotherhood's authority.</p>
<p>While the military branch (The Knights) and the research branch (The Scribes) remain distinct, the current state of the chapter requires total cohesion. Every member, regardless of their primary specialty, is expected to be a capable combatant and a scholar of the Codex. Collateral damage during recovery operations is often dismissed as a necessary sacrifice for the "Greater Good" of preventing another global catastrophe.</p>

## Brotherhood Hierarchy

<Table Columns="3">
  <Box>[bold]Rank[/bold]</Box>
  <Box>[bold]Role[/bold]</Box>
  <Box>[bold]Notes[/bold]</Box>
  <Box>Elder</Box>
  <Box>Command the chapter. Technology acquisitions, alliances, and military operations require your authorization. Other factions will seek your ear first - or avoid you entirely.</Box>
  <Box>Interprets the Codex; holds final say on the Chain of Binding.</Box>
  <Box>[bold]Head (Knight / Scribe / Paladin)[/bold]</Box>
  <Box>Supreme leaders of each branch and the primary advisory body to the Elder. Head Knight: armory & Power Armor maintenance. Head Scribe: research, archives, pre-war data. Head Paladin: tactical coordination & deployment.</Box>
  <Box>Three officers; one per branch.</Box>
  <Box>[bold]Senior (Knight / Scribe / Paladin)[/bold]</Box>
  <Box>Field officers and mentors. Supervise junior members, execute complex technical or tactical operations. Evaluate Initiate readiness.</Box>
  <Box>Often tasked with oversight of critical recovery missions.</Box>
  <Box>[bold]Paladin[/bold]</Box>
  <Box>Lead combat operations and enforce Brotherhood authority in the field. The Elder's arm - wherever you go, the chapter's will follows.</Box>
  <Box>Only members permitted to lead independent recovery teams.</Box>
  <Box>[bold]Knight[/bold]</Box>
  <Box>Protect Brotherhood territory, maintain weapons and armor. The Brotherhood's tactical backbone.</Box>
  <Box>Primary engineers and field operators; stewards of T-51b Power Armor suits.</Box>
  <Box>[bold]Scribe[/bold]</Box>
  <Box>Research, repair, and document Brotherhood technology. Your knowledge protects assets no amount of force could replace.</Box>
  <Box>Scientists, engineers, medics, and archivists. Accompany field teams when technical expertise is required.</Box>
  <Box>[bold]Squire[/bold]</Box>
  <Box>Observe, assist, and master the technical foundations under a senior mentor.</Box>
  <Box>Assigned to a specific Knight or Paladin. Permitted on low-risk missions under direct supervision only.</Box>
  <Box>[bold]Initiate[/bold]</Box>
  <Box>Follow orders. Learn the Brotherhood's ways. Prove your worth. You will be assigned the most demanding and least glamorous duties - and perform them without complaint.</Box>
  <Box>The Chapter's future. Undergo rigorous training before promotion eligibility.</Box>
</Table>

## Promotion Scripts

<p>Within the Brotherhood, advancement is earned through discipline, loyalty, and unwavering service. Promotions are not rewards but obligations, binding the promoted to greater responsibility and deeper commitment to the Codex and the Chapter.</p>

<h3 Text="Initiate → Squire"/>

<p>This ceremony marks the transition from a "new recruit" to a recognized member of the command structure.</p>
<ul>
<li>[bold]Elder/Senior:[/bold] [italic]"Initiate, you have performed your duties without complaint. You have shown the discipline required of the Brotherhood. But the path to the Steel is long."[/italic]</li>
<li>[bold]Elder/Senior:[/bold] [italic]"I hereby assign you to [Knight/Paladin Name] as their Squire. You will be their shadow. You will maintain their gear, you will carry their ammunition, and you will learn the weight of the Codex through their actions."[/italic]</li>
<li>[bold]Squire:[/bold] [italic]"I accept the burden. Steel be with you."[/italic]</li>
</ul>

<h3 Text="Initiate → Squire (Corps Assignment)"/>

<p>For Initiates not yet claimed by a mentor.</p>
<ul>
<li>[bold]Elder/Senior:[/bold] [italic]"Initiate, you have demonstrated discipline, obedience, and respect for the Codex. These qualities form the foundation of every Brotherhood soldier."[/italic]</li>
<li>[bold]Elder/Senior:[/bold] [italic]"Until a Knight or Paladin claims you for mentorship, you will serve within the Squire Corps. You will assist our Scribes, maintain our arms and armor, and learn the rhythms of the Chapter."[/italic]</li>
<li>[bold]Elder/Senior:[/bold] [italic]"Prove yourself worthy, and the Steel will open its path to you."[/italic]</li>
<li>[bold]Squire:[/bold] [italic]"I accept the duty. Steel be with you."[/italic]</li>
</ul>

<h3 Text="Squire → Knight"/>

<p>The "Big Moment" - entrusted with Power Armor.</p>
<ul>
<li>[bold]Elder:[/bold] [italic]"Squire [Name], your mentorship is complete. Your mentor vouches for your skill with the wrench and the rifle. You have proven that you understand that technology is a burden, not a toy."[/italic]</li>
<li>[bold]Elder:[/bold] [italic]"By the authority of the High Elders, I promote you to the rank of Knight. We entrust you with the relics of the Old World. Guard them with your life. Rise, Knight [Name]. Steel be with you."[/italic]</li>
<li>[bold]Knight:[/bold] [italic]"I rise in service to the Chapter. Steel protects."[/italic]</li>
</ul>

## Field Protocols

<h3 Text="Technology Classification"/>

<p>The Brotherhood categorizes gear into Tiers. Active intervention is generally reserved for [bold]Tier 3[/bold] technology.</p>

<Table Columns="3">
  <Box>[bold]Tier[/bold]</Box>
  <Box>[bold]Examples[/bold]</Box>
  <Box>[bold]Standard Procedure[/bold]</Box>
  <Box>[bold]T1[/bold]</Box>
  <Box>Service Rifles, Pistols, Leather Armor, Stimpaks</Box>
  <Box>[bold]Ignore.[/bold] Standard wasteland gear.</Box>
  <Box>[bold]T2[/bold]</Box>
  <Box>Laser Weaponry, Advanced SMG, Servo-Assisted Gauntlet, Pip-Boy</Box>
  <Box>[bold]Monitor.[/bold] Note the owner and origin. No intervention yet.</Box>
  <Box>[bold]T3[/bold]</Box>
  <Box>Plasma/Gauss Weapons, Power Armor, Pre-War Holotapes</Box>
  <Box>[bold]Requisition.[/bold] Active Brotherhood intervention is authorized and expected.</Box>
</Table>

## Rules of Engagement (The Escalation Ladder)

<p>[italic]When Tier 3 technology is identified in "unauthorized" hands (NCR, Legion, or Civilians), members must follow these steps:[/italic]</p>
<ul>
<li>[bold]The Formal Request:[/bold] State the hazard and offer a trade if possible. [italic]"Hold there, Wastelander. That Plasma Rifle is a dangerous relic of the Old World; you are unauthorized to possess it. For the safety of the wastes, we request you turn it over. In exchange, we can offer you Caps and a reliable Service Rifle."[/italic]</li>
<li>[bold]The Final Warning:[/bold] If the request is refused, weapons are drawn (but not fired). [italic]"This is not a request, Trooper. That technology is beyond your understanding and poses a threat to the region. Hand over the hardware now, or it will be secured by force. Final warning."[/italic]</li>
<li>[bold]Forced Seizure:[/bold] Combat is authorized [bold]only[/bold] to disable the tech-user. Once the player is "downed," the BOS secures the specific item and retreats immediately. [bold]Strict Rule:[/bold] Do NOT loot the player's personal items (food, water, armor, caps). Only the high-tech objective (and its specific ammo) is to be taken.</li>
</ul>

<h3 Text="Post-Seizure Protocol"/>

<p>If the subject does not demonstrate continued hostility and instead attempts to disengage or flee, lethal force is not authorized. Following recovery of the technology, the subject is to be stabilized to a condition in which they can safely vacate the area.</p>
<p>The use of basic medical aid is permitted if required. Termination is only authorized under the following conditions:</p>
<ul>
<li>Direct orders from a higher-ranking member</li>
<li>Renewed hostile action from the subject</li>
<li>Environmental or situational threats that endanger the Brotherhood member</li>
</ul>

## Formal Greetings & Mottos

<Table Columns="2">
  <Box>[bold]Phrase[/bold]</Box>
  <Box>[bold]Usage & Field Dialogue[/bold]</Box>
  <Box>[bold]Steel Be With You[/bold]</Box>
  <Box>A parting phrase, often used by Scribes or during somber moments. [italic]"You're heading into a high-rad zone, Knight. Steel be with you."[/italic]</Box>
  <Box>[bold]Walk in the Light of the Founders[/bold]</Box>
  <Box>A formal blessing reserved for ceremonies or Elders. [italic]"You have served the Chapter well this day. Walk in the light of the Founders."[/italic]</Box>
  <Box>[bold]Knowledge is Our Shield[/bold]</Box>
  <Box>A Scribe-favored motto emphasizing that preservation of technology is the Order's true protection. [italic]"Secure the mainframe first. Remember, Initiate: Knowledge is our shield."[/italic]</Box>
  <Box>[bold]By the Will of the Founders[/bold]</Box>
  <Box>A formal declaration invoking the authority of the Founders and the Maxson lineage; used when issuing orders rooted in doctrine rather than circumstance. [italic]"This bunker will be secured by the will of the Founders. No deviation from the Codex will be tolerated."[/italic]</Box>
</Table>

## Brotherhood Lingo & Slang

<p>Use these terms to establish the Brotherhood's "Techno-Monastic" superiority. Using the correct term for an outsider defines your character's personality.</p>

<Table Columns="2">
  <Box>[bold]Term[/bold]</Box>
  <Box>[bold]Definition & Field Usage[/bold]</Box>
  <Box>[bold]Abomination[/bold]</Box>
  <Box>Any non-human threat (Ghouls, Mutants, Synths, Robobrains). [italic]"Target the Abomination! Don't let that Super Mutant pass the line."[/italic]</Box>
  <Box>[bold]The Chain[/bold]</Box>
  <Box>Short for the Chain of Binding (the command structure). [italic]"I don't care if you disagree. Respect the Chain and follow your orders."[/italic]</Box>
  <Box>[bold]Relic[/bold]</Box>
  <Box>Any piece of Tier 3 technology (Plasma, Power Armor, Pre-War data). [italic]"We have secured a pre-war Relic. Knight, prepare the transport crate."[/italic]</Box>
  <Box>[bold]The Codex[/bold]</Box>
  <Box>The governing set of laws for the Brotherhood. [italic]"That action is not supported by the Codex, Knight."[/italic]</Box>
  <Box>[bold]Hard-Case[/bold]</Box>
  <Box>A term used for someone in Power Armor (usually a Knight or Paladin). [italic]"We need two Hard-Cases to breach that vault door."[/italic]</Box>
</Table>

## Faction Relations

<p>As of 2296, the Brotherhood operates under a state of [bold]Tense Neutrality[/bold] with most organized groups.</p>

<Table Columns="3">
  <Box>[bold]Faction[/bold]</Box>
  <Box>[bold]Standing[/bold]</Box>
  <Box>[bold]Diplomacy & Field Interaction[/bold]</Box>
  <Box>[textlink="NCR" link="https://ss14.misfitsystems.net/wiki/index.php/New_California_Republic"/]</Box>
  <Box>Cold Hostile</Box>
  <Box>Post-Sunburst ceasefire observed. [italic]"NCR. Maintain your distance and keep your weapons holstered. We have no business with you today."[/italic]</Box>
  <Box>[textlink="Caesar's Legion" link="https://ss14.misfitsystems.net/wiki/index.php/Caesar%27s_Legion"/]</Box>
  <Box>Tense Neutral</Box>
  <Box>Viewed as primitive but dangerous. [italic]"Halt, Legionnaire. Do not interfere with our recovery operations, and we shall not interfere with your conquest."[/italic]</Box>
  <Box>[textlink="Wastelanders" link="https://ss14.misfitsystems.net/wiki/index.php/Wastelanders"/]</Box>
  <Box>Watchful</Box>
  <Box>Unaffiliated survivors. Viewed as "ignorant" and prone to tech misuse. [italic]"Move along, scavenger. These ruins are under Brotherhood jurisdiction."[/italic]</Box>
  <Box>[textlink="Townsfolk" link="https://ss14.misfitsystems.net/wiki/index.php/Townsfolk"/]</Box>
  <Box>Managed</Box>
  <Box>"Managed Populations." Protected from external threats, kept at arm's length. [italic]"The Brotherhood is conducting a sweep for hazardous materials. Stay within the town perimeter for your own safety."[/italic]</Box>
  <Box>[textlink="Vault Dwellers" link="https://ss14.misfitsystems.net/wiki/index.php/Vault_Dwellers"/]</Box>
  <Box>Curious / Suspicious</Box>
  <Box>Viewed with curiosity but suspicion regarding their Vault's technology. [italic]"A Vault-Tec jumpsuit. Tell me, dweller, is your Vault's reactor still operational? We may need to perform a safety audit."[/italic]</Box>
  <Box>[textlink="Followers of the Apocalypse" link="https://ss14.misfitsystems.net/wiki/index.php/Followers_of_the_Apocalypse"/]</Box>
  <Box>Hostile</Box>
  <Box>Their tech-sharing directly threatens the Mission. [italic]"Your 'charity' is dangerous, Follower. You provide tools the wasteland is not yet ready to handle."[/italic]</Box>
  <Box>[textlink="Outlaws" link="https://ss14.misfitsystems.net/wiki/index.php/Outlaws"/]</Box>
  <Box>Hostile</Box>
  <Box>Raiders and bandits. Threats to be swept aside. [italic]"Clear the area, scavver, or be cleared."[/italic]</Box>
  <Box>[textlink="Super Mutants" link="https://ss14.misfitsystems.net/wiki/index.php/Super_Mutants"/]</Box>
  <Box>[bold]Kill on Sight[/bold]</Box>
  <Box>Biological Abominations. No exceptions. [italic]"Target the Abomination. Heavy ordnance authorized."[/italic]</Box>
  <Box>[textlink="Automated Units" link="https://ss14.misfitsystems.net/wiki/index.php/Synthetics"/]</Box>
  <Box>Mobile Property</Box>
  <Box>Use Field Audits to check logic and prime directives. [italic]"Unit, state your designation and current prime directive. Report any high-tier technology signatures detected."[/italic]</Box>
</Table>

</Document>
