<Document>
# Washington Brotherhood of Steel

[textlink="View Full Wiki Page" link="https://ss14.misfitsystems.net/wiki/index.php/Brotherhood_of_Steel"]

<Table Columns="2">
  <Box>[bold]Status[/bold]</Box>
  <Box>[color=#4caf50]Active — Minor Faction[/color]</Box>
  <Box>[bold]Location[/bold]</Box>
  <Box>Operating covertly near Wendover</Box>
  <Box>[bold]Leadership[/bold]</Box>
  <Box>Elder (Washington Chapter Commander)</Box>
  <Box>[bold]Ideology[/bold]</Box>
  <Box>Technological elitism, biological purism</Box>
  <Box>[bold]Motto[/bold]</Box>
  <Box>[italic]"Technology must be earned."[/italic]</Box>
</Table>

<p>The Washington Brotherhood of Steel is a splinter branch descended from a Midwest Brotherhood expedition that lost contact with their parent organization long ago. Cut off from their origins, they evolved into a purist faction that mirrors the ideals of the original Brotherhood — but with a harder edge. They are the most formidable military force in the local Wasteland, possessing power armor, energy weapons, and an uncompromising will to use them.</p>

<hr/>

## Philosophy

<p>The Washington Brotherhood holds to strict technological elitism. They believe only they are qualified to possess and utilize advanced technology. They are hostile to mutants of all kinds and deeply suspicious of outsiders. They act discreetly when possible — but if they choose to act openly, they bring overwhelming firepower.</p>

<hr/>

## Roles

<ColorBox Color="#3B72BF">
  <Box Margin="2">
  [bold]Elder[/bold]
  </Box>
</ColorBox>
<Box>
[color=#a4885c]Your role:[/color] The supreme authority of the Washington Brotherhood. All major decisions flow through you. You rarely appear in the field, but your word is absolute law. Set the chapter's agenda and determine how aggressively to pursue technology acquisition in the region.
</Box>

<br/>

<ColorBox Color="#3B72BF">
  <Box Margin="2">
  [bold]Paladin[/bold]
  </Box>
</ColorBox>
<Box>
[color=#a4885c]Your role:[/color] Elite warrior in full power armor. The enforcement arm of the Brotherhood — feared throughout the Wasteland. Execute the Elder's directives and lead operations in the field.
</Box>

<br/>

<ColorBox Color="#3B72BF">
  <Box Margin="2">
  [bold]Knight[/bold]
  </Box>
</ColorBox>
<Box>
[color=#a4885c]Your role:[/color] Veteran soldiers outfitted with Brotherhood-standard gear. The backbone of the chapter's combat strength. Protect assets, enforce the Elder's will, and keep the chapter's equipment battle-ready.
</Box>

<br/>

<ColorBox Color="#3B72BF">
  <Box Margin="2">
  [bold]Scribe[/bold]
  </Box>
</ColorBox>
<Box>
[color=#a4885c]Your role:[/color] Scholar and technician responsible for cataloguing, maintaining, and recovering technology. Your records are what justify the Brotherhood's mission. Keep them current and accurate.
</Box>

<br/>

<ColorBox Color="#3B72BF">
  <Box Margin="2">
  [bold]Initiate[/bold]
  </Box>
</ColorBox>
<Box>
[color=#a4885c]Your role:[/color] New recruit undergoing Brotherhood training. Monitored closely and not yet trusted with the faction's most valuable assets. Follow every order, learn fast, and earn the trust of those above you.
</Box>

<hr/>

## Faction Relations

<Table Columns="3">
  <Box>[bold][color=#a4885c]Faction[/color][/bold]</Box>
  <Box>[bold][color=#a4885c]Standing[/color][/bold]</Box>
  <Box>[bold][color=#a4885c]Notes[/color][/bold]</Box>
  <Box>NCR</Box>
  <Box>[color=#cc3333]Hostile[/color]</Box>
  <Box>Competing interests over technology and territory.</Box>
  <Box>Midwest Brotherhood</Box>
  <Box>[color=#a4885c]Complex[/color]</Box>
  <Box>Shared lineage, opposing doctrine. Their recruitmen policy is an affront.</Box>
  <Box>Caesar's Legion</Box>
  <Box>[color=#cc3333]Hostile[/color]</Box>
  <Box>The Legion destroys what the Brotherhood is here to preserve.</Box>
  <Box>Townsfolk</Box>
  <Box>[color=#ffb000]Managed[/color]</Box>
  <Box>Protected from threats, kept at arm's length. Vault-Tec tech is of interest.</Box>
  <Box>Wastelanders</Box>
  <Box>[color=#ffb000]Dismissive[/color]</Box>
  <Box>Ignorant civilians. Tech confiscation likely if advanced equipment is spotted.</Box>
  <Box>Enclave</Box>
  <Box>[color=#cc3333]Kill on Sight[/color]</Box>
  <Box>Existential threat. The catalyst that drove the chapter's resurgence.</Box>
</Table>

</Document>
