<Document>
# Wasteland Tribes

[textlink="View Full Wiki Page" link="https://ss14.misfitsystems.net/wiki/index.php/Wasteland_Tribes"]

<Table Columns="2">
  <Box>[bold]Status[/bold]</Box>
  <Box>Active — Independent communities</Box>
  <Box>[bold]Location[/bold]</Box>
  <Box>Various camps near Wendover</Box>
  <Box>[bold]Leadership[/bold]</Box>
  <Box>Tribal Chieftain (per tribe)</Box>
  <Box>[bold]Ideology[/bold]</Box>
  <Box>Community, oral tradition, self-reliance</Box>
  <Box>[bold]Motto[/bold]</Box>
  <Box>[italic]"The land remembers. We remember with it."[/italic]</Box>
</Table>

<hr/>

<p>Tribes are among the oldest post-war social structures in the Fallout universe. Long before the NCR organized a government or the Brotherhood fortified a bunker, tribal communities formed from survivors who stayed together through kinship, shared land, and shared belief. They have endured for over two centuries through deep environmental knowledge, oral tradition, and fierce community bonds.</p>

<p>Each tribe is shaped entirely by its Chieftain. The Chieftain's philosophy defines whether the tribe is peaceful or aggressive, isolationist or open to trade, suspicious of technology or eager to adopt it.</p>

<hr/>

## Philosophy

<ColorBox Color="#1a1a1a" OutlineColor="#d69b3d" OutlineThickness="1" Margin="5">
  <Box Orientation="Vertical" Margin="8">
    [italic]"The land provides. The tribe endures. What more does anyone need?"[/italic]
  </Box>
</ColorBox>

<p>Tribal societies place community over individual ambition and oral history over written records. They often possess environmental knowledge that outsiders entirely miss — which plants are edible, which ruins are stable, which seasonal patterns the Wasteland follows. What all tribes share is a fierce will to survive on their own terms.</p>

<hr/>

## Roles

<ColorBox Color="#d69b3d">
  <Box Margin="2">
  [bold]Tribal Chieftain[/bold]
  </Box>
</ColorBox>
<Box>
[color=#a4885c]Your role:[/color] Set your tribe's character for the round. Decide how your people relate to the town, the NCR, the Brotherhood, and the wider Wasteland. Your choices shape everyone beneath you — make them with intention.
</Box>

<br/>

<ColorBox Color="#d69b3d">
  <Box Margin="2">
  [bold]Tribal Warrior[/bold]
  </Box>
</ColorBox>
<Box>
[color=#a4885c]Your role:[/color] Protect the tribe and enforce the Chieftain's will in the field. When conflict arrives — and it will — you are the tribe's first and last line of defense.
</Box>

<br/>

<ColorBox Color="#d69b3d">
  <Box Margin="2">
  [bold]Tribal Shaman[/bold]
  </Box>
</ColorBox>
<Box>
[color=#a4885c]Your role:[/color] Heal the tribe, maintain its traditions, and counsel the Chieftain. You are the keeper of what the tribe was and the guide toward what it might become. Your expertise makes you valuable to outsiders as well.
</Box>

<br/>

<ColorBox Color="#d69b3d">
  <Box Margin="2">
  [bold]Tribesperson[/bold]
  </Box>
</ColorBox>
<Box>
[color=#a4885c]Your role:[/color] Keep the tribe alive. Hunt, gather, farm, and craft. Your labor is the foundation that every Chieftain's decision rests on. Without you, there is no tribe.
</Box>

<hr/>

## Faction Relations

<Table Columns="3">
  <Box>[bold][color=#a4885c]Faction[/color][/bold]</Box>
  <Box>[bold][color=#a4885c]Standing[/color][/bold]</Box>
  <Box>[bold][color=#a4885c]Notes[/color][/bold]</Box>
  <Box>NCR</Box>
  <Box>[color=#a4885c]Variable[/color]</Box>
  <Box>Depends on Chieftain's decision. Some trade, some resist annexation.</Box>
  <Box>Brotherhood of Steel</Box>
  <Box>[color=#ffb000]Cautious[/color]</Box>
  <Box>Mixed record — some chapters recruit tribal warriors, others view them with suspicion.</Box>
  <Box>Caesar's Legion</Box>
  <Box>[color=#cc3333]Hostile[/color]</Box>
  <Box>The Legion conquers and assimilates tribes by force.</Box>
  <Box>Townsfolk</Box>
  <Box>[color=#6bba5e]Friendly[/color]</Box>
  <Box>Trade partners. Tribes bring herbs, hides, and knowledge the town needs.</Box>
  <Box>Wastelanders</Box>
  <Box>[color=#a4885c]Variable[/color]</Box>
  <Box>Treated individually. Some are welcomed, some are watched.</Box>
  <Box>Caravan Company</Box>
  <Box>[color=#6bba5e]Friendly[/color]</Box>
  <Box>Regular trade partners. Caravans supply what the land cannot.</Box>
  <Box>Followers of the Apocalypse</Box>
  <Box>[color=#6bba5e]Friendly[/color]</Box>
  <Box>Respected for their healing knowledge and willingness to teach.</Box>
</Table>
</Document>
