<Document>
# Wastelanders

[textlink="View Full Wiki Page" link="https://ss14.misfitsystems.net/wiki/index.php/Wastelanders"/]

<p>◈ Wastelanders ◈ Faction Dossier ◈ Independent ◈</p>

<Table Columns="2">
  <Box>[bold]Wastelanders[/bold]</Box>
  <Box></Box>
  <Box>◈ FACTION DOSSIER ◈</Box>
  <Box></Box>
  <Box>[bold]Status[/bold]</Box>
  <Box>Active - Unaligned</Box>
  <Box>[bold]Location[/bold]</Box>
  <Box>The Wasteland
Wendover Region, Utah</Box>
  <Box>[bold]Commander[/bold]</Box>
  <Box>None</Box>
  <Box>[bold]Ideology[/bold]</Box>
  <Box>Personal Code
Survival</Box>
  <Box>[bold]Motto[/bold]</Box>
  <Box>[italic]Nobody's soldier. Nobody's enemy.[/italic]</Box>
  <Box>[bold]Affiliation[/bold]</Box>
  <Box>Independent</Box>
  <Box>⬜ RESTRICTED ACCESS ⬜</Box>
  <Box></Box>
</Table>

<p>[bold]Wastelanders[/bold] are the independent survivors of the nuclear devastation - people who belong to no faction, answer to no flag, and make their living on the open Wasteland through skill, instinct, and personal code. They are the beating heart of every Fallout story: wanderers who walk into every situation without a predetermined role and walk out having shaped it.</p>
<p>No two Wastelanders are alike. Former raiders who went straight. Travelers heading somewhere better. Drifters who have been walking since before they can remember. What they share is a refusal to be defined by anyone else's war.</p>

## Philosophy

<ColorBox Color="#1a1a1a" OutlineColor="#666666" OutlineThickness="1" Margin="5">
  <Box Orientation="Vertical" Margin="8">
[italic]"There is no single Wastelander philosophy - that is the point. Independence and personal code are all that connects them. Some run by honor, others by caps, others by something harder to name. The Wasteland does not ask for justification. Only survival."[/italic]
  </Box>
</ColorBox>

## Roles

<Table Columns="3">
  <Box>[bold]Role[/bold]</Box>
  <Box>[bold]Description[/bold]</Box>
  <Box>[bold]Notes[/bold]</Box>
  <Box>Drifter</Box>
  <Box>You are nobody's soldier and nobody's enemy by default. Make alliances, take contracts, pursue your own goals - or make someone else's goals your own. You are the wildcard this round needs.</Box>
  <Box>Maximum freedom. No allegiance required.</Box>
  <Box>[bold]Scavenger[/bold]</Box>
  <Box>Explore, recover, and trade. You know what things are worth and where to look for them. The resources you bring back keep the local economy moving - and your own caps flowing.</Box>
  <Box>Exploration and trade specialist.</Box>
  <Box>[bold]Wasteland Medic[/bold]</Box>
  <Box>Provide medical care to anyone who needs it - for caps, for favors, or out of principle. Your neutrality is a strength: you can go where soldiers cannot and be trusted where guns would get the door slammed.</Box>
  <Box>Independent medical provider.</Box>
</Table>

## Relations

<p>Wastelanders can work with or against any faction depending on personal goals and available caps. They are the wildcards of every round - their choices can shift the balance between factions in directions no one predicted.</p>

<Table Columns="3">
  <Box>[bold]Faction[/bold]</Box>
  <Box>[bold]Standing[/bold]</Box>
  <Box>[bold]Notes[/bold]</Box>
  <Box>[textlink="Townsfolk" link="https://ss14.misfitsystems.net/wiki/index.php/Townsfolk"/]</Box>
  <Box>Variable</Box>
  <Box>Towns are where Wastelanders trade, resupply, and find work. The relationship is transactional.</Box>
  <Box>[textlink="NCR" link="https://ss14.misfitsystems.net/wiki/index.php/New_California_Republic"/]</Box>
  <Box>Variable</Box>
  <Box>The NCR offers stability. Some Wastelanders appreciate that. Others see it as a leash.</Box>
  <Box>[textlink="Brotherhood of Steel" link="https://ss14.misfitsystems.net/wiki/index.php/Brotherhood_of_Steel"/]</Box>
  <Box>Watchful</Box>
  <Box>The Brotherhood views Wastelanders as "ignorant" - a nuisance to be managed, not an enemy to be destroyed.</Box>
  <Box>[textlink="Caesar's Legion" link="https://ss14.misfitsystems.net/wiki/index.php/Caesar%27s_Legion"/]</Box>
  <Box>Dangerous</Box>
  <Box>Unaligned travelers in Legion territory are enslaved or killed.</Box>
  <Box>[textlink="Followers of the Apocalypse" link="https://ss14.misfitsystems.net/wiki/index.php/Followers_of_the_Apocalypse"/]</Box>
  <Box>Friendly</Box>
  <Box>The Followers provide free medical care. Wastelanders are frequent patients.</Box>
  <Box>[textlink="Outlaws" link="https://ss14.misfitsystems.net/wiki/index.php/Outlaws"/]</Box>
  <Box>Variable</Box>
  <Box>Some Wastelanders were raiders once. Some still deal with them. The line is blurry.</Box>
</Table>

<p>[bold]Note:[/bold] Wastelanders are [bold]excluded[/bold] from faction-wide [textlink="war enlistment" link="https://ss14.misfitsystems.net/wiki/index.php/Faction_War"/]. They may join a side individually via [bold]/warjoin[/bold] but are never auto-drafted.</p>

</Document>
