<Document>
# Guide to Townsfolk

[textlink="View Full Wiki Page" link="https://ss14.misfitsystems.net/wiki/index.php/Townsfolk"]

<Table Columns="2">
  <Box>[bold]Status[/bold]</Box>
  <Box>Active — Settled community</Box>
  <Box>[bold]Location[/bold]</Box>
  <Box>Oasis (Wendover town center)</Box>
  <Box>[bold]Leadership[/bold]</Box>
  <Box>Mayor &amp; Sheriff</Box>
  <Box>[bold]Ideology[/bold]</Box>
  <Box>Neutrality, trade, community defense</Box>
  <Box>[bold]Motto[/bold]</Box>
  <Box>[italic]"Keep the peace. Keep the lights on."[/italic]</Box>
</Table>

<hr/>

## Core Mission

<ColorBox Color="#1a1a1a" OutlineColor="#5c733a" OutlineThickness="1" Margin="5">
  <Box Orientation="Vertical" Margin="8">
    [italic]"To provide a secure, neutral haven for trade, shelter, and survival, prioritizing the prosperity of our citizens and the strict enforcement of the peace, regardless of what colors you wear outside the gates."[/italic]
  </Box>
</ColorBox>

<hr/>

## Roles

<ColorBox Color="#5c733a">
  <Box Margin="2">
  [bold]Mayor[/bold]
  </Box>
</ColorBox>
<Box>
[color=#a4885c]Your role:[/color] Lead Oasis. Coordinate with the Sheriff on security and negotiate with outside factions on behalf of your people. Every deal you make has consequences for every person in town.
</Box>

<br/>

<ColorBox Color="#5c733a">
  <Box Margin="2">
  [bold]Sheriff[/bold]
  </Box>
</ColorBox>
<Box>
[color=#a4885c]Your role:[/color] Protect Oasis from threats internal and external. Manage your deputies, keep the peace, and work alongside the Mayor on anything that touches both law and politics. What your badge means to this town is entirely up to how you carry it.
</Box>

<br/>

<ColorBox Color="#5c733a">
  <Box Margin="2">
  [bold]Deputy[/bold]
  </Box>
</ColorBox>
<Box>
[color=#a4885c]Your role:[/color] Support the Sheriff. Enforce order, investigate problems, and step up when the Sheriff is unavailable. Your loyalty to the badge — and the people it's supposed to protect — defines what law means in Oasis.
</Box>

<br/>

<ColorBox Color="#5c733a">
  <Box Margin="2">
  [bold]Shopkeeper[/bold]
  </Box>
</ColorBox>
<Box>
[color=#a4885c]Your role:[/color] Stock and run the town's store. Trade with travelers, manage inventory, and keep the local economy moving. You may not carry a weapon to war, but caps talk — and yours talk loudly.
</Box>

<br/>

<ColorBox Color="#5c733a">
  <Box Margin="2">
  [bold]Mechanic[/bold]
  </Box>
</ColorBox>
<Box>
[color=#a4885c]Your role:[/color] Repair and maintain the settlement's critical equipment — weapons, armor, robots, and machinery. Craft new items for the town's defense or for sale to travelers. When something breaks, everyone comes to you.
</Box>

<br/>

<ColorBox Color="#5c733a">
  <Box Margin="2">
  [bold]Doctor[/bold]
  </Box>
</ColorBox>
<Box>
[color=#a4885c]Your role:[/color] Provide medical care to townsfolk and travelers. Charge for your services or give them freely — that is your call. Your skills will be needed before the round ends, regardless of how peacefully things start.
</Box>

<br/>

<ColorBox Color="#5c733a">
  <Box Margin="2">
  [bold]Townsperson[/bold]
  </Box>
</ColorBox>
<Box>
[color=#a4885c]Your role:[/color] Work the land, tend animals, craft goods, and do what your town needs to stay alive. You are not a soldier — but the Wasteland has a way of making everyone a fighter eventually.
</Box>

<hr/>

## Faction Relations

<Table Columns="3">
  <Box>[bold][color=#a4885c]Faction[/color][/bold]</Box>
  <Box>[bold][color=#a4885c]Standing[/color][/bold]</Box>
  <Box>[bold][color=#a4885c]Notes[/color][/bold]</Box>
  <Box>NCR</Box>
  <Box>[color=#6bba5e]Friendly[/color]</Box>
  <Box>Trade and mutual defense. NCR provides security for supply routes.</Box>
  <Box>Brotherhood of Steel</Box>
  <Box>[color=#a4885c]Neutral[/color]</Box>
  <Box>Tolerated so long as they buy supplies and don't confiscate property.</Box>
  <Box>Caesar's Legion</Box>
  <Box>[color=#cc3333]Hostile[/color]</Box>
  <Box>The Legion views unaligned settlements as resources to be taken.</Box>
  <Box>Tribes</Box>
  <Box>[color=#6bba5e]Friendly[/color]</Box>
  <Box>Regular trade partners. Tribes supply raw materials the town needs.</Box>
  <Box>Wastelanders</Box>
  <Box>[color=#6bba5e]Welcome[/color]</Box>
  <Box>Travelers and drifters are welcome as long as they keep the peace.</Box>
  <Box>Caravan Company</Box>
  <Box>[color=#6bba5e]Allied[/color]</Box>
  <Box>The town's economic lifeline. Without caravans, the town stagnates.</Box>
  <Box>Outlaws</Box>
  <Box>[color=#cc3333]Hostile[/color]</Box>
  <Box>Raiders are shot on sight inside town limits.</Box>
</Table>

<p>[color=#a4885c]Note:[/color] Townsfolk are a [bold]war-capable[/bold] faction and can participate in the Faction War system.</p>
</Document>