<Document>
# New California Republic (NCR)

[textlink="View Full Wiki Page" link="https://ss14.misfitsystems.net/wiki/index.php/New_California_Republic"]

<Table Columns="2">
  <p>[bold]Status[/bold]</p>  <p>[color=#4caf50]Active — Major Faction[/color]</p>
  <p>[bold]Base[/bold]</p>  <p>Bonneville Station, Nevada side of Wendover bridge</p>
  <p>[bold]Leadership[/bold]</p>  <p>Major Blackhawk &amp; Major Walker (Salt Dogs Battalion)</p>
  <p>[bold]Ideology[/bold]</p>  <p>Democracy, Rule of Law, Expansionism</p>
  <p>[bold]Motto[/bold]</p>  <p>[italic]"For the Republic"[/italic]</p>
</Table>

<p>The New California Republic stands as a beacon of democracy and order in the wasteland — a federal presidential republic rooted in old values of democracy, personal freedom, and the sanctity of law. Founded by Aradesh and his daughter Tandi in Shady Sands, it is now led by President Aaron Kimball. The NCR's mission is to restore civilization, uplift infrastructure and economic frameworks, and foster peace. But the Republic is not without flaws: it grapples with expansion, territorial disputes, wavering loyalties, and rising corruption.</p>

<hr/>

## Bonneville Station: The Salt Dogs Battalion

<p>The NCR's foothold east of Nevada is held by the [bold]Salt Dogs Battalion[/bold], garrisoned at Bonneville Station on the Nevada side of the Wendover bridge. The Utah side is maintained as a forward checkpoint on rotation. The bridge itself is a permanent NCR asset — it does not change hands.</p>

<p>The battalion is commanded jointly by [bold]Major Blackhawk[/bold] and [bold]Major Walker[/bold]. Intelligence operations are coordinated by [bold]DAGGER-02[/bold], a Ranger attached from regional command.</p>

<p>Wendover sits at the last real chokepoint before Utah opens into open wastes. I-80 runs through it. The salt trade runs through it. Whatever moves east or west in this region moves through Bonneville, and the Salt Dogs are there to make sure the NCR has a say in how it moves.</p>

<ColorBox Color="#1a1a1a" OutlineColor="#fbc02d" OutlineThickness="1" Margin="5">
  <Box Orientation="Vertical" Margin="8">
    [italic]"Station is established. Major Blackhawk and Major Walker are on the ground and operational. We're here for I-80 and salt. Wendover is the last real chokepoint before Utah opens up. The Brotherhood has dug into the old airfield on the Utah side. They're not here by accident and they aren't telling us why. Legion presence has been noted in the region. Extent and intent unknown."[/italic]
    — DAGGER-02, Bonneville Station
  </Box>
</ColorBox>

<hr/>

## Laws

<p>Dictated by the constitution of the Republic, every citizen of the NCR — civilian or military — must follow these laws.</p>

<p>It is a crime to [bold]take the life of another[/bold], be it murder or manslaughter. These acts are harshly punished; punishment can reach execution. It is a crime to [bold]steal from another[/bold] regardless of circumstances, punishable by prison with the possibility of parole.</p>

[bold]Basic Rights:[/bold]
<ul>
<li>The right to own personal property</li>
<li>The right to freedom of expression, religion, and speech</li>
<li>The right to self-defense</li>
<li>The right to bear a sidearm and concealed carry inside NCR-controlled territories</li>
<li>The right to enlist</li>
<li>The right to an attorney</li>
<li>The right to remain silent in cases of self-incrimination</li>
<li>The right to a fair trial</li>
</ul>

<p>In the case of criminal arrest, all rights barring the right to remain silent, to a fair trial, and to an attorney are suspended.</p>

<p>[bold]Treason:[/bold] All acts of treason are, in most cases, punishable by death. Includes: fraternizing with or providing information to an enemy of the state, terrorism, desertion, and dereliction of duty.</p>

<p>[bold]Fraudulent Activities:[/bold] Punishable by prison or voluntary labor. Includes: money laundering, identity theft, falsification of reports or official documents, forgery of currency, and the sale and distribution of illicit substances (Jet, Psycho, Turbo).</p>

<hr/>

## New California Republic Army (NCRA)

<p>The defense forces of the Republic. The NCR Army must tackle conflicts in a non-aggressive way — de-escalate first, deal with threats with the minimum of force possible. Assaulting enemy settlements is discouraged except when absolutely necessary, and only with supervision of High Command.</p>

<ColorBox Color="#1a1a1a" OutlineColor="#fbc02d" OutlineThickness="1" Margin="5">
  <Box Orientation="Vertical" Margin="8">
    [italic]"The mission of the NCR is to uphold the law in the region, as well as trying to gain anything valuable — trading with major powers or settlements, or obtaining resources from the area. Expansionism is allowed but only by diplomacy or to expel a threat. Keeping a good image of the Republic is key."[/italic]
  </Box>
</ColorBox>

[bold]Basic Principles:[/bold]
<ul>
<li>Follow the rules of war and human rights</li>
<li>Obey the chain of command</li>
<li>While on duty, do not drink alcohol or gamble</li>
<li>Treat prisoners with respect and dignity. Field execution can only be authorized by officers or High Command</li>
<li>Wear your uniform at all times when conducting NCR operations. Dog tags and rank pins must always be visible</li>
<li>NCR Troops cannot go off duty whenever they desire. It must be passed through the chain of command</li>
</ul>

<p>[bold]Field Promotions[/bold] are legal. An NCO may promote enlisted personnel; a CO may promote an NCO for exceptional service. Cannot promote between branches, nor from Enlisted to NCO to CO, and can only promote to specialized jobs if the soldier has actual training in that specialization.</p>

## Chain of Command

<hr/>

## Officers

<ColorBox Color="#fbc02d">
  <Box Margin="2">
  [bold]Captain[/bold]
  </Box>
</ColorBox>
<Box>
[color=#a4885c]Your role:[/color] Command the NCR's local detachment. All military and diplomatic decisions run through you. Balance force, political dealings, and the Republic's interests — your choices determine whether the NCR gains a foothold in Wendover or retreats in failure.
</Box>

<br/>

<ColorBox Color="#fbc02d">
  <Box Margin="2">
  [bold]Lieutenant[/bold]
  </Box>
</ColorBox>
<Box>
[color=#a4885c]Your role:[/color] Second-in-command. Support the Captain, manage day-to-day operations, and step into command if the Captain is unavailable. You are the bridge between officer intent and the NCOs who execute it.
</Box>

<br/>

<ColorBox Color="#fbc02d">
  <Box Margin="2">
  [bold]Medical Doctor[/bold]
  </Box>
</ColorBox>
<Box>
[color=#a4885c]Your role:[/color] Senior medical officer attached to the NCR detachment. Keep soldiers combat-capable, treat civilian allies to build goodwill, and advise command on medical threats. Your skills are a diplomatic asset as much as a survival one.
</Box>

<hr/>

## Non-Commissioned Officers

<ColorBox Color="#fbc02d">
  <Box Margin="2">
  [bold]Sergeant First Class[/bold]
  </Box>
</ColorBox>
<Box>
[color=#a4885c]Your role:[/color] Senior NCO of the detachment. You translate officer intent into enlisted action — enforcing discipline, managing formation readiness, and carrying the load between command and the soldiers who carry out its orders.
</Box>

<br/>

<ColorBox Color="#fbc02d">
  <Box Margin="2">
  [bold]Staff Sergeant[/bold]
  </Box>
</ColorBox>
<Box>
[color=#a4885c]Your role:[/color] Senior squad leader. Lead your troops in the field, coordinate with the Sergeant First Class, and handle the mid-level decisions that keep small-unit operations running.
</Box>

<br/>

<ColorBox Color="#fbc02d">
  <Box Margin="2">
  [bold]Sergeant[/bold]
  </Box>
</ColorBox>
<Box>
[color=#a4885c]Your role:[/color] Squad leader. Know your soldiers, execute the Staff Sergeant's direction, and make the right call when there is no time to ask. NCR troopers live or die by Sergeant-level judgment.
</Box>

<hr/>

## Enlisted

<ColorBox Color="#fbc02d">
  <Box Margin="2">
  [bold]Specialist[/bold]
  </Box>
</ColorBox>
<Box>
[color=#a4885c]Your role:[/color] Trained specialist serving in combat, engineering, or medical roles. Pick your loadout to match the mission. Your versatility is what makes the NCR work.
</Box>

<br/>

<ColorBox Color="#fbc02d">
  <Box Margin="2">
  [bold]Private First Class[/bold]
  </Box>
</ColorBox>
<Box>
[color=#a4885c]Your role:[/color] Experienced private. You have proven you can be relied on — better gear, more latitude, a little more trust from the NCOs above you.
</Box>

<br/>

<ColorBox Color="#fbc02d">
  <Box Margin="2">
  [bold]Private[/bold]
  </Box>
</ColorBox>
<Box>
[color=#a4885c]Your role:[/color] Standard soldier. Enforce NCR authority, protect personnel and assets, and carry out orders.
</Box>

<br/>

<ColorBox Color="#fbc02d">
  <Box Margin="2">
  [bold]Recruit[/bold]
  </Box>
</ColorBox>
<Box>
[color=#a4885c]Your role:[/color] Newest enlistee. You are at the bottom of a very long ladder. Follow orders, learn the ropes, and avoid getting yourself or your squadmates killed.
</Box>

<hr/>

## New California Republic Rangers (NCRR)

<p>The Rangers — originally descended from Pre-War Rangers — are the elite soldiers of the NCR. They are a volunteer special forces renowned for survival, reconnaissance, scouting, sabotage, and martial arts. Their primary purpose is dealing with threats the regular forces cannot handle.</p>

<p>The Rangers are the living image of NCR ideals of liberty, justice, and freedom from tyrants, slavers, and raiders. To break their bond to the Ranger Code is to fail the NCR and their people.</p>

<p>[bold]Command Structure:[/bold] Rangers are loosely based around the typical NCR command structure. A Ranger holds the rank equivalent of a Sergeant; a Veteran Ranger holds the rank equivalent of an Officer. They can give orders to the NCRA if no NCRA command is available. The Rangers are expected to follow their own command, but can receive orders from NCRA command if no Ranger command is present.</p>

<hr/>

## Crime and Punishment

<p>Punishment in the NCR is divided between Non-Judicial and Judicial Punishment.</p>

[bold]Non-Judicial Punishment (NJP):[/bold] For less severe offenses. Given by NCOs and Officers in the field.
<ul>
<li>Reprimand</li>
<li>Forfeiture of Pay</li>
<li>Extra Duty</li>
<li>Diminished Rations</li>
<li>Confinement to Base or Brig</li>
<li>Loss of Rank (requires Captain or higher approval)</li>
</ul>

[bold]Judicial Punishment (JP):[/bold] Determined after court martial for major or capital offenses.
<ul>
<li>Other Than Honorable Discharge</li>
<li>Dishonorable Discharge</li>
<li>Execution via Firing Squad or Hanging</li>
<li>Barred from Reenlistment</li>
</ul>

<p>[bold]Court Martial:[/bold] Requested by high-ranking members and/or the Military Police. Handles serious crimes between NCRA and NCRR. Non-civilians may be sentenced to Court Martial in extreme cases.</p>

<hr/>

## List of Offenses

<p>Offenses are categorized as:</p>
<ul>
<li>[bold]MR:[/bold] Minor Offense (NJP required)</li>
<li>[bold]MO:[/bold] Major Offense (Judicial Punishment required)</li>
<li>[bold]CO:[/bold] Capital Offense (more severe than MO)</li>
</ul>

[bold]Minor Offenses (MR):[/bold]
<ul>
<li>Assault, Verbal — 5 min brig</li>
<li>Hooliganism (loud yelling, throwing garbage, breaking windows) — 5 min brig</li>
<li>Insubordination with Minor Consequences — 10 min brig</li>
<li>Failure of Proper Conduct (poor grooming, improper uniform, friendly fire) — situational 5–10 min</li>
<li>Neglect of Duty — loss of rank, 10 min brig</li>
<li>Substance Abuse (legal substances) — NJP 10 min</li>
<li>Absence Without Leave (AWOL) — situational 10–20 min</li>
</ul>

[bold]Major Offenses (MO):[/bold]
<ul>
<li>Fraternization (between enlisted/NCO and CO) — dismissal or loss of rank</li>
<li>Manslaughter — dismissal or loss of rank</li>
<li>Abandonment of Duty — loss of rank</li>
<li>Assaulting or Disobeying an Officer — dismissal or loss of rank</li>
<li>Sedition — dismissal or loss of rank</li>
<li>Desertion — execution or life imprisonment</li>
<li>Fraternization with Enemy — execution or life imprisonment</li>
<li>Drug Trafficking (illegal substances, e.g. Jet, Psycho) — demotion, can escalate to CO</li>
</ul>

[bold]Capital Offenses (CO):[/bold]
<ul>
<li>Use of Mercenaries — execution or life imprisonment</li>
<li>Treason — execution or life imprisonment</li>
<li>Murder — execution or life imprisonment</li>
<li>Sabotage — execution or life imprisonment</li>
<li>Cannibalism — execution or life imprisonment</li>
</ul>

<p>[color=#a4885c]Modifiers:[/color] Aggravating factors make punishment harsher (e.g. repeating the same offense, refusing to cooperate). Mitigating factors make punishment less harsh (e.g. surrendering, cooperating).</p>

<hr/>

## Dress Code

<p>All on-duty personnel are expected to be in full uniform during all NCR operations and may not change or remove uniform without authorization of an NCO or CO.</p>

<p>Cadets do not have the possibility of modifying their issued loadout. Upon reaching NCO rank, soldiers are permitted to use non-NCR apparel such as cowboy hats or bandanas.</p>

<p>[bold]Hair Regulations:[/bold] Hair must be well-groomed with a natural color. Bright and exotic dyes are prohibited. Hair must fit underneath a helmet.</p>

<p>[bold]Weapon Regulations:[/bold] Low-ranking troopers such as Cadets will mainly use weapons issued at the start of the shift and are not allowed to change them unless authorized by a superior. Weapons manufactured by other factions are strictly forbidden and will be held in the armory until repurposed. High-quality weapons are held in the armory and distributed by logistics to where they are needed.</p>

<hr/>

## Criminals and Prisoners of War

<p>[bold]Criminals[/bold] are individuals not part of any organization who have broken NCR laws, committed crimes against NCR citizens or personnel, or intentionally undermined NCR operations. Criminals are protected under NCR laws and must be treated humanely, provided with basic necessities (food, clothing, shelter). They may not be abused or harmed while in captivity and non-resisting.</p>

<p>[bold]Prisoners of War (POWs)[/bold] are individuals who are part of an organization or faction currently at war with the NCR. POWs are protected under NCR laws and must be treated humanely. They are not to be used for tactical purposes, nor traded, exchanged, or released without High Command authorization. Anyone releasing a POW without authorization is to be charged with Sedition or Treason.</p>
</Document>
