<Document>
# Followers of the Apocalypse

[textlink="View Full Wiki Page" link="https://ss14.misfitsystems.net/wiki/index.php/Followers_of_the_Apocalypse"]

<Table Columns="2">
  <Box>[bold]Status[/bold]</Box>
  <Box>Active — Humanitarian organization</Box>
  <Box>[bold]Location[/bold]</Box>
  <Box>Mobile clinics near Wendover</Box>
  <Box>[bold]Leadership[/bold]</Box>
  <Box>Followers Doctor (senior)</Box>
  <Box>[bold]Ideology[/bold]</Box>
  <Box>Knowledge, medicine, education for all</Box>
  <Box>[bold]Motto[/bold]</Box>
  <Box>[italic]"Knowledge. Medicine. For everyone."[/italic]</Box>
</Table>

<hr/>

<p>The Followers of the Apocalypse were founded in the ruins of the Los Angeles Public Library — a group that believed knowledge, medicine, and education were more powerful tools for rebuilding civilization than any weapon or army. They have grown into one of the most respected organizations in the post-war West, running free clinics, teaching the illiterate, and maintaining one of the largest accessible archives of pre-war knowledge.</p>

<p>They are non-violent. They are non-aligned. And they will help anyone.</p>

<hr/>

## Philosophy

<ColorBox Color="#1a1a1a" OutlineColor="#33a1c1" OutlineThickness="1" Margin="5">
  <Box Orientation="Vertical" Margin="8">
    [italic]"The old world ended because people chose power over people. Our answer is to refuse that choice entirely."[/italic]
  </Box>
</ColorBox>

<p>The Followers believe the old world ended because people chose power over people. Their answer is to refuse that choice entirely. They document so mistakes are not forgotten. They educate so the cycle of ignorance cannot repeat. They treat the sick because suffering is not a political variable.</p>

<hr/>

## Roles

<ColorBox Color="#33a1c1">
  <Box Margin="2">
  [bold]Followers Doctor[/bold]
  </Box>
</ColorBox>
<Box>
[italic]In the Fallout universe:[/italic] Followers physicians are among the most trusted individuals across all faction lines — providing free or low-cost medical care to anyone, regardless of alignment. Figures like Dr. Usanagi of the New Vegas Medical Clinic or the Followers staff in Freeside demonstrate how powerful a reputation for healing can be even in a world that runs on violence. Their neutrality is not weakness — it is their access pass to places soldiers cannot go.

[color=#a4885c]Your role:[/color] Provide medical care to anyone who needs it. Your neutrality and your skills make you welcome almost anywhere. You will be tested by factions who want your resources turned toward their cause — hold your principles.
</Box>

<br/>

<ColorBox Color="#33a1c1">
  <Box Margin="2">
  [bold]Followers Scholar[/bold]
  </Box>
</ColorBox>
<Box>
[italic]In the Fallout universe:[/italic] Scholars are the Followers' archivists and educators — people who believe that the greatest gift the old world left behind is its knowledge, and the greatest tragedy is how much has been lost. In Fallout: New Vegas, Followers scholars document everything: history, biology, culture. Their records are genuinely valuable to civilizations trying to rebuild without repeating history.

[color=#a4885c]Your role:[/color] Record what happens and why. Teach anyone willing to learn. Collect pre-war documents and technical knowledge. The events of a single round may matter to generations — document them accordingly.
</Box>

<br/>

<ColorBox Color="#33a1c1">
  <Box Margin="2">
  [bold]Followers Aid Worker[/bold]
  </Box>
</ColorBox>
<Box>
[italic]In the Fallout universe:[/italic] Aid workers are the Followers' front-line humanitarian presence — the first to arrive in a crisis and the last to leave. They go where the need is greatest without asking what faction you belong to. In Fallout's world, they are often the only representative of organized compassion that ordinary people in dangerous regions will ever encounter.

[color=#a4885c]Your role:[/color] Assist in crisis situations. Distribute food, water, and basic medical supplies to those in need. You are the human face of the Followers' mission — how you conduct yourself in the field is the organization's reputation.
</Box>

<hr/>

## Faction Relations

<p>The Followers are welcomed by most factions as neutral common ground. They serve as natural mediators in conflict and provide critical support during crises. Their strict non-violence principle is both their most respected quality and their most frequently exploited vulnerability.</p>
</Document>
