<Document>
# Caesar's Legion

[textlink="View Full Wiki Page" link="https://ss14.misfitsystems.net/wiki/index.php/Caesar%27s_Legion"]

<Table Columns="2">
  <p>[bold]Status[/bold]</p>  <p>[color=#4caf50]Active — Major Faction[/color]</p>
  <p>[bold]Base[/bold]</p>  <p>Salt Column Camp, Bonneville Salt Flats</p>
  <p>[bold]Leadership[/bold]</p>  <p>Legate Ferro Maro (Salt Column)</p>
  <p>[bold]Ideology[/bold]</p>  <p>Neo-Roman Imperialism, Martial Discipline</p>
  <p>[bold]Motto[/bold]</p>  <p>[italic]"Ave, true to Caesar"[/italic]</p>
</Table>

<p>Caesar's Legion stands as a force of absolute order, forged from the conquest and assimilation of over eighty-six tribes across the former American Southwest. Built on the doctrines of Caesar himself, the Legion rejects the degeneracy of the Old World and the weakness of those who cling to its remnants. Caesar is dead. The fire that forged the Legion has gone out, and what survives the cooling will prove whether the work was real.</p>

<p>The Legion's presence in this region belongs to the [bold]Salt Column[/bold], commanded by [bold]Legate Ferro Maro[/bold]. They have held the Bonneville Salt Flats for three years. They will continue to hold it.</p>

<hr/>

## History and Current Affairs

<p>[bold]The Death of Caesar:[/bold] Caesar is gone. What he left behind is not grief but a question: what was built here, and does it stand without him? The Legion was designed to outlast its founder. Whether it does so depends entirely on the character of those who remain.</p>

<p>[bold]The Claim of Lacerta:[/bold] Before his death, Caesar named no successor publicly. A man named Lacerta moved the moment Caesar fell. He destroyed the record of succession. He killed the witness. He put on the Laurels. These are not the actions of a man who was named. A man who was named has no reason to do any of that. Lacerta is a pretender.</p>

<p>[bold]The Pactum Ferri:[/bold] Two columns have aligned against Lacerta's advance. The [bold]Salt Column[/bold], under Legate Ferro Maro, has held the Bonneville Salt Flats for three years. Ferro Maro is a man of arithmetic — Lacerta's character is settled, his trajectory is known, and Ferro Maro intends to stop him. The [bold]Cinder Cohort[/bold] marches under Legate Verus Caldius. Where Ferro Maro is measured, Caldius is deliberate in a different way — he intends to make the cost of every mile felt, bleeding the pretender's column pass by pass until doubt spreads like rot through timber. Together these two columns form the [bold]Pactum Ferri[/bold], sometimes called Legio Vera. They are not rebels. They are the Legion.</p>

<p>[bold]The Salt Column's Position:[/bold] The Salt Column holds Wendover and the Bonneville Salt Flats, anchored along the I-80 corridor at the Utah-Nevada line. The flats offer no cover, no comfort, and no room for self-deception. This position commands the approach from the west. Lacerta's eventual advance from New Vegas runs through this ground. The Salt Column intends to be standing on it when he arrives.</p>

<ColorBox Color="#1a1a1a" OutlineColor="#8B0000" OutlineThickness="1" Margin="5">
  <Box Orientation="Vertical" Margin="8">
    [italic]"The Salt Column has held this ground in conditions that would have broken a lesser force. We will continue to hold it. Ave. — Legate Ferro Maro, Salt Column, Caesar's Legion"[/italic]
  </Box>
</ColorBox>

<hr/>

## The Code of the Legion

<p>Every Legionary, from the freshest Recruit to the Centurion himself, is bound by the will of Caesar. These are not suggestions. They are the sinew that holds the Legion together.</p>

<ul>
<li>Obey the orders of your superiors without question or delay</li>
<li>Wear your uniform and bear your arms as a servant of Caesar. You are his face in the wastes</li>
<li>Never kill a fellow servant of Caesar without just cause. Disputes of honor are settled through the duel</li>
<li>Do not rely on the crutches of the Old World. Stimpaks, advanced chems, and the armor of tyrants weaken the body and corrupt the spirit</li>
<li>Take no chems, alcohol, or narcotics. Acceptable remedies are those derived from the land</li>
<li>Prisoners taken in the field are a resource. Deal with them with creativity and purpose. Should they resist, lethal force is permitted</li>
<li>Cannibalism is a taboo and is not to be discussed openly</li>
<li>The Legion does not attack those without cause</li>
<li>Technology captured in the field may be used at the Centurion's discretion. Radios, night-vision, and illumination tools are acceptable. Power armor, cyborg units, and medical beam weapons are not</li>
</ul>

<hr/>

## Command Structure

<p>The Legion operates through an unbroken chain of command. Authority flows downward. Obedience flows upward. There is no middle ground.</p>

<hr/>

## Command

<ColorBox Color="#8B0000">
  <Box Margin="2">
  [bold]Legate[/bold]
  </Box>
</ColorBox>
<Box>
[color=#a4885c]Your role:[/color] Command all Legion military operations in the Wendover region. Strategic decisions — troop movements, alliances, subjugation or destruction of opposing factions — are yours to make. Caesar's will is expressed through you. Act accordingly. The Legate speaks with Caesar's voice.
</Box>

<br/>

<ColorBox Color="#8B0000">
  <Box Margin="2">
  [bold]Centurion[/bold]
  </Box>
</ColorBox>
<Box>
[color=#a4885c]Your role:[/color] Lead combat operations. Execute the Legate's strategy in the field and commands the camp in full. His word is law within it, superseded only by the Legate. Direct Decani, and deal with any tactical situation that arises. You are the Legion's instrument of force in any direct engagement.
</Box>

<br/>

<ColorBox Color="#8B0000">
  <Box Margin="2">
  [bold]Veteran Decanus[/bold]
  </Box>
</ColorBox>
<Box>
[color=#a4885c]Your role:[/color] A senior officer of the Legion. Lead your contubernium with authority and experience. Commands Veterans, Primes, and Legionaries in the field; answers directly to the Centurion and above. Your experience is a resource — use it.
</Box>

<br/>

<ColorBox Color="#8B0000">
  <Box Margin="2">
  [bold]Prime Decanus[/bold]
  </Box>
</ColorBox>
<Box>
[color=#a4885c]Your role:[/color] An officer commanding Prime Legionaries and below. Command your squad in the field. Carry out orders from Centurion and Veteran Decani without question. Demonstrate the judgment that earns the trust of those above you.
</Box>

<br/>

<ColorBox Color="#8B0000">
  <Box Margin="2">
  [bold]Recruit Decanus[/bold]
  </Box>
</ColorBox>
<Box>
[color=#a4885c]Your role:[/color] The junior officer of the Legion, responsible for managing and shaping newly inducted Legionaries. Answers to Prime and Veteran Decani, the Centurion, and those above. Lead a contubernium and carry out the orders of your superiors without hesitation.
</Box>

<hr/>

## Line Ranks

<ColorBox Color="#8B0000">
  <Box Margin="2">
  [bold]Veteran Legionnaire[/bold]
  </Box>
</ColorBox>
<Box>
[color=#a4885c]Your role:[/color] A hardened and experienced Legionary, proven in battle. Fight, survive, and serve as the example your younger brothers are measured against. Serves the Decani, the Centurion, and those above. Veterans are expected to set an example for those beneath them.
</Box>

<br/>

<ColorBox Color="#8B0000">
  <Box Margin="2">
  [bold]Prime Legionnaire[/bold]
  </Box>
</ColorBox>
<Box>
[color=#a4885c]Your role:[/color] A capable, seasoned Legionary who has demonstrated their worth to the Legion. Execute orders. Fight as directed. Protect your brothers and represent the Legion in every action you take. Ave, true to Caesar.
</Box>

<br/>

<ColorBox Color="#8B0000">
  <Box Margin="2">
  [bold]Legionnaire[/bold]
  </Box>
</ColorBox>
<Box>
[color=#a4885c]Your role:[/color] A Legionary of the rank and file. Follows the orders of all Decani, the Centurion, and those above. Expected to conduct yourself with discipline at all times.
</Box>

<hr/>

## Special Roles

<ColorBox Color="#8B0000">
  <Box Margin="2">
  [bold]Explorer (Venator)[/bold]
  </Box>
</ColorBox>
<Box>
[color=#a4885c]Your role:[/color] Scout the region. Gather intelligence on other factions, track persons of interest, and feed operational information back to the Centurion. Explorers operate with more autonomy than line Legionaries, ranging ahead of the main force to assess threats. You work alone or in pairs — that is by design.
</Box>

<br/>

<ColorBox Color="#8B0000">
  <Box Margin="2">
  [bold]Frumentarii[/bold]
  </Box>
</ColorBox>
<Box>
[color=#a4885c]Your role:[/color] Agents of intelligence and infiltration. Operate in the shadows. Infiltrate, observe, and report. Gather information, sow discord among the Legion's enemies, and eliminate high-value targets when ordered. They answer to the Centurion and are not bound by the visible rank structure in the execution of their duties. The Frumentarii do not exist — and that is the point.
</Box>

<br/>

<ColorBox Color="#8B0000">
  <Box Margin="2">
  [bold]Houndmaster[/bold]
  </Box>
</ColorBox>
<Box>
[color=#a4885c]Your role:[/color] Responsible for the Legion's war dogs and their deployment in battle and scouting. The Houndmaster operates as a specialist within the camp, answering to the Centurion. His animals are assets of the Legion and are to be treated as such. Care for and deploy your hounds in service of the Legion — tracking fugitives, patrolling the perimeter, or leading the charge.
</Box>

<br/>

<ColorBox Color="#8B0000">
  <Box Margin="2">
  [bold]Vexillarius[/bold]
  </Box>
</ColorBox>
<Box>
[color=#a4885c]Your role:[/color] Carry the Legion's standard and serve as its visible heart in the field. Rally your brothers, maintain cohesion under fire, and protect the standard at all costs. Where you stand, the Legion stands.
</Box>

<br/>

<ColorBox Color="#8B0000">
  <Box Margin="2">
  [bold]Orator[/bold]
  </Box>
</ColorBox>
<Box>
[color=#a4885c]Your role:[/color] Speak for the Legion. Deal with non-Legion parties, broadcast Caesar's ideology, and manage the faction's reputation with communities that can be brought into compliance without force. You are the edge of the sword that doesn't cut.
</Box>

<hr/>

## Camp Roles

<ColorBox Color="#8B0000">
  <Box Margin="2">
  [bold]Auxilia[/bold]
  </Box>
</ColorBox>
<Box>
[color=#a4885c]Your role:[/color] Women who provide essential functions within the camp. Respected members of the Legion's support structure. Non-combative. Not placed above Legionaries in matters of discipline; disrespect toward a Legionary will not go unaddressed.
</Box>

<br/>

<ColorBox Color="#8B0000">
  <Box Margin="2">
  [bold]Recruit[/bold]
  </Box>
</ColorBox>
<Box>
[color=#a4885c]Your role:[/color] You are at the bottom. Follow every order. Do not question above your station. Every great Centurion started where you are standing.
</Box>

<br/>

<ColorBox Color="#8B0000">
  <Box Margin="2">
  [bold]Slave[/bold]
  </Box>
</ColorBox>
<Box>
[color=#a4885c]Your role:[/color] The lowest station within the camp. Slaves serve all above them without exception and are marked by collar and tattoo. Put to work in farming, cooking, mining, crafting, and healing. Failure to work or disrespect toward Legionaries will result in punishment, up to and including death by crucifixion. Slaves who labor faithfully are protected, fed, and housed; those who prove loyal enough may in time find themselves elevated to a higher station within the camp.
</Box>

<hr/>

## Medical Provisions

<p>The Legion rejects the chemical degeneracy of the Old World. The body is a weapon; to poison it with manufactured substances is to dishonor Caesar.</p>

<p>[bold]Permitted:[/bold] Healing Powder / Poultice, Regenerative Mesh, Mourning Poultice, Ephedra (Ephi), Charcoal, Saline Glucose, Mannitol / Neurine, RadAway (extreme radiation exposure only).</p>

<p>[bold]Forbidden:[/bold] Morphine, Rad-X, Stimpaks, Brute/Burn Patches, Med-X, Jet, Buffout, Psycho, Alcohol.</p>

<p>[italic]Note: RadAway is found naturally in Punga. Use only when a Legionary faces severe radiation exposure. Bagged sources found in the field are acceptable.[/italic]</p>

<hr/>

## Prisoners and Slaves

<p>[bold]Prisoners:[/bold] Those taken captive in the field are a resource to be managed with intelligence and purpose, not simply disposed of. A prisoner may serve as leverage, labor, a source of information, or a candidate for eventual service. Crucifixion is available as a sentence, but it is not the default answer to every capture. Officers are expected to exercise judgment. Prisoners who resist captivity or make attempts to escape may be killed. Those who cooperate are to be processed and their disposition determined by the Centurion or ranking officer.</p>

<p>[bold]Slaves:[/bold] Slaves within the camp serve at the pleasure of Caesar's Legion and are under the protection of its members, provided they conduct themselves with obedience and humility. They are not to be abused arbitrarily; the Legion requires their labor and cooperation. However, insubordination, refusal to work, or disrespect toward Legionaries will be met with appropriate consequences.</p>
</Document>
