<Document>
# Vault Dwellers

[textlink="View Full Wiki Page" link="https://ss14.misfitsystems.net/wiki/index.php/Vault_Dwellers"]

<Table Columns="2">
  <Box>[bold]Status[/bold]</Box>
  <Box>Active — Sealed community</Box>
  <Box>[bold]Location[/bold]</Box>
  <Box>The Vault (near Wendover)</Box>
  <Box>[bold]Leadership[/bold]</Box>
  <Box>Overseer</Box>
  <Box>[bold]Ideology[/bold]</Box>
  <Box>Preservation, protocol, survival</Box>
  <Box>[bold]Motto[/bold]</Box>
  <Box>[italic]"Prepare for the Future."[/italic]</Box>
</Table>

<hr/>

## Core Mission

<ColorBox Color="#1a1a1a" OutlineColor="#0d47a1" OutlineThickness="1" Margin="5">
  <Box Orientation="Vertical" Margin="8">
    [italic]"To maintain optimal operational efficiency, preserve pure human genetics, and strictly execute all directives handed down by 'Management' to prepare for the eventual reclamation of the surface."[/italic]
  </Box>
</ColorBox>

<hr/>

## Roles

<ColorBox Color="#0d47a1">
  <Box Margin="2">
  [bold]Overseer[/bold]
  </Box>
</ColorBox>
<Box>
[color=#a4885c]Your role:[/color] Administer the vault. You know something the others may not — the vault's true purpose, if one exists. Decide whether to shield your people from that knowledge or lead them through it. If the door opens, you determine how your community meets the surface world.
</Box>

<br/>

<ColorBox Color="#0d47a1">
  <Box Margin="2">
  [bold]Vault Security[/bold]
  </Box>
</ColorBox>
<Box>
[color=#a4885c]Your role:[/color] Maintain order inside the vault and protect it if the door opens. You enforce the Overseer's authority. How you use that authority — with justice or with fear — shapes what the vault becomes.
</Box>

<br/>

<ColorBox Color="#0d47a1">
  <Box Margin="2">
  [bold]Vault Scientist[/bold]
  </Box>
</ColorBox>
<Box>
[color=#a4885c]Your role:[/color] Keep vault systems running, conduct research, and provide medical care. You may hold critical information about the vault's experiment — and that knowledge could save or destroy your community depending on what you choose to do with it.
</Box>

<br/>

<ColorBox Color="#0d47a1">
  <Box Margin="2">
  [bold]Vault Dweller[/bold]
  </Box>
</ColorBox>
<Box>
[color=#a4885c]Your role:[/color] Live vault life. Follow protocols, contribute to community work, and try to make sense of what is happening. If the door opens, every assumption you have about the world will be tested — starting immediately.
</Box>

<hr/>

## The Vault

<p>Vault-Tec vaults were marketed as survival shelters — underground bunkers built to preserve humanity through nuclear war. In reality, many vaults were designed as controlled experiments. The inhabitants did not know what they had signed up for. Some vaults tested social dynamics, others tested biological limits, and the unlucky ones tested both.</p>

<p>Whether this vault has a hidden purpose is something the Overseer may — or may not — choose to reveal.</p>

<hr/>

## Faction Relations

<Table Columns="3">
  <Box>[bold][color=#a4885c]Faction[/color][/bold]</Box>
  <Box>[bold][color=#a4885c]Standing[/color][/bold]</Box>
  <Box>[bold][color=#a4885c]Notes[/color][/bold]</Box>
  <Box>NCR</Box>
  <Box>[color=#a4885c]Cautious[/color]</Box>
  <Box>Views vault technology with interest. May attempt annexation.</Box>
  <Box>Brotherhood of Steel</Box>
  <Box>[color=#ffb000]Suspicious[/color]</Box>
  <Box>Wants vault technology. May attempt a "safety audit."</Box>
  <Box>Caesar's Legion</Box>
  <Box>[color=#cc3333]Hostile[/color]</Box>
  <Box>Views vault dwellers as soft targets for enslavement.</Box>
  <Box>Townsfolk</Box>
  <Box>[color=#6bba5e]Friendly[/color]</Box>
  <Box>Trade partners when the door opens. Vault tech is valuable.</Box>
  <Box>Wastelanders</Box>
  <Box>[color=#a4885c]Curious[/color]</Box>
  <Box>Vault dwellers are novelties on the surface — sheltered but resourceful.</Box>
  <Box>Followers of the Apocalypse</Box>
  <Box>[color=#6bba5e]Friendly[/color]</Box>
  <Box>Values vault records and scientific knowledge.</Box>
</Table>
</Document>
