<Document>
# Children of Atom

[textlink="View Full Wiki Page" link="https://ss14.misfitsystems.net/wiki/index.php/Children_of_Atom"]

<Table Columns="2">
  <Box>[bold]Status[/bold]</Box>
  <Box>Active — Religious cult</Box>
  <Box>[bold]Location[/bold]</Box>
  <Box>Irradiated sites near Wendover</Box>
  <Box>[bold]Leadership[/bold]</Box>
  <Box>High Confessor</Box>
  <Box>[bold]Ideology[/bold]</Box>
  <Box>Worship of atomic fission as divine creation</Box>
  <Box>[bold]Motto[/bold]</Box>
  <Box>[italic]"Bask in the Glow of Atom."[/italic]</Box>
</Table>

<hr/>

<p>The Children of Atom are a post-war religious cult founded around the worship of atomic fission — specifically the chain reaction they call "Atom." To them, when the atom splits, it does not destroy: it multiplies. Every soul divided by the Bomb became many souls. The Great War was not genocide. It was divine creation on a cosmic scale.</p>

<p>Present throughout the Wasteland from the Capital to the Commonwealth's Far Harbor, the Children are fervent, armed, and prepared to martyr themselves without hesitation.</p>

<hr/>

## Philosophy

<ColorBox Color="#1a1a1a" OutlineColor="#558b2f" OutlineThickness="1" Margin="5">
  <Box Orientation="Vertical" Margin="8">
    [italic]"Radiation is God's light made manifest. To cleanse it is sacrilege. To embrace it is salvation."[/italic]
  </Box>
</ColorBox>

<p>Children of Atom believe radiation is a sacred gift — the literal Glow of their god manifesting in irradiated flesh. They view RadAway and radiation treatment as sacrilege. Those blessed with radiation resistance or ghoulification are considered touched by Atom himself. Their theology transforms what kills most people into a mark of divine favor — giving them a framework for fearlessness that makes them genuinely dangerous.</p>

<hr/>

## Roles

<ColorBox Color="#558b2f">
  <Box Margin="2">
  [bold]High Confessor[/bold]
  </Box>
</ColorBox>
<Box>
[italic]In the Fallout universe:[/italic] The High Confessor is the spiritual and operational commander of a Children of Atom congregation. Notable High Confessors include Martin Paintner of the Capital Wasteland and Tektus of Far Harbor — figures who combine genuine religious authority with tactical command over devoted followers. Their word is doctrine, and their followers treat it accordingly.

[color=#a4885c]Your role:[/color] Lead the congregation. Interpret Atom's will. Direct the cult's activities and relationships with other factions. When you speak with conviction, your people follow without hesitation — use that power carefully.
</Box>

<br/>

<ColorBox Color="#558b2f">
  <Box Margin="2">
  [bold]Confessor[/bold]
  </Box>
</ColorBox>
<Box>
[italic]In the Fallout universe:[/italic] Confessors are senior religious authorities — responsible for ministering to the congregation, conducting rituals, and maintaining doctrinal purity. They handle day-to-day spiritual functions and serve as the bridge between the High Confessor's leadership and ordinary Disciples.

[color=#a4885c]Your role:[/color] Support the High Confessor, conduct worship, and ensure the congregation stays focused on Atom's mission. You are the link between doctrine and the people who live by it.
</Box>

<br/>

<ColorBox Color="#558b2f">
  <Box Margin="2">
  [bold]Disciple[/bold]
  </Box>
</ColorBox>
<Box>
[italic]In the Fallout universe:[/italic] Disciples are fully initiated members of the Children of Atom — believers who have proven their faith and are willing to fight or die for it. In Fallout, Disciples often carry irradiated weapons or wear minimal armor as a deliberate demonstration of their trust in Atom's protection. Their willingness to absorb punishment that would stop most fighters makes them unpredictable in combat.

[color=#a4885c]Your role:[/color] Serve Atom and the High Confessor. Spread the Glow. Protect the congregation. Your faith is your armor — and the source of every action you take.
</Box>

<hr/>

## Faction Relations

<p>The Children of Atom are deeply hostile to any faction that uses RadAway or works to reduce radiation exposure. They may cooperate narrowly with groups that respect their religious autonomy, but their ultimate loyalty is to Atom — and they will act on that loyalty when tested.</p>
</Document>
