<Document>
# Big Guns

[textlink="View Full Wiki Page" link="https://ss14.misfitsystems.net/wiki/index.php/Big_Guns"]

<p>Big Guns are heavy weapons that deal devastating damage. They are difficult to carry and expensive to feed, but nothing matches their raw stopping power once a fight turns serious.</p>

<hr/>

## Miniguns

<p>Miniguns deliver overwhelming volume of fire and are best used for suppression, defense, and faction-level fire superiority.</p>

<ul>
<li>[bold]Minigun[/bold] — Standard rotary-barrel machine gun. Enormous ammo consumption but unmatched sustained fire.</li>
<li>[bold]Avenger Minigun[/bold] — Military-upgraded minigun with a higher rate of fire and improved accuracy.</li>
</ul>

<hr/>

## Launchers

<p>Grenade and missile launchers are area-denial weapons that break fortified positions and punish clustered enemies.</p>

<ul>
<li>[bold]Grenade Launcher[/bold] — Fires explosive grenades in an arc. Effective against groups and behind cover.</li>
<li>[bold]Missile Launcher[/bold] — Shoulder-fired guided missile platform. Devastating but expensive to reload.</li>
<li>[bold]Rifle Grenade[/bold] — Grenade attachment fired from a rifle. Lower yield but more portable.</li>
</ul>

<hr/>

## Light Machine Guns

<p>LMGs provide sustained automatic fire and excel in prepared positions or coordinated squad fights.</p>

<ul>
<li>[bold]Light Machine Gun[/bold] — Belt-fed automatic weapon. Best used from a stationary or braced position.</li>
<li>[bold]Automatic Rifle[/bold] — Magazine-fed support weapon. Lighter than a proper LMG and easier to reposition.</li>
</ul>

<hr/>

## Flamers

<p>The flamer projects burning fuel across a wide area and is especially effective against creatures and lightly armored targets.</p>

<ul>
<li>[bold]Flamer[/bold] — Short-range incendiary weapon. Area denial and crowd control in one package.</li>
</ul>

<ColorBox Color="#3a0000" OutlineColor="#f44336" OutlineThickness="1" Margin="5">
  <Box Orientation="Vertical" Margin="8">
    [bold][color=red]Warning:[/color][/bold] Big Guns are usually restricted to military-grade factions. Carrying one openly is enough to attract attention almost anywhere in the Wasteland.
  </Box>
</ColorBox>
</Document>
