<Document>
# Organ Manipulation

[textlink="View Full Wiki Page" link="https://ss14.misfitsystems.net/wiki/index.php/Surgery"]

<p>Organ manipulation surgeries allow you to remove, transplant, or replace internal organs. Replacing a damaged or missing organ can resolve conditions that no amount of surface treatment will fix.</p>

<hr/>

## Standard Anatomy

<p>A typical human body contains the following organs:</p>

<ul>
<li>[bold]Brain[/bold]</li>
<li>[bold]Eyes[/bold]</li>
<li>[bold]Heart[/bold]</li>
<li>[bold]Kidneys[/bold]</li>
<li>[bold]Liver[/bold]</li>
<li>[bold]Lungs[/bold]</li>
<li>[bold]Stomach[/bold]</li>
</ul>

<p>Some species have additional or combined organs. The above list covers the standard human baseline.</p>

<hr/>

## Removing and Transplanting Organs

<p>To [bold]remove[/bold] an organ, apply the corresponding Organ Removal surgery to the target body part. The organ will be extracted without harming the patient.</p>

<p>To [bold]transplant[/bold] a replacement organ, apply the corresponding Organ Transplant surgery to the same site where the original organ was located.</p>

<hr/>

## Transplant Effects

<ul>
<li>Transplanting a [color=#a4885c]brain[/color] — transfers the patient's consciousness to a new body.</li>
<li>Transplanting a [color=#a4885c]liver[/color] — cures severe poisoning.</li>
<li>Transplanting [color=#a4885c]lungs[/color] — treats severe asphyxiation.</li>
<li>Transplanting a [color=#a4885c]heart[/color] — cures rot and organ decay.</li>
<li>Transplanting [color=#a4885c]eyes[/color] — restores vision and heals eye damage.</li>
</ul>

<hr/>

## Sourcing Organs

<p>When a patient needs a replacement organ, their original is usually missing or too damaged to reuse. New organs can be manufactured using a [bold]Medical Biofabricator[/bold] with [bold]Biomass[/bold]. The biofabricator can produce biosynthetic organs for all species.</p>

<p>Every Chief Medical Officer has access to a Medical Biofabricator board in their starting equipment.</p>

<hr/>

## Organ Rejection

<p>If an organ transplant has no effect, the patient's body has rejected it. This usually means the organ is in poor condition. Use a fresh organ from a donor or manufacture a new one using the Medical Biofabricator.</p>

</Document>
