<Document>
# Caravan Company

[textlink="View Full Wiki Page" link="https://ss14.misfitsystems.net/wiki/index.php/Caravan_Company"]

<Table Columns="2">
  <Box>[bold]Status[/bold]</Box>
  <Box>Active — Trade organization</Box>
  <Box>[bold]Location[/bold]</Box>
  <Box>Trade routes through Wendover region</Box>
  <Box>[bold]Leadership[/bold]</Box>
  <Box>Caravan Master</Box>
  <Box>[bold]Ideology[/bold]</Box>
  <Box>Profit, pragmatism, mutual benefit</Box>
  <Box>[bold]Motto[/bold]</Box>
  <Box>[italic]"Everyone needs us. That is our leverage."[/italic]</Box>
</Table>

<hr/>

<p>Trade caravans are among the most essential institutions in the Fallout universe — the lifelines connecting isolated settlements, carrying news alongside goods, and preventing the Wasteland's fragile economy from collapsing into pure subsistence. From the Crimson Caravan to the Far Go Traders, every major post-war civilization depends on traders willing to brave dangerous roads.</p>

<p>The Caravan Company is the primary source of goods and supplies flowing into this region. Without their routes, settlements stagnate or starve. Everyone needs them — which means everyone has leverage over them, and they know how to use leverage in return.</p>

<hr/>

## Philosophy

<ColorBox Color="#1a1a1a" OutlineColor="#a1887f" OutlineThickness="1" Margin="5">
  <Box Orientation="Vertical" Margin="8">
    [italic]"We sell to anyone who can pay. That is not a weakness — it is our survival strategy."[/italic]
  </Box>
</ColorBox>

<p>The Caravan Company operates on profit and mutual benefit above any ideology. They sell to anyone who can pay. This pragmatism makes them valuable neutral parties — and frustrating ones when choosing sides is exactly what a situation demands.</p>

<hr/>

## Roles

<ColorBox Color="#a1887f">
  <Box Margin="2">
  [bold]Caravan Master[/bold]
  </Box>
</ColorBox>
<Box>
[color=#a4885c]Your role:[/color] Oversee the local CC operation. Manage inventory, coordinate traders, protect assets, and maintain relationships with every faction simultaneously. When the Caravan Company suffers, the whole region suffers — including your bottom line.
</Box>

<br/>

<ColorBox Color="#a1887f">
  <Box Margin="2">
  [bold]Merchant[/bold]
  </Box>
</ColorBox>
<Box>
[color=#a4885c]Your role:[/color] Buy, sell, and trade. The regional economy runs through your hands. Your relationships with customers — fair dealing or otherwise — define the Caravan Company's reputation in every settlement you reach.
</Box>

<br/>

<ColorBox Color="#a1887f">
  <Box Margin="2">
  [bold]Caravan Guard[/bold]
  </Box>
</ColorBox>
<Box>
[color=#a4885c]Your role:[/color] Protect the caravan, its personnel, and its inventory. You are not looking for a fight — but if trouble finds your employer, you are the reason it does not end badly for them.
</Box>

<hr/>

## Faction Relations

<Table Columns="3">
  <Box>[bold][color=#a4885c]Faction[/color][/bold]</Box>
  <Box>[bold][color=#a4885c]Standing[/color][/bold]</Box>
  <Box>[bold][color=#a4885c]Notes[/color][/bold]</Box>
  <Box>NCR</Box>
  <Box>[color=#6bba5e]Allied[/color]</Box>
  <Box>Mutual protection and supply access agreements.</Box>
  <Box>Brotherhood of Steel</Box>
  <Box>[color=#a4885c]Neutral[/color]</Box>
  <Box>Trades supplies, avoids selling restricted technology.</Box>
  <Box>Caesar's Legion</Box>
  <Box>[color=#ffb000]Cautious[/color]</Box>
  <Box>Will trade if approached peacefully. Does not trust Legion motives.</Box>
  <Box>Townsfolk</Box>
  <Box>[color=#6bba5e]Allied[/color]</Box>
  <Box>The town's economic lifeline. Mutual dependency.</Box>
  <Box>Tribes</Box>
  <Box>[color=#6bba5e]Friendly[/color]</Box>
  <Box>Regular trade partners. Caravans supply what the land cannot.</Box>
  <Box>Wastelanders</Box>
  <Box>[color=#6bba5e]Friendly[/color]</Box>
  <Box>Good source of contracts and hired protection.</Box>
</Table>

<p>[color=#a4885c]Note:[/color] If the Caravan Company is destroyed or driven off, the entire region loses its primary supply lifeline. The CC remains neutral by default but will cut off trade with any faction that attacks their caravans or personnel.</p>
</Document>
