<Document>
# Two-Handed Melee

[textlink="View Full Wiki Page" link="https://ss14.misfitsystems.net/wiki/index.php/Two-Handed%20Melee"/]

## Two-Handed Melee

<p>Two-handed melee weapons are slower to swing but deal significantly more damage. They require both hands to use, meaning you cannot hold a firearm at the same time - but in melee range, their power is unmatched.</p>

<h3 Text="Spears"/>

<p>Spears are versatile two-handed weapons with reach. They can be thrown and deal good damage against armored and unarmored targets alike.</p>

<Table Columns="2">
  <Box>[bold]Weapon[/bold]</Box>
  <Box>[bold]Notes[/bold]</Box>
  <Box>[bold]Wasteland Spear[/bold]</Box>
  <Box>Basic reaching weapon. Can be thrown.</Box>
  <Box>[bold]Tribal Spear[/bold]</Box>
  <Box>Decorated tribal construction. Similar stats to the Wasteland Spear.</Box>
  <Box>[bold]Flag Spear[/bold]</Box>
  <Box>Spear with faction banner. Ceremonial but fully combat-capable.</Box>
</Table>

<h3 Text="Hammers &amp; Sledges"/>

<p>Blunt force weapons that crush through armor. The Super Sledge is the pinnacle of two-handed blunt weaponry.</p>

<Table Columns="2">
  <Box>[bold]Weapon[/bold]</Box>
  <Box>[bold]Notes[/bold]</Box>
  <Box>[bold]Sledgehammer[/bold]</Box>
  <Box>Heavy blunt weapon. Good damage against armored targets.</Box>
  <Box>[bold]Super Sledge[/bold]</Box>
  <Box>Pre-war hydraulic sledge. Exceptional damage. Rare and prized.</Box>
  <Box>[bold]Tribal War Club[/bold]</Box>
  <Box>Large blunt club. Slower swing, heavy impact.</Box>
  <Box>[bold]Nail Board[/bold]</Box>
  <Box>Improvised spiked club. Common Wasteland weapon.</Box>
</Table>

<h3 Text="Long Blades"/>

<p>Large swords and blades for those who prefer cutting over crushing. Many are tribal or ceremonial in origin.</p>

<Table Columns="2">
  <Box>[bold]Weapon[/bold]</Box>
  <Box>[bold]Notes[/bold]</Box>
  <Box>[bold]Longsword[/bold]</Box>
  <Box>Standard two-handed blade. Balanced reach and damage.</Box>
  <Box>[bold]Tribal Sword[/bold]</Box>
  <Box>Handcrafted long blade. Rougher edge than manufactured swords.</Box>
  <Box>[bold]Tribal Machete[/bold]</Box>
  <Box>Oversized two-handed cutting blade.</Box>
  <Box>[bold]Ripper[/bold]</Box>
  <Box>Motorized blade weapon. Pre-war construction. Very high damage.</Box>
</Table>

</Document>
