<Document>
# Vault Dwellers

[textlink="View Full Wiki Page" link="https://ss14.misfitsystems.net/wiki/index.php/Vault%20Dwellers"/]

<p>◈ Vault Dwellers ◈ Faction Dossier ◈ Vault-Tec ◈</p>

<Table Columns="2">
  <Box>[bold]Vault Dwellers[/bold]</Box>
  <Box></Box>
  <Box>◈ FACTION DOSSIER ◈</Box>
  <Box></Box>
  <Box>[bold]Status[/bold]</Box>
  <Box>Active - Emerged</Box>
  <Box>[bold]Location[/bold]</Box>
  <Box>Vault (Location Classified)
Wendover Region, Utah</Box>
  <Box>[bold]Commander[/bold]</Box>
  <Box>Overseer</Box>
  <Box>[bold]Ideology[/bold]</Box>
  <Box>Vault-Tec Protocols
Genetic Preservation</Box>
  <Box>[bold]Motto[/bold]</Box>
  <Box>[italic]Prepared for the Future.[/italic]</Box>
  <Box>[bold]Affiliation[/bold]</Box>
  <Box>Vault-Tec Corporation (Pre-War)</Box>
  <Box>⬜ RESTRICTED ACCESS ⬜</Box>
  <Box></Box>
</Table>

<p>[bold]Vault Dwellers[/bold] are survivors of Vault-Tec's underground shelters - sealed communities designed to protect a select population from nuclear annihilation. Equipped with Pip-Boys and Vault jumpsuits, they emerge into a world nothing could have prepared them for.</p>
<p>Every Vault was an experiment. Not every experiment was humane. What the Dwellers know - or don't know - about their Vault's true purpose shapes everything that follows.</p>

## Core Mission

<ColorBox Color="#1a1a1a" OutlineColor="#666666" OutlineThickness="1" Margin="5">
  <Box Orientation="Vertical" Margin="8">
[italic]"To maintain optimal operational efficiency, preserve pure human genetics, and strictly execute all directives handed down by 'Management' to prepare for the eventual reclamation of the surface."[/italic]
  </Box>
</ColorBox>

## Roles

<Table Columns="3">
  <Box>[bold]Role[/bold]</Box>
  <Box>[bold]Description[/bold]</Box>
  <Box>[bold]Notes[/bold]</Box>
  <Box>Overseer</Box>
  <Box>Administer the Vault. You know something the others may not - the Vault's true purpose, if one exists. Decide whether to shield your people from that knowledge or lead them through it. If the door opens, you determine how your community meets the surface world.</Box>
  <Box>Vault command authority.</Box>
  <Box>[bold]Vault Security[/bold]</Box>
  <Box>Maintain order inside the Vault and protect it if the door opens. You enforce the Overseer's authority. How you use that authority - with justice or with fear - shapes what the Vault becomes.</Box>
  <Box>Internal law enforcement.</Box>
  <Box>[bold]Vault Scientist[/bold]</Box>
  <Box>Keep Vault systems running, conduct research, and provide medical care. You may hold critical information about the Vault's experiment - and that knowledge could save or destroy your community depending on what you choose to do with it.</Box>
  <Box>Technical and medical specialist.</Box>
  <Box>[bold]Vault Dweller[/bold]</Box>
  <Box>Live Vault life. Follow protocols, contribute to community work, and try to make sense of what is happening. If the door opens, every assumption you have about the world will be tested - starting immediately.</Box>
  <Box>General population.</Box>
</Table>

## The Vault

<p>Vault-Tec built 122 known Vaults across the United States. Most were social experiments - controlled environments designed to test human behavior under extreme conditions. Some Vaults were benign. Others were not.</p>
<p>The Vault's systems - water purification, hydroponics, medical bays, the Pip-Boy network - are pre-war technology that the surface world has lost. This makes Vault Dwellers simultaneously invaluable and vulnerable: everyone wants what they have, and most Dwellers are not prepared for what the Wasteland demands.</p>

## Relations

<Table Columns="3">
  <Box>[bold]Faction[/bold]</Box>
  <Box>[bold]Standing[/bold]</Box>
  <Box>[bold]Notes[/bold]</Box>
  <Box>[textlink="Brotherhood of Steel" link="https://ss14.misfitsystems.net/wiki/index.php/Brotherhood_of_Steel"/]</Box>
  <Box>Curious / Suspicious</Box>
  <Box>The Brotherhood values Vault technology - Pip-Boys, reactors, pre-war data. [italic]"Tell me, Dweller. Is your Vault's reactor still operational?"[/italic]</Box>
  <Box>[textlink="NCR" link="https://ss14.misfitsystems.net/wiki/index.php/New_California_Republic"/]</Box>
  <Box>Welcoming</Box>
  <Box>The NCR sees Vault Dwellers as potential citizens and a source of pre-war knowledge.</Box>
  <Box>[textlink="Caesar's Legion" link="https://ss14.misfitsystems.net/wiki/index.php/Caesar%27s_Legion"/]</Box>
  <Box>Hostile</Box>
  <Box>The Legion views Vault Dwellers as soft, sheltered, and ripe for enslavement.</Box>
  <Box>[textlink="Townsfolk" link="https://ss14.misfitsystems.net/wiki/index.php/Townsfolk"/]</Box>
  <Box>Friendly</Box>
  <Box>Towns are usually the first place Dwellers find after emerging. They are welcome - and pitied.</Box>
  <Box>[textlink="Followers of the Apocalypse" link="https://ss14.misfitsystems.net/wiki/index.php/Followers_of_the_Apocalypse"/]</Box>
  <Box>Allied</Box>
  <Box>The Followers are eager to share knowledge with Dwellers and learn from their Vault's archives.</Box>
  <Box>[textlink="Outlaws" link="https://ss14.misfitsystems.net/wiki/index.php/Outlaws"/]</Box>
  <Box>Hostile</Box>
  <Box>A Vault Dweller in a clean jumpsuit with a Pip-Boy is a walking target for raiders.</Box>
</Table>

</Document>
