<Document>
# Enclave

[textlink="View Full Wiki Page" link="https://ss14.misfitsystems.net/wiki/index.php/The_Enclave"]

<Table Columns="2">
  <Box>[bold]Status[/bold]</Box>
  <Box>Active — Covert operations</Box>
  <Box>[bold]Location[/bold]</Box>
  <Box>Classified</Box>
  <Box>[bold]Leadership[/bold]</Box>
  <Box>Enclave Officer Corps</Box>
  <Box>[bold]Ideology[/bold]</Box>
  <Box>American restoration, genetic purity</Box>
  <Box>[bold]Motto[/bold]</Box>
  <Box>[italic]"God Bless the Enclave. God Bless America."[/italic]</Box>
</Table>

<hr/>

<p>The Enclave are the remnants of the pre-war United States government — a shadow organization that survived the nuclear exchange in offshore platforms and hardened facilities, preserving their personnel, their technology, and their ideology through two centuries of wasteland history.</p>

<p>They consider themselves the legal successors of America. Everyone else — ghouls, mutants, virtually all surface survivors contaminated by post-war radiation — is subhuman in their view, to be eliminated so the land can be reclaimed for "pure" humans.</p>

<hr/>

## Philosophy

<ColorBox Color="#1a1a1a" OutlineColor="#263238" OutlineThickness="1" Margin="5">
  <Box Orientation="Vertical" Margin="8">
    [italic]"The Enclave operates with cold bureaucratic efficiency in service of a genocidal agenda they genuinely believe is necessary and just."[/italic]
  </Box>
</ColorBox>

<p>Their goal is not survival but restoration — the forced re-establishment of federal authority over land they view as rightfully theirs. They are the most technologically advanced faction in the Wasteland, constrained only by small numbers and the universal hostility of everyone who understands their intentions.</p>

<hr/>

## Roles

<ColorBox Color="#263238">
  <Box Margin="2">
  [bold]Enclave Officer[/bold]
  </Box>
</ColorBox>
<Box>
[italic]In the Fallout universe:[/italic] Enclave Officers are the highest-ranking field operatives — people like Colonel Autumn of Fallout 3 or President Richardson's command staff in Fallout 2. They are career military professionals who have lived their entire lives within Enclave ideology. To them, the atrocities their organization commits are policy, not cruelty. Many genuinely believe they are saving humanity — which makes them significantly more dangerous than people who know they are doing wrong.

[color=#a4885c]Your role:[/color] Command local Enclave operations. Pursue the Enclave's agenda with precision and control. Your orders come from above — your judgment determines how those orders manifest on the ground.
</Box>

<br/>

<ColorBox Color="#263238">
  <Box Margin="2">
  [bold]Enclave Soldier[/bold]
  </Box>
</ColorBox>
<Box>
[italic]In the Fallout universe:[/italic] Enclave Soldiers are elite infantry in advanced power armor unavailable anywhere else in the Wasteland. In Fallout 3 and 2, a single Enclave patrol is a serious threat even to well-armed parties. Their combination of ideological conditioning, advanced equipment, and military discipline makes them among the most dangerous combatants any faction will face.

[color=#a4885c]Your role:[/color] Execute orders with precision and overwhelming force. You are the Enclave's fist. Your equipment outperforms virtually everything else in the field — and you are expected to make full use of that advantage.
</Box>

<br/>

<ColorBox Color="#263238">
  <Box Margin="2">
  [bold]Enclave Scientist[/bold]
  </Box>
</ColorBox>
<Box>
[italic]In the Fallout universe:[/italic] Enclave Scientists are the intellectual core of the faction — researchers who continued pre-war government programs in isolation for generations, developing weapons and technologies the surface world cannot replicate. In canon, Enclave science produced modified FEV, advanced vertibird technology, and Robobrain development programs. They are responsible for both the Enclave's greatest capabilities and some of its most horrific projects.

[color=#a4885c]Your role:[/color] Develop and maintain Enclave technology. Conduct research assignments. Your work is what justifies the Enclave's belief in their own indispensability — ensure it is worth that justification.
</Box>

<hr/>

## Faction Relations

<p>The Enclave does not negotiate with "contaminated" populations. They operate covertly until ready to move openly. Discovery of their presence creates a hard choice for other factions: expose them and invite retaliation, or stay silent and wait for the inevitable hammer to fall.</p>
</Document>
